<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 10/26/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/27/summary251026/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/27/summary251026/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, global markets generally saw rising stocks and slightly falling government bonds. However, the specific factors driving market performance differed across regions. Let’s dive into details for each major market.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.92%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+2.31%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+2.20%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+2.50%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+3.11%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+1.72%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+0.63%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+3.61%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.47% -&gt; <font color="red">3.50%</font></li><li>10yr          4.01% -&gt; <font color="red">4.02%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.54% -&gt; <font color="green">4.43%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.58% -&gt; <font color="red">2.63%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.36% -&gt; <font color="red">3.44%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.63% -&gt; <font color="red">1.66%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            57.6-&gt; <font color="green">61.4</font></li><li>Gold           4,268-&gt; <font color="red">4,127</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Trade-Noise-and-CPI-Cheer"><a href="#U-S-Market-Trade-Noise-and-CPI-Cheer" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Trade Noise and CPI Cheer"></a>U.S. Market: Trade Noise and CPI Cheer</h1><p>The U.S. market was heavily influenced by the ongoing U.S.-China trade negotiations. News from the U.S. side, particularly from President Donald Trump, caused market sentiment to swing back and forth from caution to optimism. However, having weathered previous rounds of tariff threats, the market generally settled on the view that the threats would ultimately be more bark than bite, leading to an overall recovery in sentiment.</p><p>A major driver of market optimism came from the CPI data released on Friday. Due to the U.S. government shutdown delaying data releases, this particular CPI report became a crucial reference point for the Federal Reserve to judge future rate cuts. The data came in slightly lower than market expectations, which boosted investor confidence that the Fed would continue its easing cycle. This momentum pushed U.S. stocks to new record highs.</p><p>Corporate Earnings also played a significant role. With Q3 earnings season coming, strong results from companies like GM and 3M led to stock surges, while Netflix’s weak performance caused its stock to fall. The performance of tech stocks like Tesla and IBM was unusual: despite disappointing earnings, their share prices, after initial drops, quickly recovered, suggesting that some long-term investors are seizing price dips as buying opportunities in the tech sector.</p><p>In the bond market, rate cut expectations provided upward pressure. However, the U.S. sanctioning of a Russian oil giant on Wednesday caused oil prices to spike, raising inflation concerns. This inflation worry brought downward pressure on U.S. bonds, which ultimately ended the week slightly lower.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Diverging-Local-Factors"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Diverging-Local-Factors" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Diverging Local Factors"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Diverging Local Factors</h1><p>The European market mirrored the U.S., with stocks generally rising and bonds falling. Because the European Central Bank’s (ECB) rate-cutting cycle is almost complete, and with relatively strong PMI data released this week, the decline in European bond prices was more pronounced than in the U.S.</p><ul><li>The UK market significantly outperformed Germany and France. This was due to two factors: <ul><li>Lower UK CPI data led the market to anticipate a potential rate cut by the Bank of England in December, which boosted UK bond prices and stocks. </li><li>The rise in oil prices lifted energy stocks, which have a larger weighting in the UK stock market.</li></ul></li></ul><p>In Japan, the “Takaichi Trade,” which had temporarily slowed, was reignited. This trade is based on the economic platform of Sanae Takaichi, which advocates for fiscal expansion and opposes rate hikes. This policy outlook (more spending, easy money) pushed Japanese stocks higher and the yen lower (See Week 10&#x2F;12&#x2F;2025 for logic behind). Simultaneously, market caution about a widening fiscal deficit and increased bond issuance pushed Japanese bond prices lower.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Oil-Rallies-Gold-Slides"><a href="#Commodities-Oil-Rallies-Gold-Slides" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Oil Rallies, Gold Slides"></a>Commodities: Oil Rallies, Gold Slides</h1><p>As mentioned above, the U.S. sanctioning of a Russian oil giant on Wednesday caused oil prices to spike. </p><p>Meanwhile, the prevailing optimistic sentiment reduced safe-haven demand. This, combined with profit-taking pressure after nine consecutive weeks of gains, caused gold prices to dip slightly this week.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 10/19/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/21/summary251019/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/21/summary251019/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, with the U.S. government shutdown persisting and delaying key economic data releases, markets were predominantly influenced by political factors and corporate earnings.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.70%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+2.14%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.56%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+2.4%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-0.77%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-1.69%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+3.24%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="red">-1.05%</font></li><li>NKD1!         <font color="green">+6.73%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.51% -&gt; <font color="green">3.47%</font></li><li>10yr          4.04% -&gt; <font color="green">4.01%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.67% -&gt; <font color="green">4.54%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.63% -&gt; <font color="green">2.58%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.48% -&gt; <font color="green">3.36%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.70% -&gt; <font color="green">1.63%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            58.2-&gt; <font color="red">57.6</font></li><li>Gold           4,015-&gt; <font color="green">4,268</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Trade-War-Eases-Earnings-Shine"><a href="#U-S-Market-Trade-War-Eases-Earnings-Shine" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Trade War Eases, Earnings Shine"></a>U.S. Market: Trade War Eases, Earnings Shine</h1><p>The central focus remained the trade war risk sparked by Donald Trump last week. After an initial spike in risk aversion, markets stabilized this week, having gained some immunity to the recurring threats. The overall sentiment improved, particularly after Trump stated on October 17th that 100% tariffs were not a long-term goal, which fueled a rebound in U.S. stocks.</p><p>Two other major factors contributed to the rally:</p><ul><li><p>Fed Signals: Fed Chair Powell suggested during a Tuesday speech that rate cuts were likely to continue and that the balance sheet reduction (quantitative tightening) could end within a few months, signaling a supportive policy environment.</p></li><li><p>Strong Earnings: Approximately 12% of S&amp;P 500 companies released earnings this week, with over 80% beating expectations. News of Broadcom’s joint development with OpenAI and strong earnings from TSMC sustained the market’s enthusiasm for the AI semiconductor industry.</p></li></ul><p>The dovish signals from the Fed also influenced the bond market, pushing U.S. Treasury yields down and prices up.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Political-Stabilization-and-Turmoil"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Political-Stabilization-and-Turmoil" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Political Stabilization and Turmoil"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Political Stabilization and Turmoil</h1><p>European bond markets largely followed the U.S. trend, seeing slight gains. Stocks, however, faced downward pressure due to lingering concerns over the trade war risk. A notable bright spot was France, where the Prime Minister survived two no-confidence motions this week. While the cabinet still faces challenges, this temporary stability boosted confidence in the French market, leading to a stock market rebound and a narrowing of the yield spread between German and French bonds.</p><p>In Japan, the political scene remains volatile. Following the split with its long-term ally, Komeito, the LDP actively sought other coalition partners this week. The “Takaichi Trade” logic—which anticipated a surge in stocks based on Takaichi’s election as LDP president—experienced several reversals. Ultimately, Japanese stocks saw a small pullback for the week, though Nikkei futures showed a large increase over the previous week’s closing price. Amidst the political confusion, the market anticipates that the Bank of Japan will be hesitant to raise rates, leading to a slight decrease in Japanese bond yields.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Gold-Rallies-Oil-Slides"><a href="#Commodities-Gold-Rallies-Oil-Slides" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Gold Rallies, Oil Slides"></a>Commodities: Gold Rallies, Oil Slides</h1><p>The trade war risk lowered the outlook for global energy demand, causing oil prices to slide further to near a six-month low.</p><p>Conversely, both the risk-averse sentiment stemming from the trade war threat and the accommodative signals released by the Fed are positive for gold. These factors combined to drive gold prices to surge dramatically, breaking the $4,000 per ounce. This spike in gold also lifted other precious metals, with silver prices on the London market hitting an all-time high this week.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 10/12/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/11/summary251012/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/11/summary251012/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, markets were primarily driven by political events, with the U.S., Japan, and Europe each facing their own unique turmoil. Let’s break down the main logic based on timeline.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="red">-2.43%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-2.27%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-2.73%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="red">-4.14%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-1.07%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-0.88%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-2.43%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+5.07%</font></li><li>NKD1!         <font color="red">-0.02%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.57% -&gt; <font color="green">3.51%</font></li><li>10yr          4.12% -&gt; <font color="green">4.04%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.69% -&gt; <font color="green">4.67%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.70% -&gt; <font color="green">2.63%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.51% -&gt; <font color="green">3.48%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.67% -&gt; <font color="red">1.70%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            60.7-&gt; <font color="red">58.2</font></li><li>Gold           3,886-&gt; <font color="green">4,015</font></li></ul><h1 id="Japan-The-“Takaichi-Trade”-and-Political-Instability"><a href="#Japan-The-“Takaichi-Trade”-and-Political-Instability" class="headerlink" title="Japan: The “Takaichi Trade” and Political Instability"></a>Japan: The “Takaichi Trade” and Political Instability</h1><p>Last weekend, Sanae Takaichi was elected as the new president of Liberal Democratic Party (LDP), making her a likely candidate for the next prime minister. This result was somewhat unexpected, triggering a “Takaichi Trade” at the start of the week.</p><p>The logic of this trade was based on Takaichi’s economic policies, which are centered on two points: fiscal expansion and opposition to rate hikes.</p><ul><li>Fiscal expansion raises the risk of a larger deficit and increased government bond issuance, which puts downward pressure on Japanese bonds.</li><li>Her opposition to rate hikes led the market to lower its expectations for a Bank of Japan rate hike, which widened the yield spread with the U.S. and caused the yen to depreciate.</li><li>For the stock market, fiscal expansion, delayed rate hikes, and a weaker yen are all positive catalysts.</li></ul><p>As a result of the “Takaichi Trade,” the Japanese stock market saw a significant rally, while Japanese bonds and the yen fell.</p><p>However, the LDP does not hold a majority in the House of Representatives on its own, so Takaichi’s election doesn’t automatically guarantee her the prime minister position. On Friday, the political situation took a dramatic turn when the LDP’s key ally, the Komeito party, indicated it might not vote for Takaichi in the upcoming prime ministerial election. This uncertainty shook the foundation of the “Takaichi Trade,” causing a reversal in market trends and leading to a sharp drop in Nikkei stock futures on Friday night.</p><h1 id="U-S-and-Europe-Politics-Drive-Risk-Off-Sentiment"><a href="#U-S-and-Europe-Politics-Drive-Risk-Off-Sentiment" class="headerlink" title="U.S. and Europe: Politics Drive Risk-Off Sentiment"></a>U.S. and Europe: Politics Drive Risk-Off Sentiment</h1><p>The U.S. government remains in a partial shutdown due to budget disagreements, which continues to prevent the release of key economic data. In this environment, markets are highly sensitive to policy developments. On Friday, Donald Trump sent a series of posts threatening to impose tariffs on China, triggering market fears of a new trade war. This caused a shift toward risk-averse sentiment.</p><p>This flight to safety pushed U.S. bonds higher and stocks lower, a trend that also spread to European markets. European markets largely mirrored the U.S., with bonds rising and stocks falling.</p><p>In France, the Prime Minister resigned again due to an inability to pass the fiscal budget. While President Macron re-appointed him on Friday, the underlying issues of political division and fiscal deadlock remain. Consequently, both the French stock and bond markets continue to lag behind the UK and Germany.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Geopolitical-Risks-and-a-Stronger-Gold"><a href="#Commodities-Geopolitical-Risks-and-a-Stronger-Gold" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Geopolitical Risks and a Stronger Gold"></a>Commodities: Geopolitical Risks and a Stronger Gold</h1><p>The commodity market saw significant volatility. The Middle East risk premium has fallen due to the Gaza ceasefire agreement. OPEC and the Americas are still expected to increase production. Plus, Trump’s trade war threats significantly lowered the outlook for energy demand. All these factors ultimately cause oil prices to fall to a near six-month low.</p><p>Gold prices, on the other hand, continued to rise sharply, breaking the $4,000 mark, primarily driven by the market’s risk-averse sentiment. The surge in gold also boosted other precious metals, with silver prices on the London market hitting a new record high this week.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 10/05/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/05/summary251005/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/05/summary251005/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, the big news was the U.S. government shutdown. Since the U.S. fiscal year begins on October 1st, and the Republican and Democratic parties failed to agree on a new budget, the U.S. government entered a partial shutdown. </p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.08%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+1.15%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.10%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+1.66%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+1.94%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+2.72%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+2.68%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.91%</font></li><li>TOPIX         <font color="red">-1.82%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.65% -&gt; <font color="green">3.57%</font></li><li>10yr          4.18% -&gt; <font color="green">4.12%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.76% -&gt; <font color="green">4.69%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.75% -&gt; <font color="green">2.70%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.57% -&gt; <font color="green">3.51%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.66% -&gt; <font color="red">1.67%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            65.2-&gt; <font color="red">60.7</font></li><li>Gold           3,754-&gt; <font color="green">3,886</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Missing-Major-Economics-Data"><a href="#U-S-Market-Missing-Major-Economics-Data" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Missing Major Economics Data"></a>U.S. Market: Missing Major Economics Data</h1><p>The government shutdown had an immediate effect on the market: the U.S. Census Bureau couldn’t operate normally, so two key economic reports—weekly unemployment claims and non-farm payrolls—were not released on schedule. Without this key data, the market’s attention shifted to the secondary ADP employment report and the ISM services PMI, both of which came in weaker than expected.</p><p>Weaker-than-expected data often signals a slowing economy and strengthens the expectation of a Fed rate cut. This increased prospect of a rate cut, combined with the flight of capital to safe-haven assets due to the shutdown, pushed U.S. Treasury bonds up.</p><p>The logic for the stock market was a bit different: bad news is good news. Weaker economic data, by reinforcing rate cut expectations, helped to fuel optimistic sentiment in the stock market. This logic propelled major U.S. and UK stock indices to new record highs.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Following-US-and-LDP-Presidential-Election"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Following-US-and-LDP-Presidential-Election" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Following US and LDP Presidential Election"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Following US and LDP Presidential Election</h1><p>Both bond and stock markets of EU follows the movement of US.</p><p>And for Japan, in a speech this week, the Bank of Japan (BOJ) Governor stated that the Japanese economy still faces many uncertainties and showed no eagerness to raise interest rates. Despite this, Japanese bond auctions this week showed weak demand, causing Japanese bond prices to fall slightly. The stock market was supported by the rally in U.S. equities, but some investors remained cautious ahead of the LDP presidential election. The Nikkei index continued its rise to a new record high, while the Topix index saw a small decline.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Navigating-Uncertainty"><a href="#Commodities-Navigating-Uncertainty" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Navigating Uncertainty"></a>Commodities: Navigating Uncertainty</h1><p>The U.S. government shutdown and the stronger rate cut expectations both contributed to a slight depreciation of the U.S. dollar, which is generally positive for gold. Fueled by these factors, gold prices rose sharply, once again hitting a new all-time high.</p><p>A Reuters report that OPEC would continue to increase production in November sent oil prices plunging at the beginning of the week. This increased supply outlook put significant downward pressure on oil. </p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 9/28/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/09/28/summary250928/"/>
    <url>/2025/09/28/summary250928/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, with few major news events, the market continued to digest the Federal Reserve’s recent rate cut while adjusting expectations for future cuts based on new economic data and Fed officials’ statements.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="red">-0.31%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-0.5%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-0.15%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="red">+2.16%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.85%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.42%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+0.15%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.69%</font></li><li>TOPIX         <font color="green">+1.25%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.58% -&gt; <font color="red">3.65%</font></li><li>10yr          4.13% -&gt; <font color="red">4.18%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.71% -&gt; <font color="red">4.76%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.75% -&gt; <font color="green">2.74%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.56% -&gt; <font color="red">3.57%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.64% -&gt; <font color="red">1.66%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            62.7-&gt; <font color="green">65.2</font></li><li>Gold           3,682-&gt; <font color="green">3,754</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Strong-Data-and-Hawkish-Comments"><a href="#U-S-Market-Strong-Data-and-Hawkish-Comments" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Strong Data and Hawkish Comments"></a>U.S. Market: Strong Data and Hawkish Comments</h1><p>Economic data was generally robust this week. The September PMI data came in below expectations, but other indicators, including new home sales, unemployment claims, and Q2 GDP, were strong. The Q2 GDP data, in particular, eased market fears of a recession.</p><p>This economic strength reduced the pressure on the Fed to cut rates quickly. Fed officials’ comments this week reinforced this conservative stance. On Tuesday, Fed Chair Powell reiterated his vigilance against inflation in a speech, which the market interpreted as slightly hawkish. Other Fed officials’ remarks were also generally hawkish, with the exception of Trump’s confidant, Miran.</p><p>The combination of strong economic data and hawkish comments led the market to lower its expectations for the future pace of rate cuts. This caused U.S. bonds to fall and put the brakes on the stock market’s upward momentum. Following a long rally, a wave of profit-taking selling pressure led to small declines in major stock indices. The week started with a brief rise in tech stocks after news broke of Nvidia’s investment in OpenAI to build an AI data center, but the rally was short-lived.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Following-Their-Own-Leads"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Following-Their-Own-Leads" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Following Their Own Leads"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Following Their Own Leads</h1><p>There was little major news in Europe this week. The bond market largely followed the trend of falling U.S. bonds, with European bonds also experiencing a slight decline. Stock markets saw little change, although the UK market, with its higher proportion of energy stocks, slightly outperformed Germany and France due to the rise in oil prices.</p><p>Weak Tokyo CPI data led the market to lower its expectations for a rate hike from the Bank of Japan. This caused the yen to depreciate slightly, providing some upward momentum for the Japanese stock market. However, the Japanese bond market faced conflicting pressures. The lower CPI reduced rate hike expectations, pushing bond prices up, but mounting concerns over a new cabinet’s potential fiscal expansion and the downward pull from U.S. bonds caused Japanese bonds to fall. The yield on 10-year Japanese bonds reached its highest level in nearly 17 years.</p><ul><li>Why lowering its expectations for a rate hike will cause the depreciation of Yen and provide upward momentum for stock market?<ul><li>A currency becomes less attractive when you are told its yield will remain low for the foreseeable future compared to its peers. Lower demand for a currency means a lower price.</li><li>Japan is a major export economy. Its corporate giants (like Toyota, Sony, Nintendo, Canon, etc.) earn a massive portion of their revenue in foreign currencies. When the Yen is weak, the overseas profits of these companies, when converted back into Yen, become significantly larger.</li><li>A weaker Yen makes Japanese products cheaper for foreign buyers. This can lead to an increase in sales volume, gaining market share from competitors in countries with stronger currencies. This provides a double boost: higher volumes and higher Yen-denominated revenue per unit.</li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Commodities-Slow-Reaction"><a href="#Commodities-Slow-Reaction" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Slow Reaction"></a>Commodities: Slow Reaction</h1><p>Gold prices continued to rise, reaching a new all-time high. It seems the gold market is still digesting the full implications of the Fed’s recent rate cut.</p><p>Oil prices were primarily influenced by supply-side concerns. News of an attack on a Russian oil facility and Trump’s call for the EU to ban the purchase of oil led to a decrease in expected oil supply, causing prices to rise slightly.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Will the Recent Gold Rally Last Long?</title>
    <link href="/2025/09/21/note-gold/"/>
    <url>/2025/09/21/note-gold/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gold has been on an impressive run, with prices more than doubling from $1,429 per ounce in November 2022 to $3,700 per ounce by today, a 30% compound annual growth rate. This surge has captured a lot of attention, and for good reason. But with gold breaking new highs, many investors are asking a crucial question: What is the next for gold?</p><p>To understand the risks, we can look to two recent analyses: <a href="https://www.gold.org/goldhub/research/whats-a-bear-case-for-gold">a detailed historical review from the World Gold Council (WGC)</a> and <a href="https://www.deshaw.com/library/worth-its-weight">an article from D.E. Shaw</a>.</p><h1 id="The-World-Gold-Council’s-Historical-View"><a href="#The-World-Gold-Council’s-Historical-View" class="headerlink" title="The World Gold Council’s Historical View"></a>The World Gold Council’s Historical View</h1><p>The World Gold Council’s report on the bear case for gold analyzes five major pullbacks in its price since the 1971 Bretton Woods collapse. These historical declines were generally driven by three main factors: rising opportunity costs, cooling risks and uncertainty, and structural supply changes.</p><p>Here is a summary of each pullback:</p><ul><li><strong>1st Bear Run (1974-1976): The Establish of Petrodollar</strong><br>The anchor of dollar changed from gold to oil, which strengthened the dollar again and as a result, gold price pullbacked.</li></ul><!-- ![image](./note-gold/1st%20gold%20pullback.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/1st%20gold%20pullback.png" class=""><ul><li><strong>2nd &amp; 3rd Bear Run (1980-1982 &amp; 1983-1985): Hike Rates to Fight Inflation</strong><br>Although the report separates two pullbacks, I personally believe these two were both the result of then-Fed Chair Paul Volcker rates hiking for inflation cool down. The sharp rise in real interest rates caused the dollar to strengthen</li></ul><!-- ![image](./note-gold/2nd&3rd%20gold%20pullback.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/2nd&3rd%20gold%20pullback.png" class=""><ul><li><strong>4th Bear Run (1987-1999): Formation of Unipolar Hegemony</strong><br>This was the longest bear run in history. The collapse of the Soviet Union marked the end of Cold War, which significantly reduced geopolitical risk. Dollar become the only worldwide currency and all central banks generally believed that gold has lost its monetary properties and started to sell over the years.</li></ul><!-- ![image](./note-gold/4th%20gold%20pullback.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/4th%20gold%20pullback.png" class=""><ul><li><strong>5th Bear Run (2011-2015): Rising Real Interest Rate</strong><br>After the Fed ended its quantitative easing program, the real yield rose and dollar became strengthed.</li></ul><!-- ![image](./note-gold/5th%20gold%20pullback.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/5th%20gold%20pullback.png" class="">  <p>It is obvious that the underlying reason for a pullback is <strong>the stengthen of dollar</strong>, either confidence level (Petrodollar, Unipolar Hegemony) or fundamental level (increase in real interest rate, decrease in inflation, economic strength)</p><p>This report also mentioned the near-term and long-term risk for gold price weakness.</p><!-- ![image](./note-gold/near%20term%20risk.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/near%20term%20risk.png" class=""><!-- ![image](./note-gold/long%20term%20risk.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/long%20term%20risk.png" class=""><h1 id="D-E-Shaw’s-Portfolio-Optimization-Aspect-of-Gold"><a href="#D-E-Shaw’s-Portfolio-Optimization-Aspect-of-Gold" class="headerlink" title="D.E. Shaw’s Portfolio Optimization Aspect of Gold"></a>D.E. Shaw’s Portfolio Optimization Aspect of Gold</h1><p>D.E. Shaw tackles the issue from a different angle, addressing the problem of valuing gold. Unlike stocks or bonds, which have future cash flows, gold is a non-productive store of value (NPSOV). This makes it impossible to price using traditional methods like discounted cash flow.</p><p>Instead, D.E. Shaw proposes a model based on gold’s relationship with other assets and use optimizer to illustrate the ideal time to add gold to a portfolio.</p><ol><li>In a positive stock-bond correlation environment, the potential portfolio utility of gold increases, even if our forecast for gold remains unchanged.</li><li>A strong expectation of high inflation and a looming stock market crash</li></ol><p>These were further comfirmed by optimizer for portfolio  allocation. Specifically, the more exposed the portfolio is to risks like a positive stock-bond correlation, equity crashes, or inflation shocks, the more value the optimizer assigns to gold’s diversification benefits.</p><!-- ![image](./note-gold/optimizer.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/optimizer.png" class=""><h1 id="Synthesis-Why-a-Bear-Case-is-Unlikely-Now"><a href="#Synthesis-Why-a-Bear-Case-is-Unlikely-Now" class="headerlink" title="Synthesis: Why a Bear Case is Unlikely Now"></a>Synthesis: Why a Bear Case is Unlikely Now</h1><p>Combining the insights from both reports, a powerful picture emerges. The factors that have historically driven gold into a bear market—a strong U.S. dollar and cooling geopolitical risks—are not currently present.</p><p>The U.S. economy faces a unique situation where both “weak dollar” and “de-dollarization” forces are active. “Weak dollar” is a deliberate action by the U.S. to devalue its currency to stimulate a soft economy and manufacturing. “De-dollarization” is a trend among other countries to reduce their reliance on the dollar for trade, often due to concerns over its use as a tool for sanctions. When both the producer of the dollar (the U.S.) and its major consumers (other export-heavy nations) are moving away from the currency, the result is a powerful “double kill” that prevents the dollar from fundamentally strengthening.</p><p>Therefore, given the current macro environment, the historical conditions for a gold bear run simply do not exist. While short-term pullbacks are always possible, the core factors that have fueled gold’s bull run—high geopolitical risk, a weak dollar, and fears of inflation—remain firmly in place.</p><h1 id="Some-Personal-Thoughts"><a href="#Some-Personal-Thoughts" class="headerlink" title="Some Personal Thoughts"></a>Some Personal Thoughts</h1><p>The traditional framework for gold analysis depends on <strong>real interest rate + overall returns of other asset classes</strong>. </p><ul><li>The lower real interest rate, the higher gold price. <ul><li>Econ 101 tells us the real interest rate &#x3D; norminal interest rate - inflation. It’s very easy to get the relationship between inflation and gold price.</li><li>In the real market, traders also consider expectation, ie. real interest rate &#x3D; (realized norminal interest rate + expected norminal interest rate) - (realized inflation + expected inflation). That makes things a bit complex.</li></ul></li><li>The higher other asset classes returns, the lower gold price</li></ul><p>But since 2022, the framework no longer holds. The main reason is that we have a lower boundery for real interest rate. We cannot go below 0 for too long. However, the gold has no up ceiling. </p><!-- ![image](./note-gold/gold&real%20interest%20rate.png)--><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/gold&real%20interest%20rate.png" class=""><p>Now, the new logic behind the all-time high gold price is the global debt and credit, especially US government credit problem and debt monetization. There are only two ways to alleviate the current crisis.</p><ol><li>War</li><li>Technological progress + reshoring of high-value-added manufacturing<ul><li>the problem is reshoring of manufacturing impacts China’s interests and unavoidablely, this can cause the conflict between these two big countries.</li></ul></li></ol><p>Thus, as long as the credit problem is not solved, the gold price won’t come down.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Financial Notes</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Gold</tag>
      
      <tag>NPSOV</tag>
      
      <tag>D.E. Shaw</tag>
      
      <tag>World Gold Council</tag>
      
      <tag>Macro</tag>
      
      <tag>Commodity</tag>
      
      <tag>Portfolio Management</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 9/21/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/09/21/summary250921/"/>
    <url>/2025/09/21/summary250921/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week was dominated by central banks, with the U.S., UK, and Japan all holding key policy meetings.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.22%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+2.22%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.05%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+2.16%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-0.46%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-0.25%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+0.36%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.62%</font></li><li>TOPIX         <font color="red">-0.41%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.56% -&gt; <font color="red">3.58%</font></li><li>10yr          4.07% -&gt; <font color="red">4.13%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.68% -&gt; <font color="red">4.71%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.70% -&gt; <font color="red">2.75%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.51% -&gt; <font color="red">3.56%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.60% -&gt; <font color="red">1.64%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            62.6-&gt; <font color="green">62.7</font></li><li>Gold           3,644-&gt; <font color="green">3,682</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Rate-Cut-and-Record-Highs"><a href="#U-S-Market-Rate-Cut-and-Record-Highs" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Rate Cut and Record Highs"></a>U.S. Market: Rate Cut and Record Highs</h1><p>On Wednesday, the Federal Reserve cut interest rates by 0.25%, the first cut in nine months and a move that was in line with market expectations. The dot plot, which forecasts the future path of interest rates, showed the potential for two more cuts by the end of the year.</p><p>Fed Chair Powell described this as a “risk management” cut, suggesting that although economic data hadn’t significantly deteriorated and inflation remained a concern, the job market seemed to be weakening. Historically, rate-cutting cycles that begin before a full-blown economic downturn are often favorable for stocks. This sentiment, combined with other positive news like Nvidia’s investment in Intel, fueled an optimistic mood. As a result, the S&amp;P 500, Nasdaq, and Dow Jones all hit new record highs.</p><p>In contrast to the stock market, the bond market was more conservative. Since the Fed’s decision—both the size of the cut and the future forecast—didn’t exceed market expectations, and because weekly retail and employment data showed some improvement, U.S. Treasury yields rose slightly, causing bond prices to dip.</p><ul><li>Why does bond price go down after the interest rate cut?<ul><li>It is often called ‘buy the rumor, sell the news’. The market has already anticipate for almost 100% chance that the Fed will cut the rate. Thus, traders and investors had already bought bonds, pushing their prices up and yields down, in anticipation of the move (Check the yield curve for the past month, the yield keep going down).</li><li>When the Fed delivered exactly what was expected, there was no new information to cause a further rally. Instead, some traders likely “sold the news,” locking in profits from the anticipated rate cut.</li><li>The improving economic data contradicted the recession fears that had been building<ul><li>Retail Sales: The data showed that retail spending was improving, indicating that consumer demand remained resilient</li><li>Unemployment Claims: The number of new unemployment claims fell significantly for the week, pushing back against recent concerns of a rapid labor market deterioration</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Relative-Peacefull-Markets"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Relative-Peacefull-Markets" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Relative Peacefull Markets"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Relative Peacefull Markets</h1><p>There was little major news impacting Europe this week. The decline in U.S. bonds and news of an increase in German bond issuance pushed European bond prices down slightly. On Thursday, the Bank of England chose not to cut rates, and the UK’s fiscal deficit came in higher than expected. This raised market concerns about a potential fiscal crisis, leading to declines in both UK bonds and stocks.</p><p>Japan: On Friday, the Bank of Japan (BOJ) kept its interest rate unchanged, which was expected. However, the vote was split 7-2, with two members arguing for an immediate rate hike. This strengthened market expectations that the BOJ will resume rate hikes within the year, pushing Japanese bond yields higher and prices down. The BOJ also made an unexpected announcement that it would begin selling its vast holdings of ETFs and REITs. This decision put some downward pressure on the Japanese stock market. As a result, despite the positive momentum from U.S. stocks, the Nikkei index only saw a small gain, while the Topix index saw a slight loss.</p><ul><li>What the difference between Nikkei index and Topix index?<ul><li>Nikkei Index covers 225 the most liquid, blue-chip companies listed on the Tokyo Stock Exchange (TSE). It’s a price-weighted index</li><li>Topix Index covers all domestic stocks listed on the Tokyo Stock Exchange with market capitalization weight. Each individual stock influence is capped at 10%.</li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Commodities-Clear-Logic"><a href="#Commodities-Clear-Logic" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Clear Logic"></a>Commodities: Clear Logic</h1><p>The logic for commodities was clear. The Fed’s rate cut boosted market sentiment and lowered the opportunity cost of holding gold, pushing gold prices to a new all-time high.</p><p>Important news affecting oil prices was scarce this week. Oil prices fluctuated slightly in response to changes in supply expectations for Russian crude but ultimately closed the week unchanged.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 9/14/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/09/13/summary250914/"/>
    <url>/2025/09/13/summary250914/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, several major events influenced the market, but the logic was very clear. Simply put, the U.S. pays attention to the data, while Europe and Japan focus on the events. Let’s take a look at each region.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.59%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+1.86%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+0.95%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+0.24%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.47%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.43%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+1.96%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+4.07%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.52% -&gt; <font color="red">3.56%</font></li><li>10yr          4.08% -&gt; <font color="green">4.07%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.65% -&gt; <font color="red">4.68%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.66% -&gt; <font color="red">2.7%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.45% -&gt; <font color="red">3.50%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.57% -&gt; <font color="red">1.60%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            62.2-&gt; <font color="green">62.6</font></li><li>Gold           3,590-&gt; <font color="green">3,642</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Data-Driven-Optimism"><a href="#U-S-Market-Data-Driven-Optimism" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Data-Driven Optimism"></a>U.S. Market: Data-Driven Optimism</h1><p>This week, the U.S. released the final batch of key economic data before the next Federal Reserve meeting. Inflation data showed that PPI was lower than expected, while CPI was slightly higher. Employment data remained weak, with a significant downward revision to annual non-farm employment and a much higher-than-expected number of new unemployment claims.</p><p>This data further solidified the market’s expectation of a Fed rate cut, fueling optimistic sentiment and providing upward momentum for U.S. stocks. The S&amp;P 500, Nasdaq, and Dow Jones all hit new record highs. U.S. stock gains also drove a rally in European markets.</p><ul><li>why market believe unemployment rate is more important for FED rate decision?<ul><li>Let’s first break down the CPI data. <ul><li>Core consumer prices, which exclude food and energy, rose by 0.3% from the previous month in August of 2025, the same pace as in July, in line with market forecasts.</li><li>The major pushup factor is shelter, 0.4%. But the data of shelter in CPI is very lagged. If you check Zillow Rent Index or New Tennant Rent Index, they are actually much lower, which indicates that in the future CPI calculation, shelter will not be a big concern for inflation.</li><li>Import Prices MoM is 0.4, which is mainly caused by Tariffs. But it takes time to pass this cost to consumers. Also, corporations will absort some cost changes and this won’t be fully reflected to the price.</li></ul></li><li>The rising unemployment rate and slowing job growth can be viewed as a leading indicator that inflation will naturally come down on its own. Here’s the logic:<ul><li>A weakening labor market means less wage growth.</li><li>Less wage growth means consumers have less money to spend.</li><li>Reduced consumer demand puts downward pressure on businesses to lower prices to attract customers.</li></ul></li><li>Overall, unemployment issue is the most important for FED to make decision.</li></ul></li></ul><p>Another major force behind the U.S. stock rally was the continued excitement over AI investment. This week, Oracle released its earnings report, and its recent major contracts—including several from OpenAI—sent its stock soaring. This surge briefly pushed Oracle’s founder, Larry Ellison, to the top of the list of the world’s wealthiest people.</p><p>Since the expectation of a September rate cut was already priced into U.S. Treasury bonds, their prices saw little change this week.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Event-Driven-Concern"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Event-Driven-Concern" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Event-Driven Concern"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Event-Driven Concern</h1><p>In France, the Béroux cabinet ultimately failed to pass a no-confidence vote. President Macron appointed Lecomte as the new Prime Minister, but the new government still faces a fiscal challenge with the budget. The market, wary of a potential French fiscal crisis, saw French bonds come under further selling pressure. On Thursday, the European Central Bank (ECB) kept its policy rate unchanged, which was in line with expectations. However, it also slightly raised its economic forecast, a move interpreted as a hawkish signal that the rate-cutting cycle may be ending. This also contributed to the decline in European bond prices.</p><p>In Japan, Shigeru Ishiba announced his resignation as Prime Minister on Sunday evening. The market is now anticipating that the next leader may pursue a more aggressive fiscal policy. This, combined with the rally in U.S. stocks, fueled a significant surge in Japanese stocks. The prospect of fiscal expansion and increased bond issuance put downward pressure on Japanese bond prices, but speculation that political uncertainty might delay a rate hike by the Bank of Japan provided some counterbalance. As a result, Japanese bonds only saw a slight decline.</p><ul><li>What is Shigeru Ishiba’s political stand? And why his stepdown impact Japanese market in this direction?<ul><li>Shigeru Ishiba is a Japanese politician known for his fiscally conservative and against the ultra-loose monetary policy. </li><li>The market viewed Ishiba’s resignation as an opportunity for the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) to select a new leader who would pursue a more aggressive fiscal policy, which can boost economic growth and has a positive catalyst for equities. </li><li>When a government increases spending, it must issue more bonds to cover the deficit. This increase in the supply of bonds can overwhelm market demand, causing their prices to fall and their yields to rise.</li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences"><a href="#Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences"></a>Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences</h1><p>This week, both the Russia-Ukraine and Middle East conflicts escalated, with the resulting supply-side security concerns putting upward pressure on oil prices. However, weak U.S. employment data raised fears of an economic slowdown and a reduction in energy demand, which curbed the price rally. As a result, oil prices saw only a small increase.</p><p>Gold prices, primarily driven by U.S. rate cut expectations, continued their ascent and hit a new record high.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 9/7/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/09/07/summary250907/"/>
    <url>/2025/09/07/summary250907/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, global markets were primarily driven by U.S. employment data. However, since the data releases were concentrated from Wednesday onwards, the beginning of the week was dominated by concerns over fiscal deterioration in various countries.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.33%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+1.01%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-0.32%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+1.04%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.34%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-1.28%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-0.42%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.70%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.64% -&gt; <font color="green">3.52%</font></li><li>10yr          4.26% -&gt; <font color="green">4.08%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.72% -&gt; <font color="green">4.65%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.72% -&gt; <font color="green">2.67%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.51% -&gt; <font color="green">3.45%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.60% -&gt; <font color="green">1.58%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            64.0-&gt; <font color="red">62.0</font></li><li>Gold           3,448-&gt; <font color="green">3,587</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Tariffs-and-Employment-Reports"><a href="#U-S-Market-Tariffs-and-Employment-Reports" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Tariffs and Employment Reports"></a>U.S. Market: Tariffs and Employment Reports</h1><p>Early in the week, a court ruling that Trump’s reciprocal tariffs were unconstitutional sparked concerns that a final verdict would force the government to refund tariffs, widening the fiscal deficit. These worries led to </p><ul><li>a drop in U.S. bond prices <ul><li>reasons:<ol><li>Increased Supply of Bonds: To refund the billions of dollars in tariffs, the U.S. government would need to borrow money by issuing more Treasury bonds. </li><li>Decreased Demand of Bonds: A widening fiscal deficit can raise concerns about the government’s long-term fiscal health. Thus reducing the bond demand. To compensate for this increased risk, investors would demand a higher return, which also pushes bond yields up and prices down</li></ol></li></ul></li><li>downward pressure on the stock market.<ul><li>reasons: <ol><li>Rising Interest Rates: When Treasury yields rise, all other interest rates, including those for corporate and personal loans, hikes as well. Higher borrowing costs for companies can cut into their profits and slow down expansion plans. For consumers, higher interest rates on mortgages, auto loans, and other credit can dampen spending. Thus the whole economy will slow down.</li><li>Impact on Valuation: Higher interest rates also make stocks less attractive to investors. A higher discount rate means a lower present value for the stock, putting downward pressure on stock prices.</li><li>Reduced Investor Confidence: A new element of political and economic uncertainty is introduced. This “uncertainty tax” can cause businesses to delay investment and consumers to become more cautious, both of which can lead to a slowing economy. Such a pessimistic outlook makes investors more risk-averse, prompting a flight from stocks into safer assets.</li></ol></li></ul></li></ul><p>However, the trend was dramatically reversed from Wednesday to Friday with a series of three weak U.S. employment reports. The data showed a decline in job openings, lower-than-expected payroll growth, and an increase in unemployment claims. The deteriorating employment picture intensified market expectations for a Federal Reserve rate cut. The market is now highly confident of a rate cut in September, with some even anticipating an aggressive 0.5% reduction. This concern leads to</p><ul><li>Treasury yields are pushed down<ul><li>reasons:<ol><li>the Fed Fund rate is the major impact of the treasury yield, especially the short term.</li></ol></li></ul></li><li>The impact on stocks was more mixed. On one hand, rate cut expectations served as a catalyst, but on the other, the consecutive weak employment reports fueled fears of an economic recession. Amid this push and pull, U.S. stocks ended the week slightly higher.<ul><li>A major driver for the tech sector was Google’s legal victory in an antitrust case, which prevented its Chrome browser business from being broken up. This win was a “win-win” for both Google and Apple, securing a key business for Google and protecting its lucrative deal to be the default search engine on Apple devices. The news boosted both companies’ share prices and propelled the Nasdaq index.</li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Political-and-Economic-Tensions"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Political-and-Economic-Tensions" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Political and Economic Tensions"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Political and Economic Tensions</h1><p>Like the U.S., European markets were initially weighed down by fiscal worries, including a potential no-confidence vote in the French government and the UK’s challenging budget discussions. However, they were eventually lifted by the positive spillover from the U.S. bond and stock rallies.</p><p>Both the Japanese bond and stock markets ended the week higher.</p><ul><li>Bond: Calls for an early leadership election within the Liberal Democratic Party to oust fiscally conservative Prime Minister Ishiba raised concerns about potential fiscal expansion. This put downward pressure on Japanese bonds, but the stronger influence of rising U.S. bond prices ultimately led to a small gain.<ul><li>Why concerns about potential fiscal expansion can put downward pressure on Japanese bond prices <ol><li>Suppy &amp; Demand: Fiscal expansion comes alone with issuing new government bonds. This increase in the supply of bonds in the market can overwhelm demand, causing bond prices to fall.</li><li>Inflationary Expectations: Significant fiscal expansion can be seen as inflationary. By injecting more money into the economy, it can lead to higher prices. Bondholders are particularly sensitive to inflation because it erodes the future purchasing power of their fixed interest payments. To compensate for this risk, investors will sell their existing bonds, driving down prices and pushing up yields.</li></ol></li></ul></li><li>Stocks: Japanese stocks were boosted by the rally in U.S. tech stocks and the finalization of a U.S. tariff on Japan at a moderate 15%, which was less severe than the market had initially feared.<ul><li>Why the finalization of a U.S. tariff on Japan at a moderate 15% boosted Japanese stocks<ol><li>Removal of Uncertainty: Markets dislike uncertainty. The finalization of a rate, even a punitive one, allows businesses to plan and adjust. The absence of this major unknown is a positive for market stability and investor confidence. Plus, the initial fears of the possibility of a much higher tarrif rate, possibly as high as 25% or more, or a broader range of products being targeted, creates a positive surprise comparing to this moderate 15%.</li><li>Managed Economic Impact: A 15% tariff, while not ideal, is a manageable headwind for many Japanese export-oriented companies. They can potentially absorb some of the cost, pass a portion on to consumers, or adjust their supply chains to mitigate the impact. A higher tariff could have been a catastrophic shock, but a moderate one is a challenge that can be overcome, which reassures investors about the profitability and stability of Japanese corporations.</li></ol></li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences"><a href="#Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences"></a>Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences</h1><p>The expectation of a rate cut lowered the opportunity cost of holding gold, while mounting fears of a recession increased demand for safe-haven assets. These two factors combined to drive a significant increase in gold prices.</p><p>Oil prices, on the other hand, fell. The market is anticipating that OPEC may decide to increase production at its September 7th ministerial meeting, while recession fears have lowered demand expectations. The combination of increased supply and decreased demand put strong downward pressure on oil prices.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Structure of FOMC and Who Are Trump&#39;s People</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/31/note-FED/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/31/note-FED/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Fed’s primary monetary policy-making body, the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC), has 12 voting members. Of these, seven seats are permanently held by the seven members of the Board of Governors. The remaining five seats rotate among the presidents of the 12 regional Federal Reserve banks.</p><p>A governor’s term is an extensive 14 years, with a new seat expiring every two years. This staggered system ensures a degree of policy continuity. Under this design, a president can, in theory, appoint at least two governors during a single term, allowing them to shape the Fed’s long-term policy direction.</p><p>So, who on the current Board of Governors can be considered “Trump’s people?”</p><p>During his first term, Trump appointed two governors: Michelle Bowman and Christopher Waller. Both of them voted in favor of a rate cut at the July meeting. However, it’s clear that the current Fed, led by Chairman Jerome Powell (also a Trump appointee in 2018), has not fully aligned with Trump’s aggressive push for rapid rate cuts to stimulate the economy and ease the government’s interest burden.</p><p>It’s precisely this lack of full alignment that has made Trump eager to exert greater influence through new appointments.</p><p>Based on the staggered term schedule, Trump has two theoretical opportunities to appoint new governors during his second term:</p><ul><li>The first opportunity is in January 2026.</li><li>The second is when Powell’s term as a governor expires in 2028.</li></ul><p>However, waiting until 2028 is not an ideal option if he wants to see immediate policy changes. This timeline explains his recent urgency to find additional opportunities to place his own people on the board and steer the Fed toward his desired course.</p><table><thead><tr><th>Name &amp; Position</th><th>Governor Term</th><th>Appointing President</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Jerome H. Powell (Chair)</td><td>May 2012 (Jun 2014 reappointment) - Jan 2028</td><td>Donald Trump</td></tr><tr><td>Philip N. Jefferson: (Vice Chair)</td><td>May 2022 - Jan 2036</td><td>Joe Biden</td></tr><tr><td>Michelle W. Bowman: (Vice Chair for Supervision)</td><td>Nov 2018 (Feb 2020 reappointment) - Jan 2034</td><td>Donald Trump</td></tr><tr><td>Lisa D. Cook</td><td>May 2022 (Feb 2024 reappointment) - Jan 2038</td><td>Joe Biden</td></tr><tr><td>Michael S. Barr</td><td>Jul 2022 - Jan 2032</td><td>Joe Biden</td></tr><tr><td>Christopher J. Waller</td><td>Dec 2020 - Jan 2030</td><td>Donald Trump</td></tr><tr><td>Vacant</td><td>TBD</td><td>TBD</td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Financial Notes</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>FED</tag>
      
      <tag>FOMC</tag>
      
      <tag>Interest Rate</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/31/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/31/summary250831/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/31/summary250831/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week was light on major economic data, but a pair of big stories broke on Monday, one in the U.S. and one in Europe. In the U.S., Donald Trump fired Federal Reserve Governor Lisa Cook. In Europe, the French Prime Minister initiated a no-confidence vote in the government. These two events became the central themes for their respective markets this week. Let’s break down the details.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="red">-0.10%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-0.35%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-0.19%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+0.19%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-1.55%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-1.89%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-3.34%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.20%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.71% -&gt; <font color="green">3.63%</font></li><li>10yr          4.26% -&gt; <font color="green">4.23%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.70% -&gt; <font color="red">4.72%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.75% -&gt; <font color="green">2.72%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.42% -&gt; <font color="red">3.51%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.62% -&gt; <font color="green">1.61%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            63.7-&gt; <font color="green">64.0</font></li><li>Gold           3,367-&gt; <font color="green">3,448</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-The-Fed-Controversy"><a href="#U-S-Market-The-Fed-Controversy" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: The Fed Controversy"></a>U.S. Market: The Fed Controversy</h1><p>The drama surrounding the firing of Fed Governor Lisa Cook, a recent Biden appointee with a term lasting until 2038, quickly took center stage. Trump accused her of fraud during a mortgage application and fired her. It is very clear attempt by Trump to create an open seat for a loyalist he could appoint (For more details on FOMC Committee. Check this <a href="https://harrisonpan1.github.io/2025/08/31/note-FED/">post</a>).</p><p>From a short-term perspective, Trump’s move to exert greater control over the Fed was seen as a push for his rate-cutting agenda. This strengthened market expectations for a rate cut and boosted U.S. bond prices. However, this action also compromises the Fed’s independence, which increases long-term inflation risk. This put pressure on the long end of the yield curve. As a result, U.S. bonds saw overall price increases, but the yield curve became steeper.</p><p>Other news included Friday’s PCE data, which largely met expectations and had little impact on rate cut forecasts. The auctions for 2, 5, and 7-year Treasury notes also showed relatively solid demand.</p><p>On the stock side, U.S. markets were already facing significant profit-taking pressure after recent gains. The modest NVDA’s earning outlook also added the downward pressure. Thus, despite the support from rate cut expectations, these combined factors led to a slight decline in U.S. stocks for the week.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Political-and-Economic-Tensions"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Political-and-Economic-Tensions" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Political and Economic Tensions"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Political and Economic Tensions</h1><p>The French no-confidence vote, triggered by a budget impasse, created the risk of the Bayrou government collapsing. The market, fearing political chaos and a potential fiscal crisis, put selling pressure on both French bonds and stocks, which in turn dragged down the broader European market. Money fleeing France for safer havens caused the yield spread between German and French bonds to widen. The minutes from the European Central Bank (ECB) meeting, which showed a more cautious stance on rate cuts, along with slightly higher-than-expected German inflation data, also contributed to the decline in European bond prices.</p><p>In Japan, the stock market saw little change, while facing the selling pressure from month-end portfolio rebalancing. In the bond market, the Bank of Japan governor’s speech at last week’s central banking conference hinted at a continued rate cut path, which should have pushed bond yields higher. However, market expectations that the government would reduce the issuance of super-long-term bonds offset this, resulting in a slight weekly decline in yields (a small price increase).</p><h1 id="Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences"><a href="#Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences"></a>Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences</h1><p>The news of Ukrainian strikes on Russian energy facilities triggered supply concerns, ultimately causing oil prices to rise slightly.</p><p>Gold prices also moved higher, largely benefiting from the Fed controversy. The firing of the governor strengthened expectations for a rate cut, increased long-term inflation risk, and damaged the Fed’s independence. All three of these factors served to push gold prices higher.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/24/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/24/summary250824/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/24/summary250824/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, the market’s primary focus was on two key developments: Jerome Powell’s Jackson Hole talk and the ongoing situation in Ukraine. Let’s break down the details.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.36%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-0.44%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.66%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+3.22%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+2.10%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.02%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+0.58%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="red">-2.26%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.76% -&gt; <font color="green">3.71%</font></li><li>10yr          4.32% -&gt; <font color="green">4.26%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.70% -&gt; <font color="green">4.70%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.79% -&gt; <font color="green">2.73%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.47% -&gt; <font color="green">3.42%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.59% -&gt; <font color="red">1.62%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            63.2-&gt; <font color="green">63.7</font></li><li>Gold           3,335-&gt; <font color="green">3,371</font></li></ul><h1 id="US-Markets-The-Anticipation-and-Reveal"><a href="#US-Markets-The-Anticipation-and-Reveal" class="headerlink" title="US Markets: The Anticipation and Reveal"></a>US Markets: The Anticipation and Reveal</h1><p>For the past few weeks, a prevailing market narrative has been the expectation of a Fed rate cut in September. This was fueled by a combination of weakening U.S. economic data and the realization that inflation from tariffs wasn’t as high as initially feared. However, this was just market speculation. The real validation had to come from the Fed itself. </p><p>Thus from Monday to Thursday, the market was in a state of cautious observation. The S&amp;P 500, having seen significant gains recently, faced selling pressure and registered four consecutive days of small declines.</p><p>On Friday, however, Powell’s speech revealed the Fed’s stance. He stated that the current policy rate is tight and that employment-related risks are significant, making a policy adjustment a “reasonable option.” While the wording was cautious, the market immediately caught the signal of a coming rate cut. In response, U.S. Treasury yields fell, and bond prices rose.</p><p>The mood in the U.S. stock market returned to optimism, and markets put the odds of a September cut at 90%. All previous downward trend sharply reversed on Friday. Most major U.S. indices saw gains, with the Nasdaq being the only exception. Despite a strong Friday rebound, it still closed slightly down for the week after its earlier sharp declines.</p><h1 id="European-Japanese-Markets-Divergent-Paths"><a href="#European-Japanese-Markets-Divergent-Paths" class="headerlink" title="European &amp; Japanese Markets: Divergent Paths"></a>European &amp; Japanese Markets: Divergent Paths</h1><p>European markets, in addition to being affected by the Fed’s rate cut signals, also closely watched developments in the Ukraine-Russia situation. On Monday, European and Ukrainian leaders met with Donald Trump, and the market’s hope for a swift resolution to the conflict helped boost European stocks. However, after several weeks of continuous gains, the stock markets in Germany and France showed some fatigue and struggled to rise further.</p><p>The anticipated de-escalation of the conflict should have, in theory, reduced safe-haven demand and pushed European bond prices lower. However, the market adopted a wait-and-see approach, so the downward pressure on bonds was limited. Instead, the rally in U.S. bonds had a more pronounced effect, pulling European bonds higher. The notable exception was the UK, where higher-than-expected CPI data reduced expectations of a Bank of England rate cut, causing UK bonds to underperform their German and French counterparts.</p><p>n Japan, both government bonds and stocks saw declines, showing a trend opposite to that of Europe. This was partly due to the time difference—the Fed’s signal came too late to fully impact the Japanese market. Another key factor was internal: after hitting a record high the previous week, the Japanese stock market faced significant selling pressure. This, combined with the decline in U.S. tech stocks, led to a weekly drop. The decline in Japanese government bonds primarily reflected market caution about fiscal expansion, which was evident in weak demand during this week’s bond auctions and the Bank of Japan’s bond purchase operations.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Riding-the-Wave"><a href="#Commodities-Riding-the-Wave" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Riding the Wave"></a>Commodities: Riding the Wave</h1><p>The Fed’s rate cut signal, along with general market optimism, boosted demand expectations and contributed to a small increase in oil prices.</p><p>Gold also saw a modest rise, mainly influenced by U.S. Treasury yields. Since bond yields reflect the opportunity cost of holding gold, falling U.S. Treasury yields make gold relatively more attractive, thus pushing its price higher.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/17/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/17/summary250817/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/17/summary250817/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market trend was largely a continuation of the previous week’s momentum.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.94%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+0.81%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.74%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+3.07%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.47%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.81%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+2.33%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+3.73%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.77% -&gt; <font color="green">3.76%</font></li><li>10yr          4.29% -&gt; <font color="red">4.32%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.60% -&gt; <font color="red">4.70%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.69% -&gt; <font color="red">2.79%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.35% -&gt; <font color="red">3.46%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.49% -&gt; <font color="red">1.56%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            63.4-&gt; <font color="red">63.2</font></li><li>Gold           3,458-&gt; <font color="red">3,382</font></li></ul><h1 id="US-Markets"><a href="#US-Markets" class="headerlink" title="US Markets"></a>US Markets</h1><p>After a significant downward revision of U.S. employment data two weeks ago, the market broadly anticipated that the Federal Reserve would resume interest rate cuts in September. Last week’s weaker economic data further strengthened this expectation, leading to the current bullish sentiment and rising stock prices.</p><p>This week the increase in core CPI and a higher-than-expected PPI reading both reminded that the  inflationary pressure still exists. Consequently, inflation concerns pushed long-term yields higher, while rate cut expectations drove short-term yields lower, resulting in a steeper U.S. Treasury yield curve.</p><p>The stock market, however, focused more on the potential for a near-term rate cut, making the CPI data a positive catalyst for U.S. stocks. The additional news that Trump extended China tariff deadline by 90 days further eased trade war concerns. This combination of factors fueled optimism, pushing the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq to new record highs.</p><h1 id="European-and-Japanese-Markets"><a href="#European-and-Japanese-Markets" class="headerlink" title="European and Japanese Markets"></a>European and Japanese Markets</h1><p>Following the lead of the U.S. market, European stock markets generally rose, while government bond prices fell. Another key factor influencing European markets was the Trump-Putin meeting on Friday. Although the meeting took place after the European market close, the week’s rising expectation of a de-escalation in the Russia-Ukraine situation contributed to the rally in European stocks. The reduction in safe-haven demand, in turn, drove down European bond prices.</p><p>In Japan, the market experienced a similar trend of rising stocks and falling bonds, with the Nikkei 225 once again reaching a new historical high. The reasons behind this, in addition to the momentum from the U.S. market, included better-than-expected Q2 GDP growth, which boosted market confidence. This strong GDP data suggested that the Bank of Japan would have more room to consider resuming rate hikes. This, combined with high market sentiment and the flow of capital from bonds to stocks, collectively pushed Japanese government bond yields higher and prices lower.</p><h1 id="Commodities"><a href="#Commodities" class="headerlink" title="Commodities"></a>Commodities</h1><p>EIA (Energy Information Administration) data this week indicated an increase in oil inventories. On Friday, China’s industrial production and retail sales data raised market concerns about weakening energy demand. These two factors together caused a slight dip in oil prices.</p><p>For gold, the tariff-related turmoil that had temporarily boosted prices last week subsided. This week, rising government bond yields increased the opportunity cost of holding gold, putting downward pressure on its price. As a result, gold saw a small decline.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/10/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/10/summary250810/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/10/summary250810/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market trend was reversed from last week. European and US stocks bounced back and government bonds fell. This was largely due to shifting expectations around the Fed’s next move.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+2.43%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+3.73%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.35%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+2.67%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.3%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+3.15%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+2.59%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+2.5%</font></li><li>NK1!          <font color="green">+2.4%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.70% -&gt; <font color="red">3.77%</font></li><li>10yr          4.23% -&gt; <font color="red">4.29%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.53% -&gt; <font color="red">4.60%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.68% -&gt; <font color="red">2.69%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.35% -&gt; <font color="red">3.35%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.51% -&gt; <font color="green">1.49%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            67.3-&gt; <font color="red">63.8</font></li><li>Gold           3426-&gt; <font color="green">3491</font></li></ul><h1 id="The-Fed-and-US-Markets"><a href="#The-Fed-and-US-Markets" class="headerlink" title="The Fed and US Markets"></a>The Fed and US Markets</h1><p>The primary driver this week was a major shift in Fed rate cut expectations. Last Friday, weaker-than-expected Non-Farm Payroll (NFP) data led to a market sell-off, as investors worried about a potential recession. This week, however, investors focused on the silver lining: the weak data solidified expectations that the Fed would need to restart rate cuts soon to stimulate the economy.</p><p>Further weak economic data this week reinforced this sentiment (weaker ISM Services PMI &amp; higher Continuing Jobless Claims). As a result, the market now prices in an almost 90% probability of a Fed rate cut in September. Some analysts are even suggesting a “double-speed” cut of 0.5% if August and September data continue to be disappointed.</p><p>This optimistic outlook, combined with the weekend cooling off of last week’s panic, fueled a significant rally in US stocks. The Nasdaq, in particular, broke a new all-time high, largely driven by strong performance in technology stocks like Apple, which saw its share price surge on news it might be exempt from certain chip tariffs.</p><p>On the bond side, US Treasury yields rose this week (prices fell). While rate cut expectations typically support bonds, the market stepped back. This was partly due to caution over new tariffs that went into effect on August 7th and their potential impact on inflation. Additionally, news that Fed Governor Christopher Waller, a moderate on rate cuts, is a potential candidate for the next Fed Chair dampened expectations for a more aggressive easing cycle after 2025. These factors, along with poor performance in this week’s Treasury auctions, led to a pullback in bond prices.</p><h1 id="European-and-Japanese-Markets"><a href="#European-and-Japanese-Markets" class="headerlink" title="European and Japanese Markets"></a>European and Japanese Markets</h1><p>European markets largely followed the US trend, with stocks rising and bond yields climbing. News about ceasefire in the Russia-Ukraine conflict and a planned meeting between President Trump and the two leaders, also helped boost European stock sentiment.</p><p>The Bank of England (BoE) cut rates as expected this week, but the vote was close, with four of the nine committee members opposing the move. This led the market to lower its expectations for the future pace of rate cuts, causing the UK market to underperform its German and French counterparts.</p><p>The Japanese market also saw a significant rally, with the TOPIX index hitting a new all-time high. This was driven by a strong round of corporate earnings reports from major Japanese companies like SoftBank and Sony, as well as the positive spillover effect from the US market’s rally. Japanese government bonds, however, moved slightly higher in price (yields fell slightly), running counter to the trend in the US and Europe. This was mainly due to the time difference; the Japanese bond market’s performance still largely reflected the safe-haven sentiment from last Friday’s weak US jobs report.</p><h1 id="Commodities"><a href="#Commodities" class="headerlink" title="Commodities"></a>Commodities</h1><p>Gold prices saw a slight increase. The Fed’s expected rate cuts weakened the US dollar, which often provides upward momentum for gold. Additionally, new tariffs announced on Friday also contributed to gold’s safe-haven appeal.</p><p>Oil prices fell slightly this week. Weak US economic data lowered demand expectations, while the potential for a Russia-Ukraine ceasefire increased supply expectations. These two factors combined to push prices down.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/3/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/03/summary250803/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/03/summary250803/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market dynamics can be traced along two main threads: <strong>trade negotiations</strong> and <strong>central banks policies</strong>.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        -2.46%</li><li>Nasdaq        -2.57%</li><li>Dow30         -2.75%</li><li>Russell2000   -4.09%</li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       -0.57%</li><li>DAX           -3.27%</li><li>CAC           -3.68%</li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         -1.19%</li><li>NK            -2.65%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.94% -&gt; 3.70%</li><li>10yr          4.40% -&gt; 4.225%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.61% -&gt; 4.53%</li><li>DE10yr        2.73% -&gt; 2.67%</li><li>FR10yr        3.39% -&gt; 3.35%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.60% -&gt; 1.55%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI           65.34 -&gt; 67.25</li><li>Gold          3331 -&gt; 3363</li></ul><h1 id="Trade-Negotiations"><a href="#Trade-Negotiations" class="headerlink" title="Trade Negotiations"></a>Trade Negotiations</h1><p>This week saw a series of trade talks involving the US-EU, US-China, and US-South Korea. From the perspective of avoiding an escalation of the trade war, this was positive news.</p><p>However, the market had already priced in these agreements. Instead, attention shifted to the potential impact of the new tariffs on the global economy, leading to cautious sentiment. This is one of the main reasons European stocks fell instead of rising after the deals were announced.</p><p>As the August 1st deadline approached, President Trump signed a new tariff order on July 31st, further heightening market anxiety and putting downward pressure on US stocks.</p><h1 id="Fed-Reserve-and-Economic-Data"><a href="#Fed-Reserve-and-Economic-Data" class="headerlink" title="Fed Reserve and Economic Data"></a>Fed Reserve and Economic Data</h1><p>On Wednesday, the Fed kept interest rates unchanged (as expected), but the Fed Chair downplayed expectations for a September rate cut during the press conference. This hit the stock market and also put downward pressure on bond prices (pushing yields up).</p><p>However, on Friday, both the Non-Farm Payroll (NFP) and PMI data came in weaker than expected. Meanwile, the NFP of May and June were revised down about 90%, way larger than normal. This led the market to believe the Fed would have to restart rate cuts sooner to counter the risk of an economic recession.</p><p>This reversal in expectations ultimately led to US bond yields falling (prices rising). At the same time, concerns about a recession intensified selling pressure on stocks, causing the US market to pull back significantly from its highs.</p><p>This also impact the Europe stock and bond market. Both European bond yields and stocks trended lower on Friday.</p><h1 id="Japanese-Market"><a href="#Japanese-Market" class="headerlink" title="Japanese Market"></a>Japanese Market</h1><p>On Thursday, the Bank of Japan (BoJ) announced that it would not raise interest rates for now and raised its inflation forecast for this year and next.</p><p>Governor Kazuo Ueda’s comments were also conservative. This pushed Japanese government bond yields slightly lower (prices rose slightly). He also mentioned that the current yen Exchange Rates has not deviated significantly from the Bank of Japan’s expectations and will not have a significant impact on the price outlook. This was interpreted by the market as the BoJ tolerating a weaker yen, which triggered a yen sell-off.</p><p>In theory, no rate hike and a weaker yen are positive for Japanese stocks. However, two stronger factors dominated: profit-taking pressure after last week’s major rally and the drag from falling US stocks. Therefore, Japanese stocks ended the week lower.</p><p><strong><em>NOTE:</em></strong> Due to the time difference, the closing price of the Japanese market on Friday did not fully reflect the negative sentiment from the late-day drop in US stocks caused by weak data. If you look at the performance of Nikkei futures, their decline was comparable to that of US and European markets.</p><h1 id="Crude-Oil"><a href="#Crude-Oil" class="headerlink" title="Crude Oil"></a>Crude Oil</h1><p>Prices rose slightly, driven by two factors:</p><ul><li><p>Demand Side: Progress in trade negotiations reduced uncertainty about demand.</p></li><li><p>Supply Side: News that President Trump would advance sanctions on Russian energy exports created supply-side anxiety.</p></li></ul><h1 id="Gold"><a href="#Gold" class="headerlink" title="Gold"></a>Gold</h1><p>Prices increased slightly, mainly influenced by US Treasury yields. Holding gold does not generate interest, so government bond yields represent the opportunity cost of holding gold. Thus, the decline in US Treasury yields this week lowered the opportunity cost of investing in gold, pushing its price higher.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Robinhood Trading Risk Management Tool</title>
    <link href="/2025/07/30/Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management/"/>
    <url>/2025/07/30/Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Level-Up-Your-Robinhood-Trading-A-Free-Open-Source-Journal-and-Risk-Manager"><a href="#Level-Up-Your-Robinhood-Trading-A-Free-Open-Source-Journal-and-Risk-Manager" class="headerlink" title="Level Up Your Robinhood Trading: A Free, Open-Source Journal and Risk Manager"></a>Level Up Your Robinhood Trading: A Free, Open-Source Journal and Risk Manager</h2><p>Trading on Robinhood is a double-edged sword. The accessibility is incredible, but for the new age of investors diving into high-risk, high-reward options and volatile stocks, there’s a distinct lack of professional-grade tools to manage that risk. When you’re making complex plays, flying blind is the fastest way to crash.</p><p>That’s why I’m excited to share the <a href="https://github.com/harrisonpan1/Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management.git">Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management</a>, a free, open-source project built with Python. It can help to keep track of your trading logs and portfolio option greek risk.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-developed Project</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Option</tag>
      
      <tag>Risk Management</tag>
      
      <tag>Robinhood</tag>
      
      <tag>Trading</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 7/27/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/07/27/summary250727/"/>
    <url>/2025/07/27/summary250727/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market logic is quite clear, though the details can get a bit complex. Let’s break it down.</p><h1 id="Japan-Election-Upset-and-the-Bond-Market-Paradox"><a href="#Japan-Election-Upset-and-the-Bond-Market-Paradox" class="headerlink" title="Japan Election Upset and the Bond Market Paradox"></a>Japan Election Upset and the Bond Market Paradox</h1><p>The week’s biggest story started in Japan. Over the weekend, the ruling coalition led by Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba suffered a major defeat in the upper house election, losing its majority. This turns the Ishiba cabinet into a minority government, sparking media speculation that the Prime Minister might resign.</p><p>From a market perspective, this created a complex reaction to Japanese Government Bonds (JGBs):</p><ul><li><strong>Pre-Election Jitters:</strong> Markets had already anticipated an imminent opposition victory. Because the opposition parties generally advocate for expansionary fiscal policy, investors grew concerned about Japan’s deficit and the potential for an over-issuance of government bonds. This led to a sell-off in JGBs starting from early this month.</li><li><strong>Post-Election Reversal:</strong> While the ruling coalition lost, the defeat wasn’t as severe as many had feared. This eased concerns about runaway fiscal spending, which in turn reduced the pressure to sell JGBs.</li><li><strong>Political Risk:</strong> At the same time, the prospect of a minority government and a potential prime minister resignation increased political uncertainty. This boosted safe-haven demand, creating buying pressure for JGBs.</li></ul><p>Based on these factors, one would expect JGB prices to rise. So why did they fall (<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/JP10Y-JP">JP10y 1.532% -&gt; 1.603%</a>)?</p><h1 id="The-Game-Changer-The-US-Japan-Trade-Agreement"><a href="#The-Game-Changer-The-US-Japan-Trade-Agreement" class="headerlink" title="The Game Changer: The US-Japan Trade Agreement"></a>The Game Changer: The US-Japan Trade Agreement</h1><p>The answer lies in the week’s other major news story. On the evening of July 22nd, President Trump announced that the US and Japan had reached a trade agreement. Key terms include a $550 billion investment by Japan in the United States and a reduction of US tariffs on Japanese goods to 15%.</p><p>This news injected a massive dose of optimism into the market:</p><ul><li><strong>Japanese and US Stocks Soared:</strong> Japanese stocks, particularly in the auto sector, surged on the news. This optimism spread to the US, where strong earnings reports (with over 80% of companies beating profit expectations) also helped push the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq to new record highs.</li><li><strong>Safe-Haven Demand Faded:</strong> The positive sentiment caused capital to flow from the safety of bonds into equities. For Japan, the stable trade environment also increased the likelihood that the Bank of Japan could consider restarting interest rate hikes in the future. This created immense downward pressure on Japanese bonds, ultimately overwhelming the upward push from the election results.</li></ul><p>Consequently, JGB yields rose significantly (ie. prices fell).</p><h1 id="US-Treasuries-and-The-Fed"><a href="#US-Treasuries-and-The-Fed" class="headerlink" title="US Treasuries and The Fed"></a>US Treasuries and The Fed</h1><p>On Thursday, President Trump visited the Federal Reserve in Washington, D.C., to review building renovations. He tried to use the $2 billion renovation costs to ramp up political pressure on Chairman Jerome Powell to lower the benchmark interest rate. <a href="https://www.ustreasuryyieldcurve.com/b/gsThlo">This reversed the logic from the previous week, causing the US Treasury yield curve to flatten, as long-term yields fell.</a></p><h1 id="A-Look-at-Europe"><a href="#A-Look-at-Europe" class="headerlink" title="A Look at Europe"></a>A Look at Europe</h1><ul><li><strong>ECB:</strong> The European Central Bank held interest rates steady at 2% on Thursday, pausing its year-long policy easing cycle and adopting a “wait-and-see” approach on future rate cuts. This was in line with expectations and had little market impact.</li><li><strong>Bonds:</strong> Amid the global optimism, German and French bond spreads tightened. In the UK, however, weak retail sales data and the Chancellor’s commitment to fiscal control helped push UK government bonds slightly higher.</li><li><strong>Stocks:</strong> UK stocks rose, driven primarily by corporate earnings. German and French stocks remained largely unchanged as investors await progress on US-EU trade negotiations.</li></ul><h1 id="Dollar-and-Commodities"><a href="#Dollar-and-Commodities" class="headerlink" title="Dollar and Commodities"></a>Dollar and Commodities</h1><ul><li><strong>US Dollar:</strong> Since President Trump’s tariff wars had the effect of strengthening the dollar. A trade agreement, therefore, has the opposite effect. The de-escalation of trade tensions pushed the US dollar lower(<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/%40DX.1?qsearchterm=dollar%20index">-0.79(-0.8%)</a>).</li><li><strong>Gold:</strong> A weaker dollar is typically bullish for gold. However, the dominant force this week was market optimism, which reduces demand for safe-haven assets. As a result, gold finished the week slightly down (<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/XAU%3D?qsearchterm=xau">-$12.61(-0.38%)</a>).</li><li><strong>Oil:</strong> While market optimism provided a tailwind for oil prices, supply-side news created stronger headwinds. Reports indicated that OPEC+ will decide to continue production at its upcoming meeting, the US eased restrictions on Venezuelan oil, and Chinese economic data raised concerns about future energy demand. The downward pressure from supply ultimately won out, and oil prices fell modestly (<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/%40CL.1?qsearchterm=wti%20crude%20">-0.89(-1.35%)</a>).</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
