<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 01/18/2026</title>
    <link href="/2026/01/18/summary260118/"/>
    <url>/2026/01/18/summary260118/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, global markets appeared relatively stable, but beneath the quiet closing prices, two powerful narratives were in a constant tug-of-war: the controversy surrounding Federal Reserve independence and the rising geopolitical risk premiums stemming from the situation in Iran.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="red">-0.38%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-0.66%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-0.29%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+2.04%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+1.09%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.14%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-1.23%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+3.84%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.54% -&gt; <font color="red">3.59%</font></li><li>10yr          4.18% -&gt; <font color="red">4.23%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.38% -&gt; <font color="red">4.40%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.87% -&gt; <font color="green">2.84%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.53% -&gt; <font color="green">3.52%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        2.10% -&gt; <font color="red">2.18%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            58.8-&gt; <font color="green">59.4</font></li><li>Gold           4,518-&gt; <font color="green">4,601</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Powell’s-Legal-Investigation-and-the-“Soft-Landing”-Narrative"><a href="#U-S-Powell’s-Legal-Investigation-and-the-“Soft-Landing”-Narrative" class="headerlink" title="U.S.: Powell’s Legal Investigation and the “Soft Landing” Narrative"></a>U.S.: Powell’s Legal Investigation and the “Soft Landing” Narrative</h1><p>The first major event this week involved Fed Chair Jerome Powell, who faced a Justice Department investigation regarding testimony related to the renovation of the Federal Reserve building. Investors quickly looked past the legal gossip to the deeper systemic risk: Is this investigation a form of political pressure from the Trump administration to force faster rate cuts?</p><p>This perceived threat to Fed independence initially triggered a classic trade—Gold strengthened, the Dollar weakened, and Treasuries were sold off. However, the momentum shifted on Friday when President Trump signaled that National Economic Council Director Kevin Hassett would remain in the White House. This move implied that Hassett—a noted hawk—would likely not be the next Fed Chair. Consequently, the market dialed back expectations for aggressive future rate cuts, causing the Dollar to rebound and Gold to face profit-taking.</p><p>Despite these macro fluctuations, the equity market remained resilient. TSMC’s strong Q4 earnings and ambitious expansion plans continued to fuel the AI investment fever, providing a solid floor for the semiconductor sector. Furthermore, data showing cooling inflation alongside economic resilience bolstered the “soft landing” narrative. This environment favored mid-and-small-cap stocks over large-cap growth giants, resulting in a noticeable sector rotation while major indices remained near their highs.</p><h1 id="Europe-Capital-Inflows-and-Regional-Strength"><a href="#Europe-Capital-Inflows-and-Regional-Strength" class="headerlink" title="Europe: Capital Inflows and Regional Strength"></a>Europe: Capital Inflows and Regional Strength</h1><p>European markets largely followed the U.S. rhythm, though performance was underpinned by improving local macro data. European bonds benefited significantly from capital inflows seeking a haven from the Fed independence drama in the U.S. In the UK, better-than-expected economic performance boosted the stock market, though it left the Gilt market (UK bonds) relatively weak.</p><h1 id="Japan-The-“Sanae-Takaichi-Trade”-Re-ignites"><a href="#Japan-The-“Sanae-Takaichi-Trade”-Re-ignites" class="headerlink" title="Japan: The “Sanae Takaichi Trade” Re-ignites"></a>Japan: The “Sanae Takaichi Trade” Re-ignites</h1><p>The primary focus in Japan remains the political landscape surrounding Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi. Reports this week show that Takaichi might dissolve the House of Representatives for a snap election as early as next week. The market logic is straightforward: if a re-election secures a stronger majority for the LDP, Takaichi will have a much smoother path to implementing her signature proactive fiscal expansion.</p><p>This anticipation triggered a familiar rally in Japanese equities, driven by policy imagination. The Yen initially weakened significantly before a slight recovery following “verbal interventions” from Japan’s Finance Minister. However, the prospect of a weaker Yen and fiscal expansion continues to put pressure on the Bank of Japan to accelerate rate hikes, pushing JGB yields higher across the curve.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Iran-Tensions"><a href="#Commodities-Iran-Tensions" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Iran Tensions"></a>Commodities: Iran Tensions</h1><p>The ongoing civil unrest and escalating tensions in Iran, together, caused oil prices to jump early in the week. While President Trump released characteristically tough rhetoric toward Iran, the market remains uncertain whether this will lead to a substantive military escalation or simply serve as a deterrent for future negotiations. As a result, oil prices experienced a volatile week—spiking during periods of tension and retreating on signs of de-escalation—ultimately closing slightly higher than last week.</p><p>The gold has been pushed up by the doubt of Federal Reserve independence and Middle Eastern tensions. It hit the historical high and faced a strategic pullback as political signals shifted.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 01/11/2026</title>
    <link href="/2026/01/13/summary260111/"/>
    <url>/2026/01/13/summary260111/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The year 2026 began with a “black swan” event: on January 3rd, the Trump administration launched a surprise operation involving the Venezuelan presidency. While such geopolitical escalation typically triggers a “flight to safety,” global equity markets, however, responded with a comprehensive rally. With economic data lacking a clear direction this week, the market’s performance was driven almost entirely by a shift in sentiment that defied conventional intuition.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.57%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+1.88%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+2.32%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+4.62%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+1.74%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+2.94%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+2.04%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+3.18%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.49% -&gt; <font color="red">3.54%</font></li><li>10yr          4.20% -&gt; <font color="green">4.18%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.54% -&gt; <font color="green">4.38%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.90% -&gt; <font color="green">2.87%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.62% -&gt; <font color="green">3.50%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        2.07% -&gt; <font color="red">2.10%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            57.3-&gt; <font color="green">58.8</font></li><li>Gold           4,329-&gt; <font color="green">4,518</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Geopolitics-Energy-Giants-and-AI-Heat"><a href="#U-S-Geopolitics-Energy-Giants-and-AI-Heat" class="headerlink" title="U.S.: Geopolitics, Energy Giants, and AI Heat"></a>U.S.: Geopolitics, Energy Giants, and AI Heat</h1><p>The Venezuelan crisis initially saw gold and oil prices jump at the opening bell. However, as the initial shock faded, investors shifted to a long-term strategic perspective:</p><ul><li>The Geopolitical Logic: While the intervention was aggressive, Trump’s rhetoric centered on “unlocking” Venezuela’s vast oil reserves through lifted sanctions and increased investment. This created a dual impact: a long-term expectation of increased global oil supply (putting downward pressure on prices) and a massive potential opportunity for U.S. energy giants to enter the Venezuelan market. Consequently, the energy sector led the charge upward.</li><li>AI and Tech Momentum: Beyond geopolitics, the tech sector remained white-hot. Strong performance from TSMC and the excitement surrounding the CES exhibition continued to fuel AI investment enthusiasm.</li><li>New Records: Combined with a rotation into defense sectors due to geopolitical risks and a reversal in U.S. housing policy sentiment, major U.S. indices once again shattered all-time highs.</li><li>Flatten Yield Curve: U.S. Treasuries fluctuated amid mixed economic data and geopolitical noise, eventually ending the week with a slightly flatter yield curve.</li></ul><h1 id="Europe-Mirror-of-US"><a href="#Europe-Mirror-of-US" class="headerlink" title="Europe: Mirror of US"></a>Europe: Mirror of US</h1><p>The European markets largely mirrored the U.S. sentiment-driven rally. Stock market was propelled by the same optimism seen in the U.S., with energy and defense sectors outperforming. And the government bonds actually performed stronger than U.S. Treasuries, primarily supported by regional data showing a steady cooling of inflation.</p><h1 id="Japan-Political-Rumors-and-the-Yen’s-Decline"><a href="#Japan-Political-Rumors-and-the-Yen’s-Decline" class="headerlink" title="Japan: Political Rumors and the Yen’s Decline"></a>Japan: Political Rumors and the Yen’s Decline</h1><p>The Japanese market opened its first full trading week of the year by catching up to global volatility while contending with significant domestic political shifts. </p><p>Rumors surfaced on Friday suggesting that Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi, currently enjoying a high approval rating of around 70%, may dissolve the House of Representatives for a snap election as early as February. This prospect of political stabilization initially excited equity markets, with the Nikkei 225 jumping nearly 3% to reach fresh record highs. </p><p>However, the move is a double-edged sword: the market anticipates that a stronger mandate for Takaichi would pave the way for her “Sanaenomics” agenda of aggressive, proactive fiscal expansion. This alarm over fiscal sustainability triggered a sharp depreciation of the Yen, which in turn boosted export-oriented stocks but pushed Japanese Government Bond (JGB) yields to 27-year highs near 2.14% as investors worried about the inflationary impact and potential further rate hikes by the Bank of Japan.</p><h1 id="Commodities-A-Tug-of-War-Between-Risk-and-Supply"><a href="#Commodities-A-Tug-of-War-Between-Risk-and-Supply" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: A Tug-of-War Between Risk and Supply"></a>Commodities: A Tug-of-War Between Risk and Supply</h1><p>Oil price saw a “spike and fade” pattern. The geopolitical risk premium was eventually offset by the prospect of Venezuela’s reserves returning to the global market under U.S. influence.</p><p>Gold remained supported by the underlying geopolitical tension, though the broader “risk-on” mood in equities limited its upward momentum.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>What Happened to Silver This Year?</title>
    <link href="/2025/12/28/note-silver/"/>
    <url>/2025/12/28/note-silver/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While mainstream investors were patting themselves on the back for a respectable 14% return on the S&amp;P 500 in 2025, a quiet revolution was taking place in the commodities sector. Silver—often dismissed as “Gold’s little brother”—exploded by 170% within a single year, outperforming gold by more than double.</p><p>This was not a simple cyclical recovery. It was a “perfect storm” woven from structural shortages, geopolitical maneuvering, and high-leverage algorithmic warfare.</p><h1 id="The-“1-200”-Shadow-Game-How-Leverage-Built-a-Throne-for-Silver"><a href="#The-“1-200”-Shadow-Game-How-Leverage-Built-a-Throne-for-Silver" class="headerlink" title="The “1:200” Shadow Game: How Leverage Built a Throne for Silver"></a>The “1:200” Shadow Game: How Leverage Built a Throne for Silver</h1><p>The core mechanism behind silver’s insanity lies in a highly opaque market structure that expanded paper claims far beyond physical reality.</p><ul><li>Physical-to-Paper Conversion: Speculators borrowed physical silver from miners, pledged it to banks for liquidity, and used that capital to go long on the market.</li><li>The Re-hypothecation Loop: Banks took those pledged certificates and lent them again to ETF issuers. This “multi-link” pledging resulted in a derivatives market that expanded silver’s exposure to more than 1:200 ratio against actual physical bars.</li><li>The Fatal Squeeze: When “Whales” demanded physical delivery, shorts found themselves in a vacuum. By October 2025, silver lease rates spiked to 30%, briefly hitting 100% in the London market as shorts scrambled to avoid default.</li></ul><h1 id="The-Structural-Deadlock-Supply-and-Demand-Imbalance"><a href="#The-Structural-Deadlock-Supply-and-Demand-Imbalance" class="headerlink" title="The Structural Deadlock: Supply and Demand Imbalance"></a>The Structural Deadlock: Supply and Demand Imbalance</h1><p>The fundamental floor for this price surge is a supply-demand mismatch that has finally reached a breaking point.</p><p>Global silver has faced a supply deficit for five consecutive years. </p><img src="/2025/12/28/note-silver/silver-demand-supply.png" class=""><p>Furthermore, silver’s industrial profile has changed as it is the most conductive metal on earth. In the AI era, it has become indispensable for high-performance chips and data center infrastructure while the solar industry’s shift to TOPCon cells has increased silver loading by up to 50% per unit. </p><p>Finally, a strategic revaluation has taken hold as the U.S. added silver to its critical minerals list, while China implemented export licensing in 2026, signaling the end of the era of cheap, abundant silver.</p><h1 id="Geofinancial-Drivers-India-Russia-and-the-JPMorgan-Migration"><a href="#Geofinancial-Drivers-India-Russia-and-the-JPMorgan-Migration" class="headerlink" title="Geofinancial Drivers: India, Russia, and the JPMorgan Migration"></a>Geofinancial Drivers: India, Russia, and the JPMorgan Migration</h1><p>The acceleration in late 2025 was catalyzed by deep geopolitical coupling and a major shift in institutional behavior. In October 2025, mysterious Indian buyers placed a delivery order for 1,000 tons in London, instantly draining New York’s available spot inventory and suggesting that silver was being used as a medium to help Russia convert “trapped” oil rupees into tangible bullion. This movement effectively tested a quasi-Silver Standard for cross-border settlements. </p><p>Simultaneously, JPMorgan, silver’s largest historical market maker, effectively flipped the table by moving their trading desk to Singapore to align with the Asian pivot. They engaged in aggressive physical take-delivery, shifting hundreds of tons from “eligible” to “locked” status and joining the squeeze they once managed.</p><h1 id="2026-Outlook"><a href="#2026-Outlook" class="headerlink" title="2026 Outlook"></a>2026 Outlook</h1><p>As we exit 2025, silver hovers near the $80&#x2F;oz mark. What’s next?</p><ul><li>The “Ghost Week” Surge: During the liquidity vacuum between Christmas and New Year (Ghost Week), roughly 145,000 futures contracts were locked. With no sellers in sight, even minimal buying pressure triggered massive price gaps.</li><li>The Long-term Bull Case: Since gold reaches $4,500, based on gold-to-silver historical extreme ratio, 15:1, the theoretical target for silver could reach $300.</li><li>The Pullbacks Warning: Silver’s volatility is typically double that of gold. Expect technical pullbacks in early 2026 due to passive fund rebalancing (BCOM index adjustments) and potential hawkish pivots from the Fed.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Financial Notes</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Silver</tag>
      
      <tag>Commodity</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 12/28/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/12/28/summary251228/"/>
    <url>/2025/12/28/summary251228/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As we approach the final stretch of 2025, the global market is being shaped by two seasonal forces: the “Santa Claus Rally” and “Window Dressing”.</p><ul><li>The Santa Claus Rally typically sees light trading volume and reduced short-selling pressure, making it easier for prices to move upward on even modest buying.</li><li>The Window Dression happens when institutional managers start to prun underperformers and double down on high-conviction themes like AI to polish their annual reports.</li></ul><p>Here is the deep-dive breakdown of the global market logic for this week.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.40%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+1.22%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.20%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+0.19%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-0.27%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.21%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-0.59%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+2.51%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.49% -&gt; <font color="green">3.48%</font></li><li>10yr          4.14% -&gt; <font color="green">4.14%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.53% -&gt; <font color="green">4.50%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.90% -&gt; <font color="green">2.86%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.62% -&gt; <font color="green">3.56%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        2.02% -&gt; <font color="red">2.04%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            56.6-&gt; <font color="green">56.9</font></li><li>Gold           4,369-&gt; <font color="green">4,562</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Holiday-Effects-vs-Mixed-Macro-Data"><a href="#U-S-Market-Holiday-Effects-vs-Mixed-Macro-Data" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Holiday Effects vs. Mixed Macro Data"></a>U.S. Market: Holiday Effects vs. Mixed Macro Data</h1><p>Macroeconomic data this week offered a mixed view about the economy and the impact is limited under this holiday market</p><ul><li>GDP Surprise: U.S. Q3 GDP growth was revised to 4.3%, significantly beating forecasts. Theoretically, it reduces the urgency for Fed rate cuts</li><li>Soft CB Consumer Confidence: The actual number is 89.1, lower than previous 92.9. </li><li>Mixed Jobless Report: The Initial Jobles Claims fall while Continuing Jobless Claims is higher than previous.</li></ul><p>Thus, the market chose to focus on capital flows rather than macro shifts. Funds continue to rotate into the AI sector, reinforcing the trend where the winners of 2025 keep winning as the year closes.</p><h1 id="Japan-Leader-of-The-Global-Bond-Ripple"><a href="#Japan-Leader-of-The-Global-Bond-Ripple" class="headerlink" title="Japan: Leader of The Global Bond Ripple"></a>Japan: Leader of The Global Bond Ripple</h1><p>The ripple effect from the Bank of Japan (BOJ) continues to be felt across global fixed-income markets.</p><p>Following last week’s symbolic rate hike to 0.75%, the Yen surprisingly weakened rather than strengthened. This raised fears of imported inflation, putting pressure on the BOJ to tighten further in 2026. Combined with concerns over expanded fiscal budgets and increased bond supply, Japan’s 10-year yield surged past 2.1%, its highest since 1999.</p><p>While the “JGB Shock” initially dragged down U.S. and European bond prices, the U.S. Treasury market found support. A solid 7-year note auction proved that demand remains robust at these yield levels, allowing U.S. Treasuries to end the week slightly stronger despite the global pressure. And the European bonds recovered due to holiday-driven buying.</p><h1 id="Europe-A-Holiday-Break"><a href="#Europe-A-Holiday-Break" class="headerlink" title="Europe: A Holiday Break"></a>Europe: A Holiday Break</h1><p>With most European markets open for only two and a half days due to the Christmas holidays, stocks saw a mild “Santa Rally” but on very thin volume, characterized more by sector rotation than broad directional moves.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Crazy-Gold-Silver"><a href="#Commodities-Crazy-Gold-Silver" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Crazy Gold &amp; Silver"></a>Commodities: Crazy Gold &amp; Silver</h1><p>Gold and Silver continue to be the standout assets of late 2025, with Gold hitting new historic highs above $4,400&#x2F;oz due to the following reasons:</p><ul><li>Safe-Haven Demand: Intensifying geopolitical risks—specifically U.S. sanctions on Venezuelan oil and escalated drone activity in the Russia-Ukraine conflict—drove investors into bullion.</li><li>The “Debasement Trade”: As investors grow wary of rising sovereign debt levels and a weakening U.S. dollar, they are rotating out of bonds and into precious metals as a hedge against currency debasement.</li><li>Silver’s Industrial Edge: Silver outpaced gold this week. As a “dual-purpose” metal, it benefited both from the precious metals rally and its critical role in the AI infrastructure buildout (data centers) and green energy.</li></ul><p>Crude Oil remained the outlier, stuck in a tug-of-war between supply disruptions and expectations of a global surplus in 2026, ending the week largely flat.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 12/21/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/12/22/summary251221/"/>
    <url>/2025/12/22/summary251221/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This past week has been a true “Super Central Bank Week” characterized by historic policy shifts and complex macro drivers. As the market grappled with multiple signals, the overarching narrative was one of resilience mixed with strategic caution.</p><p>Here is the deep-dive breakdown of the global market logic for this week.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.10%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+0.48%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-0.67%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="red">-0.86%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+2.57%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.42%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+1.03%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="red">-2.61%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.53% -&gt; <font color="green">3.49%</font></li><li>10yr          4.18% -&gt; <font color="green">4.14%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.52% -&gt; <font color="red">4.53%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.86% -&gt; <font color="red">2.90%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.59% -&gt; <font color="red">3.62%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.95% -&gt; <font color="red">2.02%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            57.5-&gt; <font color="red">56.6</font></li><li>Gold           4,330-&gt; <font color="green">4,369</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Inflation-“Cooling”-and-the-AI-Earnings-Rescue"><a href="#U-S-Market-Inflation-“Cooling”-and-the-AI-Earnings-Rescue" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Inflation “Cooling” and the AI Earnings Rescue"></a>U.S. Market: Inflation “Cooling” and the AI Earnings Rescue</h1><p>The U.S. market navigated a “high-stakes oscillation” between weakening economic data and a high-profile recovery in tech sentiment.</p><ul><li>“Cooling but not Crashing”: Recent economic data generally came in soft, yet investors interpreted this as a gradual slowdown rather than a sudden loss of momentum. Crucially, the November CPI (2.7% YoY) and Core CPI (2.6%) were lower than expected, reinforcing expectations for the Fed’s easing path.</li><li>Bond Market Rebound: The soft inflation print drove a broad decline in Treasury yields (e.g., the 10-year yield edged down to ~4.12%), resulting in a rally in U.S. government bond prices.</li><li>The AI Sentiment Rollercoaster:<ul><li>The Dip: Midweek, technology stocks faced heavy selling pressure as concerns over AI “ROI” (Return on Investment) resurfaced. Anxiety was peaked by reports of financing delays for an Oracle-linked $10B data center project, causing a sharp tech-led drawdown on Wednesday.</li><li>The Rescue: The narrative flipped following Micron Technology’s (MU) blowout earnings and bullish guidance. Micron’s record Q1 results—with revenue jumping 57%—confirmed that AI hardware demand remains a powerful near-term profit driver. This “flight to quality” helped the Nasdaq and S&amp;P 500 snap losing streaks and recover through Friday.</li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Europe-Steady-Resilience-and-“Slow-Easing”-Realism"><a href="#Europe-Steady-Resilience-and-“Slow-Easing”-Realism" class="headerlink" title="Europe: Steady Resilience and “Slow Easing” Realism"></a>Europe: Steady Resilience and “Slow Easing” Realism</h1><p>European markets showed greater stability compared to the AI-driven volatility of Wall Street.</p><p>The European Central Bank maintained its policy rates while upwardly revising growth forecasts. Market participants perceive the ECB as being in a relatively comfortable position, remaining data-dependent rather than signaling an aggressive pivot.</p><p>While the Bank of England cut rates, the 5-4 vote and cautious phrasing tempered expectations for a rapid easing cycle. This led to a general rise in European bond yields as the market priced in a slower-than-hoped-for cut schedule.</p><p>With a lower concentration of AI-sensitive tech giants, European equities outperformed U.S. indices this week, buoyed by improving regional economic outlooks and stabilizing inflation.</p><h1 id="Japan-A-Symbolic-“30-Year-High”-and-the-Yen’s-Inverse-Move"><a href="#Japan-A-Symbolic-“30-Year-High”-and-the-Yen’s-Inverse-Move" class="headerlink" title="Japan: A Symbolic “30-Year High” and the Yen’s Inverse Move"></a>Japan: A Symbolic “30-Year High” and the Yen’s Inverse Move</h1><p>The Bank of Japan (BOJ) made headlines by pushing rates to levels not seen since the mid-1990s.</p><p>On Friday, the BOJ raised its policy rate to 0.75%, a significant 30-year peak. However, because this move was heavily telegraphed by the media over the previous two weeks, the decision was “fully priced in.”</p><p>In a seemingly counterintuitive move, the Yen weakened against the Dollar after the hike. Governor Kazuo Ueda’s post-meeting press conference was characteristically vague regarding future hikes, leading the market to interpret his tone as “dovish.” Nikkei futures surged as a result.</p><p>Despite the Yen’s weakness, the hike confirmed higher long-term financing costs. Combined with concerns over Japan’s 2026 fiscal expansion and increased bond supply, the 10-year JGB yield broke through the 2.0% psychological barrier.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Precious-Metals-Shine-as-Oil-Slips"><a href="#Commodities-Precious-Metals-Shine-as-Oil-Slips" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Precious Metals Shine as Oil Slips"></a>Commodities: Precious Metals Shine as Oil Slips</h1><p>Gold Hits New Records. Lower U.S. Treasury yields reduced the opportunity cost of holding non-yielding assets, pushing Gold futures to new all-time highs.</p><p>Crude oil faced a “demand vs. supply” squeeze:</p><ul><li>Supply: Speculation surrounding Russia-Ukraine peace talks eased some geopolitical supply fears.</li><li>Demand: News of slowing industrial and retail growth in China dampened demand expectations. Despite late-week support from U.S.-Venezuela tensions, oil prices ended slightly lower for the week.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 12/14/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/12/13/summary251214/"/>
    <url>/2025/12/13/summary251214/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The central event this week was the Federal Reserve’s 25 basis point rate cut, lowering the target range to 3.5% to 3.75%, which fully met market expectations. However, the true market tension lies not in this cut itself, but in the path of future easing, leading to a subtle divergence between short-term market sentiment and long-term rate expectations.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="red">-0.63%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-1.62%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.05%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+1.19%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-0.19%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.66%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-0.57%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.68%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.57% -&gt; <font color="green">3.53%</font></li><li>10yr          4.14% -&gt; <font color="red">4.18%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.48% -&gt; <font color="red">4.52%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.80% -&gt; <font color="red">2.86%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.53% -&gt; <font color="red">3.59%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.95% -&gt; <font color="red">1.95%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            60.1-&gt; <font color="red">57.5</font></li><li>Gold           4,228-&gt; <font color="green">4,330</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Small-Cap-Rally-Tech-Slump-and-a-Steeper-Curve"><a href="#U-S-Market-Small-Cap-Rally-Tech-Slump-and-a-Steeper-Curve" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Small-Cap Rally, Tech Slump, and a Steeper Curve"></a>U.S. Market: Small-Cap Rally, Tech Slump, and a Steeper Curve</h1><p>The details of the Fed’s decision released cautious signals, tempering expectations for an accelerating pace of future cuts:</p><ul><li>Dot Plot: The Dot Plot indicated that officials forecast possibly only one additional rate cut in 2026, and the vote showed increasing division.</li><li>Hawkish Commentary: Post-meeting remarks from hawkish officials expressed caution regarding further easing.</li></ul><p>These factors combined to cause short-term rates to fall while long-term rates rose, resulting in a steepening yield curve . Notably, this scenario of a rate cut alongside rising long-term yields is not unique to this week but is a major trend characterizing the entire Fed easing cycle.</p><p>While strengthening rate cut expectations should theoretically push entire bond yields curve down (prices up), the “Goldilocks” environment (no immediate recession risk) meant safe-haven demand was weak. Optimistic sentiment drove funds from the bond market to the stock market, causing upward shift of U.S. Treasury yield curve (price to fall).</p><p>The stock market showed conflicting trends this week:</p><ul><li>Positive Drivers: The rate cut decision itself, along with the Fed’s plan to purchase short-term Treasuries as needed, boosted sentiment, leading to a global rally on Thursday.</li><li>Negative Concerns: Disappointing earnings guidance from tech giants like Broadcom and Oracle reignited market anxiety over the AI valuation bubble.</li></ul><p>The combination of these two factors resulted in a fragmented U.S. market: small-cap stocks rallied on the rate cut impulse, while tech stocks were weighed down and declined.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Tightening-vs-Easing-Expectations"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Tightening-vs-Easing-Expectations" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Tightening vs. Easing Expectations"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Tightening vs. Easing Expectations</h1><p>The Europe market trend was similar to the U.S., but European bond prices fell more sharply than U.S. Treasuries. One reason is the renewed market speculation that the European Central Bank (ECB) could potentially pivot to hiking rates in 2026, a more hawkish stance than the Fed’s cautious easing.</p><p>The Bank of Japan (BOJ) continued its public communication campaign, paving the way for a likely rate hike decision next week.</p><ul><li>Hike Expectations Solidify: By Friday, nearly all institutional economists forecast the BOJ would hike rates to 0.75% next week. Authoritative financial media like Nikkei also reported that the hike was virtually confirmed .</li><li>JGB Yields Climb: The expected return to tightening pushed government bond yields higher. This effect, combined with market concerns over increased bond issuance due to an anticipated expansion of the 2026 fiscal budget, caused Japanese government bond (JGB) yields to continue rising (prices to fall).</li><li>Nikkei Gain: Japanese stocks closed slightly higher, primarily benefiting from the momentum of the U.S. rally following the Fed cut. The decline in U.S. stocks on Friday did not affect the Nikkei’s closing price due to the time zone difference.</li></ul><h1 id="Commodities-Silver-Outperforms-Oil-Drops-Sharply"><a href="#Commodities-Silver-Outperforms-Oil-Drops-Sharply" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Silver Outperforms, Oil Drops Sharply"></a>Commodities: Silver Outperforms, Oil Drops Sharply</h1><p>The rate cut reduced the opportunity cost of holding gold, pushing gold prices higher. Silver, a high leveraged commodity with way smaller market size, not only benefited from gold’s momentum but also from the logic that lower rates would stimulate the economy and boost industrial demand <a href="https://harrisonpan1.github.io/2025/12/11/note-interest-rate-US-JP/">(for more details on how silver market plays, please see this note)</a>. Consequently, silver surged more sharply than gold this week.</p><p>Oil prices dropped sharply this week. The primary driver was the assessment by the International Energy Agency (IEA) and other bodies that the global oil market faces a significant supply surplus in 2026, which overshadowed short-term supply disruptions.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Global Monetary &quot;Duet&quot; and the New Order - Global Assets Amid Japan Hikes and US Cuts</title>
    <link href="/2025/12/11/note-interest-rate-US-JP/"/>
    <url>/2025/12/11/note-interest-rate-US-JP/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The global financial market is currently witnessing a “duet” of monetary policy orchestrated by the two major economies, the U.S. and Japan: Japan is hiking the interest rate, while the Federal Reserve cut its interest rate by 25bps on Wednesday. This has triggered traditional fears of a global asset collapse and liquidity squeeze, especially considering Japan’s unexpected rate hike last July triggered a global stock market plunge (Nikkei fell 13% in a single day, Nasdaq dropped 3.4%).</p><p>From my point of view, the essence of this move is a meticulously orchestrated global liquidity expectation management, rather than a simple risk outbreak.</p><h1 id="Global-Liquidity-Management-Unwinding-Carry-Trades-with-Fed-Coordination"><a href="#Global-Liquidity-Management-Unwinding-Carry-Trades-with-Fed-Coordination" class="headerlink" title="Global Liquidity Management: Unwinding Carry Trades with Fed Coordination"></a>Global Liquidity Management: Unwinding Carry Trades with Fed Coordination</h1><h2 id="The-Traditional-Panic-Unwinding-the-Carry-Trade"><a href="#The-Traditional-Panic-Unwinding-the-Carry-Trade" class="headerlink" title="The Traditional Panic: Unwinding the Carry Trade"></a>The Traditional Panic: Unwinding the Carry Trade</h2><p>Traditional concerns stem from the massive size (estimated at $3–4 trillion) of the “Carry Trade” . For years, speculators borrowed the Japanese Yen at ultra-low rates (0.5%–1%) to purchase high-yield USD assets (such as 4% U.S. Treasuries or Nasdaq stocks).</p><p>If Japan were to hike rates abruptly due to domestic inflation (which reached 3%), these carry funds would rush back to Japan, draining liquidity from global capital markets and causing asset prices to crash.</p><h2 id="Policy-Essence-Coordinated-Liquidity-Management"><a href="#Policy-Essence-Coordinated-Liquidity-Management" class="headerlink" title="Policy Essence: Coordinated Liquidity Management"></a>Policy Essence: Coordinated Liquidity Management</h2><p>Unlike the surprise hike last year, Japan’s current tightening is believed to be externally encouraged, possibly led by U.S. Treasury officials. The core logic is: The Fed is shifting toward releasing liquidity (ending QT, quantitative tightening, and starting the first round RMP, Researve Management Purchases). If both the U.S. and Japan simultaneously unleash massive liquidity, it could lead to short-term asset overheating and greater systemic financial risk.</p><p>Therefore, the Bank of Japan’s measured rate hike is essentially coordinating with the Fed to balance global monetary supply. This operation is designed to preemptively release risk and control liquidity expectations. Given the frequent policy signaling, the market has largely priced this in; while short-term volatility is inevitable, the probability of a major market collapse is considered low.</p><h1 id="Dollar-Hegemony’s-Dilemma-and-China’s-Structural-Challenge"><a href="#Dollar-Hegemony’s-Dilemma-and-China’s-Structural-Challenge" class="headerlink" title="Dollar Hegemony’s Dilemma and China’s Structural Challenge"></a>Dollar Hegemony’s Dilemma and China’s Structural Challenge</h1><p>The Fed’s entry into a rate-cutting cycle signals a fundamental shift in the global financial landscape, closely linked to the U.S. dollar’s struggles and China’s rising influence.</p><h2 id="The-Dollar-System’s-Pivot-From-Financial-Warfare-to-Fiscal-Survival"><a href="#The-Dollar-System’s-Pivot-From-Financial-Warfare-to-Fiscal-Survival" class="headerlink" title="The Dollar System’s Pivot: From Financial Warfare to Fiscal Survival"></a>The Dollar System’s Pivot: From Financial Warfare to Fiscal Survival</h2><p>The U.S. dollar system is fundamentally a debt system, backed by U.S. Treasuries, which achieves periodic wealth harvesting through “tides” of expansion and contraction (liquidity cycles).</p><p>However, this harvesting model is becoming less effective as China has solidified its control over core global production capacity, particularly in high-end sectors like New Energy Vehicles, lithium batteries, and photovoltaic products. The Fed’s attempt to harvest via high-interest rate hikes failed to deliver the expected results and instead triggered a domestic debt crisis (U.S. national debt is now over $37 trillion) .</p><p>To resolve this “debt black hole,” the U.S. must execute a political and monetary pivot. The previous strategy of “Strong Dollar&#x2F;Strong Fiscal Spending” is unsustainable and must transition to a “Weak Dollar&#x2F;Weak Fiscal” model <a href="https://harrisonpan1.github.io/2025/11/16/note-us-china-cycle/">(Please see my previous blog for more details)</a>. This pivot involves Quantitative Easing (QE) and rate cuts to address systemic leverage and debt issues. This historical trend of a weak dollar cycle (anticipated from 2023 to 2030) typically resolves massive systemic leverage through currency devaluation.</p><h2 id="China’s-“Impossible-Trinity”-and-Industrial-Upgrade"><a href="#China’s-“Impossible-Trinity”-and-Industrial-Upgrade" class="headerlink" title="China’s “Impossible Trinity” and Industrial Upgrade"></a>China’s “Impossible Trinity” and Industrial Upgrade</h2><p>In response to external liquidity changes, China’s domestic economy faces an “Impossible Trinity” (Trilemma) . China struggles to simultaneously achieve:</p><ol><li><strong>High Welfare and High Wages</strong>: Workers enjoy comprehensive social security and a dignified income.</li><li><strong>Low Manufacturing Costs</strong>: Factories maintain a low-cost advantage to sustain global competitiveness (“World Factory”).</li><li><strong>Vibrant Domestic Consumption</strong>: A domestic market where people are willing and able to spend.</li></ol><p>Forcing high labor standards would increase manufacturing costs, driving factories to lower-cost regions like Vietnam or India and undermining the “World Factory” foundation. Conversely, maintaining a low-cost advantage (low wages, poor social security) discourages consumer spending, stalling the domestic demand market.</p><p>The only viable path is <strong>industrial re-upgrading</strong>. By moving beyond low-value assembly to high-value sectors like chips and robotics, enterprises can afford higher wages while maintaining international competitiveness.</p><p>Additionally, the slow velocity of money also reflects weak consumer and investment sentiment, with capital “sleeping” in banks. The Fed’s entry into a cutting cycle provides room for the PBoC to ease further. Lower rates and inflation expectations are needed to incentivize the public to consume and invest, thereby accelerating capital circulation and revitalizing the economy.</p><h1 id="Commodity-Logic-and-Investment-Risks-Gold-Silver-and-Chinese-Assets"><a href="#Commodity-Logic-and-Investment-Risks-Gold-Silver-and-Chinese-Assets" class="headerlink" title="Commodity Logic and Investment Risks: Gold, Silver, and Chinese Assets"></a>Commodity Logic and Investment Risks: Gold, Silver, and Chinese Assets</h1><p>With the Fed entering a weak dollar cycle and global liquidity expected to become abundant, the market forecasts a short-term, liquidity-driven inflationary boom phase similar to the 1920s “Coolidge Prosperity”</p><h2 id="Gold-The-De-Dollarization-Anchor"><a href="#Gold-The-De-Dollarization-Anchor" class="headerlink" title="Gold: The De-Dollarization Anchor"></a>Gold: The De-Dollarization Anchor</h2><p>Gold’s current upward trajectory is a perfect reflection of the shifting global monetary regime. It serves as the primary hedge against two simultaneous risks: systemic credit degradation in the U.S. and currency debasement resulting from inevitable QE.</p><ul><li><strong>Central Bank Accumulation</strong>: Global central banks are aggressively accumulating gold, treating it not just as a hedge, but as a transitional equivalent and a foundational asset to anchor their national currencies against anticipated dollar volatility.</li><li><strong>China’s Strategic Role</strong>: China is strategically deploying gold to provide credit backing for RMB internationalization. The establishment of the Global Digital Gold Center and offshore gold vaults in Hong Kong allows overseas RMB holders to purchase gold directly, effectively creating a non-SWIFT, RMB-gold clearing mechanism. Onshore gold (mainland) remains under strict regulation, while offshore gold circulates globally. This dual-track approach positions RMB to gain credibility as the USD’s credit anchor weakens.</li><li><strong>Relocation of JPM Gold Trading Division</strong>: In November, JPMorgan Chase (JPM) suddenly decided to relocate its gold trading division from the U.S. to Singapore. The short-term objective is to divert capital away from gold and back into the U.S. equity market. But at the same time, it underscores a market consensus that the future center of liquidity and pricing power for gold is structurally shifting away from Western financial hubs and toward non-USD-denominated Asian markets. This implies that the USD’s anchor on global gold transactions is weakening.</li><li><strong>Forward-Looking Price Stability</strong>: Once the Quantitative Easing (QE) and the USD’s devaluation is fully priced in, the gold price will expected to move toward a new structural equilibrium (a higher base) rather than experiencing continuous, uncontrolled surges. Its primary function shifts from hyper-volatility hedging to foundational credit anchoring.</li></ul><h2 id="Silver-The-High-Leverage-Short-Squeeze-Game"><a href="#Silver-The-High-Leverage-Short-Squeeze-Game" class="headerlink" title="Silver: The High-Leverage Short Squeeze Game"></a>Silver: The High-Leverage Short Squeeze Game</h2><p>Silver’s recent sharp price action is not primarily driven by its long-term industrial demand narrative (AI power, solar, EVs) but rather by a highly leveraged, structural market dynamic best described as a short squeeze against inadequate physical inventory.</p><ul><li><strong>The Exaggerated Leverage</strong>: Through the banking system, physical silver is transformed into derivatives and collateral, resulting in an estimated leverage expansion that may exceed 1:200 against actual physical stock.</li><li><strong>The Squeeze Mechanics</strong>: Speculators aggressively take long positions and demand physical settlement. Since the paper derivatives market far outstrips the physical inventory, the market shorts (typically institutions) are unable to meet delivery obligations. The price surge is often driven by regional structural shortages—targeting low-inventory hubs (e.g., London or Shanghai) to force the shorts to lease or buy spot metal at exorbitant rates.</li><li><strong>Risk Assessment</strong>: Despite the compelling long-term industrial story, silver is subject to extreme financial risk due to its hyper-leveraged structure. Any sudden, large-scale monetary tightening or a significant increase in exchange margin requirements could trigger a catastrophic deleveraging event.</li></ul><h2 id="Structural-Tailwinds-for-Chinese-Assets"><a href="#Structural-Tailwinds-for-Chinese-Assets" class="headerlink" title="Structural Tailwinds for Chinese Assets"></a>Structural Tailwinds for Chinese Assets</h2><p>The monetary policy divergence (USD weakness, JPY strength) and the subsequent flood of global liquidity provide a clear, structural benefit for RMB-denominated assets.</p><ul><li><strong>RMB Appreciation Bias</strong>: The combination of the Fed’s easing (devaluing the USD) and the BOJ’s tightening (stabilizing the JPY) creates a favorable environment for the RMB to appreciate against the USD.</li><li><strong>Equities and Liquidity</strong>: Dollar weakness is a significant technical positive for Hong Kong stocks, signaling improving global USD liquidity. Historically, USD weakness cycles (e.g., 2003–2008) have coincided with major bull runs in A-Shares. As the Fed transitions to the weak USD phase (2023–2030), A-Shares are structurally positioned for a new strong bull cycle.</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Financial Notes</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Macro</tag>
      
      <tag>Economic Cycles</tag>
      
      <tag>Inerest Rate</tag>
      
      <tag>Monetary Policy</tag>
      
      <tag>Dollar Devaluation</tag>
      
      <tag>US</tag>
      
      <tag>China</tag>
      
      <tag>Japan</tag>
      
      <tag>Gold</tag>
      
      <tag>Silver</tag>
      
      <tag>Commodity</tag>
      
      <tag>Currency</tag>
      
      <tag>Carry Trade</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 12/07/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/12/06/summary251207/"/>
    <url>/2025/12/06/summary251207/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As a new round of central bank meetings approaches, the main drivers of the global market this week once again focused on expectations for Federal Reserve rate cuts and Bank of Japan rate hikes. We’ll break down the logic region by region.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.31%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+0.91%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+0.50%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+0.84%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-0.55%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.80%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-0.10%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.47%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.50% -&gt; <font color="red">3.57%</font></li><li>10yr          4.02% -&gt; <font color="red">4.14%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.45% -&gt; <font color="red">4.48%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.69% -&gt; <font color="red">2.80%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.42% -&gt; <font color="red">3.53%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.81% -&gt; <font color="red">1.95%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            58.4-&gt; <font color="green">60.1</font></li><li>Gold           4,256-&gt; <font color="red">4,228</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Mixed-Data-and-Raising-Rate-Cut-Expectation"><a href="#U-S-Market-Mixed-Data-and-Raising-Rate-Cut-Expectation" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Mixed Data and Raising Rate Cut Expectation"></a>U.S. Market: Mixed Data and Raising Rate Cut Expectation</h1><p>U.S. economic data released this week was mixed</p><ul><li>Manufacturing PMI remained weak, but Services PMI rose. </li><li>ADP private sector employment turned negative in November, and corporate layoffs increased, yet initial jobless claims fell to a two-year low.</li><li>Relatively stable PCE inflation data.</li></ul><p>Overall, economic data was slightly soft but showed no signs of a hard slowdown. Thus, market expectations for a Fed rate cut at next week’s meeting increase.</p><p>The environment of low recession risk coupled with rising rate cut expectations is generally beneficial for equities. Market sentiment leaned optimistic, driving capital into the stock market and pushing U.S. stocks slightly higher across the board.</p><p>The logic for U.S. Treasuries was subtle: while rate cut expectations typically push bond yields down, the absence of strong economic contraction risk meant safe-haven demand was weak. Optimistic sentiment drove funds from the bond market to the stock market, causing U.S. Treasury prices to decline (yields to rise).</p><h1 id="Europe-Market-Steady-Pace-and-UK-Anomaly"><a href="#Europe-Market-Steady-Pace-and-UK-Anomaly" class="headerlink" title="Europe Market: Steady Pace and UK Anomaly"></a>Europe Market: Steady Pace and UK Anomaly</h1><p>The data shows Eurozone core inflation is close to the 2% target, Q3 GDP growth was slightly revised up, and the unemployment rate held steady around 6.4%. The market believes the European Central Bank (ECB) has room for rate cuts next year but also recognizes that the easing cycle is nearing its end. Consequently, European stocks saw little change, and European bonds fell slightly, tracking the U.S. Treasury market.</p><p>The UK market remained an outlier: its bonds performed better than those in Germany and France, but its stock market lagged. The primary logic was that weak UK economic data intensified expectations for a BoE rate cut in December. This, combined with restored market confidence after the fiscal budget was announced a week prior, provided support for UK Gilts. However, restored market confidence also pushed the pound (GBP) stronger, indirectly applying downward pressure on the export-heavy UK stock market.</p><h1 id="Japan-Market-BOJ-Hints-Shock-Global-Bonds"><a href="#Japan-Market-BOJ-Hints-Shock-Global-Bonds" class="headerlink" title="Japan Market: BOJ Hints Shock Global Bonds"></a>Japan Market: BOJ Hints Shock Global Bonds</h1><p>Usually, Janpan bond markets follow the U.S., but the Japanese bond market shock on Monday visibly affected U.S. and European markets.</p><p>The Governor of the Bank of Japan (BOJ) stated in a speech on Monday that the economic and price targets were gradually being met. The market interpreted this as an intentional signal to prepare the public for a rate hike in December.</p><p>The 10-year Japanese Gilt yield surged to 1.95%, hitting a new high since 2007. The rate hike expectation also caused the yen to strengthen slightly against the dollar, which put some downward pressure on the Japanese stock market.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Gold-Consolidates-Oil-Rises"><a href="#Commodities-Gold-Consolidates-Oil-Rises" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Gold Consolidates, Oil Rises"></a>Commodities: Gold Consolidates, Oil Rises</h1><p>The expectation of a Fed rate cut was one of the main forces pushing oil prices up. </p><ul><li>why the expectation of a Federal Reserve rate cut push oil prices up?<ul><li>The Fed rate cut can stimulate economic growth, which increase the global demand for energy</li><li>The Fed rate cut weakens the dollar, oil effectively becomes cheaper for buyers using non-dollar currencies</li><li>commodity like oil is a good hedge against the inflation</li></ul></li></ul><p>Additionally, OPEC’s suspended production increase plan and the volatile Ukraine-Russia situation provided further upward momentum. Oil prices closed the week slightly higher.</p><p>Gold benefited from the weaker dollar but was constrained by rising interest rates (global yields). After a sharp rally last week, gold entered a phase of high-level consolidation and pulled back slightly this week.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 11/30/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/12/01/summary251130/"/>
    <url>/2025/12/01/summary251130/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The main theme dominating markets this week was the clear resurgence of Federal Reserve rate cut expectations, which set the pace for a coordinated rally across global equities, bonds, and commodities. While concerns over AI valuations have not vanished, the improved risk sentiment driven by rate cut hopes offered investors a short-term reprieve.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+3.73%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+4.91%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+3.18%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+5.52%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+1.90%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+3.23%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+1.75%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">3.35%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.52% -&gt; <font color="green">3.50%</font></li><li>10yr          4.07% -&gt; <font color="green">4.02%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.55% -&gt; <font color="green">4.45%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.71% -&gt; <font color="green">2.69%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.48% -&gt; <font color="green">3.42%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.79% -&gt; <font color="red">1.81%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            58.0-&gt; <font color="green">58.4</font></li><li>Gold           4,063-&gt; <font color="green">4,256</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Tech-Rebounds-on-Dovish-Pivot"><a href="#U-S-Market-Tech-Rebounds-on-Dovish-Pivot" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Tech Rebounds on Dovish Pivot"></a>U.S. Market: Tech Rebounds on Dovish Pivot</h1><p>Dovish comments from multiple Fed officials, combined with generally weaker-than-expected economic data released after the government shutdown, significantly raised market odds for a December rate cut. Inflation data remained stable, reinforcing the case for easing. This impact on bonds was immediate: U.S. Treasury yields dropped, and bond prices rose.</p><p>The improved rate cut outlook enhanced investors’ risk appetite, temporarily easing the intense debate over the high valuations of AI and tech stocks. After three weeks of tech declines fueled by valuation anxiety, the shift in risk sentiment allowed investors to look past immediate valuation issues, resulting in the Technology sector leading the U.S. equity rally.</p><p>A black swan event occurred on Thursday when the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME)—the world’s largest derivatives trading hub—experienced a nearly 10-hour outage overnight due to a data center cooling failure. This stopped trading in major futures contracts (FX, Gold, Oil, Treasuries, and Equity indices), pausing the price discovery mechanism and disrupting cross-asset hedging. The event’s impact was minimized because it occurred during a holiday-shortened trading day (after Thanksgiving) when liquidity was already thin, and CME largely restored services before the U.S. cash market opened, averting systemic risk.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Following-Stock-Rally-Diverging-Bond-Market"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Following-Stock-Rally-Diverging-Bond-Market" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Following Stock Rally, Diverging Bond Market"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Following Stock Rally, Diverging Bond Market</h1><p>European stocks broadly followed the U.S. market, achieving a significant rebound. They benefited from the general uplift in global sentiment. European government bonds were also pulled higher by U.S. Treasuries.</p><p>UK Gilts (bonds) performed noticeably better than those in Germany and France. This was driven by the November 26th UK fiscal budget, which finally included a plan for large-scale tax increases. This commitment to fiscal consolidation eased market anxieties about the UK’s debt discipline, driving UK bond prices higher.</p><p>The Japanese stock market also followed the U.S. market, achieving a significant rebound. But bond market went the other direction. Recent speeches by Bank of Japan (BOJ) officials repeatedly hinted that the conditions for resuming rate hikes were nearing maturity. The market interpreted this as the BOJ signaling its intention to prepare the public for a move, strengthening the expectation of a December rate hike and pushing Japanese bond prices lower (yields higher).</p><h1 id="Commodities-Gold-Shines-Oil-Stabilitzes"><a href="#Commodities-Gold-Shines-Oil-Stabilitzes" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Gold Shines, Oil Stabilitzes"></a>Commodities: Gold Shines, Oil Stabilitzes</h1><p>The core logic for gold’s noticeable strength this week was the Fed’s dovish pivot, which lowered U.S. Treasury yields (reducing the opportunity cost of holding non-yielding gold) and weakened the U.S. Dollar.</p><p>Oil prices were volatile due to developments in the Ukraine-Russia peace talks, initially dipping before stabilizing to close the week with a small gain.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Dollar&#39;s Final Reckoning - Why a 2025 &quot;Coolidge Prosperity&quot; Precedes the Global Collapse</title>
    <link href="/2025/11/16/note-us-china-cycle/"/>
    <url>/2025/11/16/note-us-china-cycle/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The global economy is poised at the precipice of a significant regime change, driven by the collapse of the post-1970s dollar-centric world order and the convergence of long-term economic cycles. I argue that the period beginning around 2025 will usher in a severe, yet temporary, monetary-fueled boom—a phenomenon analogous to “Coolidge Prosperity” in 1920s.</p><h1 id="The-Unraveling-of-Dollar-Hegemony-and-the-Debt-Black-Hole"><a href="#The-Unraveling-of-Dollar-Hegemony-and-the-Debt-Black-Hole" class="headerlink" title="The Unraveling of Dollar Hegemony and the Debt Black Hole"></a>The Unraveling of Dollar Hegemony and the Debt Black Hole</h1><p>The historical 16-year rhythm of the US Dollar Index (DXY), which long alternated between strong and weak phases tied to political cycles, failed after 2017. </p><!-- ![image](./note-us-china-cycle/dxy.png) --><img src="/2025/11/16/note-us-china-cycle/dxy.png" class=""><ul><li>Weak Dollar: 1985–1993 (Republican: Ronald Reagan &amp; George H.W. Bush)</li><li>Strong Dollar: 1993–2001 (Democrat: William J. Clinton)</li><li>Weak Dollar: 2001–2009 (Republican: George W. Bush)</li><li>Strong Dollar: 2009–2016 (Democrat: Barack H. Obama)</li></ul><p>The critical deviation occurred after 2017. Instead of the expected decline, the dollar held strong and reached an even higher peak in 2022. This failure to conform to the historical 8-year strong&#x2F;weak alternation is attributed to two factors: the failure to secure the necessary capital inflow from non-US sources in the wake of the 2016 geopolitical tensions and and the unpredicted COVID-19.</p><p>This persistence of high interest rates alongside soaring debt has created a fiscal monster: the Debt Black Hole. Driven by the compounding interest on an enormous debt load, this vortex absorbs global liquidity, leading to the perverse outcome of simultaneous inflation and recession. The system is now caught in a self-devouring cycle where continued money printing fails to stimulate output and instead increases the burden on producers and consumers.</p><h1 id="The-Political-Pivot-From-Financial-War-to-Fiscal-Survival"><a href="#The-Political-Pivot-From-Financial-War-to-Fiscal-Survival" class="headerlink" title="The Political Pivot: From Financial War to Fiscal Survival"></a>The Political Pivot: From Financial War to Fiscal Survival</h1><p>The policy of “Strong Dollar&#x2F;Strong Fiscal Expenditure” employed by the Biden government was essentially a strategy of financial warfare, aimed at absorbing global capital and maintaining the status quo. However, this policy proved unsustainable, leading to unsustainable US debt levels, crippling inflation, extreming wealth inequality, and profound domestic political fractures.</p><p>The political shift signaled by the rise of a Trump-led, MAGA-driven administration fundamentally changes the trajectory. Trump’s focus is on restructuring the domestic fiscal reality. This necessary pivot mandates a transition to a Weak Dollar&#x2F;Weak Fiscal regime. To tame the debt black hole and ease the internal cost-of-living crisis, the US must eventually return to quantitative easing (QE) and lower interest rates.</p><p>This Weak Dollar trend echos under the 60-year Kondratiev Wave scope. The current period falls into the late decline&#x2F;depression phase (estimated as 2018–?). This phase demands the resolution of massive, systemic leverage. History is unequivocal on the solution: currency devaluation.</p><ul><li>1930s: Devaluation occurred during the Great Depression.</li><li>1970s: Devaluation through the abandonment of the gold standard.</li><li>2025: Gold price has doubled since 2024</li></ul><p>This pivot is the global release valve. For years, non-US economies were forced to constrain their monetary policy to defend their currencies against the strong dollar. US QE will unleash global liquidity, allowing nations worldwide to resume monetary stimulus and begin their own debt resolution through inflation.</p><h1 id="China’s-Opportunities-and-the-New-Multipolar-Order"><a href="#China’s-Opportunities-and-the-New-Multipolar-Order" class="headerlink" title="China’s Opportunities and the New Multipolar Order"></a>China’s Opportunities and the New Multipolar Order</h1><p>In the past decades, China has followed its own 10-year cycle of technology upgrades and capacity elimination tied to deleveraging efforts:</p><ul><li>2003: State-owned enterprise and bank bad debt stripping (AMC).</li><li>2013: Supply-side structural reform (steel, paper, chemicals).</li><li>2023: Tightening debt resolution for remaining old industries (e.g., Evergrande).</li></ul><p>This 10-year cycle has historically synchronized with the long-term dollar cycles, leading to strong A-share performance during weak dollar phases:</p><!-- ![image](./note-us-china-cycle/dxy_sse.png) --><img src="/2025/11/16/note-us-china-cycle/dxy_sse.png" class=""><ul><li>Weak Dollar(91–92): Sharp Increase</li><li>Strong Dollar(93–01): Largely Sideways</li><li>Weak Dollar(03–08): Major Bull Market</li><li>Strong Dollar(09-22):Mostly Sideways</li><li>Next Weak Dollar(23–30): <strong>Anticipated Strong Bull</strong></li></ul><p>While the US has been preoccupied with its internal crises and external conflicts, the strong dollar period has paradoxically benefited China. The disruption and de-industrialization of US allies have effectively gifted market share to China. Having largely completed its own internal debt resolution efforts, China is uniquely positioned as the world’s largest and most complete manufacturing nation to absorb and benefit from the coming wave of global liquidity.</p><p>The current geopolitical tensions are not just about rivalry; they reflect the inevitable breakdown of the neo-liberal world order, accelerated by the US’s choice to “backstab its allies” for short-term fiscal survival. China’s strategy is not to seize global hegemony via the dollar model (a model that failed the US by abandoning manufacturing for pure monetary export), but to <strong>establish a new economic order based on RMB-Commodity&#x2F;Energy transactions</strong>.</p><h1 id="The-Investment-Forecast-A-New-Coolidge-Boom"><a href="#The-Investment-Forecast-A-New-Coolidge-Boom" class="headerlink" title="The Investment Forecast: A New Coolidge Boom"></a>The Investment Forecast: A New Coolidge Boom</h1><p>The confluence of US QE, global monetary stimulus, and China’s industrial readiness will manufacture a powerful economic rebound. This phenomenon, peaking approximately between 2025 and 2028, will be a short-term, liquidity-fueled boom. The recent AI boom is a signal of it. </p><p>Since this boom is fundamentally inflationary, the best assets are <strong>those that appreciate with rising prices</strong>, like Big Commodities (e.g., Oil, Minerals), Mining Companies, and heavy Asset Cyclical Industries. </p><p>Gold perfectly illustrates the current regime change. Central banks are using it as an equivalent value asset and a transitional medium because its value is universally recognized. Central banks are accumulating gold as a hedge against the collapse of the existing dollar-based credit system. Once the situation stabilizes (i.e., the “Coolidge Prosperity” is underway, USD devaluation is locked in, and the US debt crisis is temporarily relieved by lower rates), confidence in the economic recovery will return. By then, major central banks will stop aggressively buying gold, and the price will naturally settle down. Paradoxically, if a true recession were to break out, gold might be sold off as liquidity is needed.</p><p>This period of exuberance, while potentially very profitable, is <strong>temporary</strong>. It will conclude with a <strong>subsequent deep downturn</strong> (2028–2032), possibly triggered by a spike in oil prices engineered by US-aligned producers after the Russia-Ukraine conflict concludes, as the US seeks to restore dollar credibility after its devaluation.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Financial Notes</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Macro</tag>
      
      <tag>Economic Cycles</tag>
      
      <tag>Monetary Policy</tag>
      
      <tag>Dollar Devaluation</tag>
      
      <tag>US</tag>
      
      <tag>China</tag>
      
      <tag>Kondratiev Wave</tag>
      
      <tag>DeDollarization</tag>
      
      <tag>Coolidge Prosperity</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 11/16/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/11/16/summary251116/"/>
    <url>/2025/11/16/summary251116/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, the U.S. ended its record 43-day government shutdown. While the full impact remains to be seen (key economic data is still delayed), the relief initially boosted market sentiment. However, a rapid shift in Federal Reserve expectations led to a turbulent week across global markets.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.08%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-0.45%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+0.34%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="red">-1.83%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.16%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+1.30%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+2.77%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">0.20%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.57% -&gt; <font color="red">3.61%</font></li><li>10yr          4.10% -&gt; <font color="red">4.15%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.50% -&gt; <font color="red">4.58%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.67% -&gt; <font color="red">2.72%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.46% -&gt; <font color="green">3.46%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.68% -&gt; <font color="red">1.70%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            59.8-&gt; <font color="green">59.9</font></li><li>Gold           4,008-&gt; <font color="green">4,084</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Shutdown-Ends-and-Hawkish-Fed"><a href="#U-S-Market-Shutdown-Ends-and-Hawkish-Fed" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Shutdown Ends and Hawkish Fed"></a>U.S. Market: Shutdown Ends and Hawkish Fed</h1><p>The end of the government shutdown initially lifted risk sentiment, causing U.S. stocks to rally early in the week. However, this momentum was quickly reversed when several Federal Reserve officials delivered hawkish speeches, causing the market’s expectation for a December rate cut to fall sharply. This brought downward pressure on stocks.</p><p>This combined with persisted concerns from the previous week about the over-valuation of AI stocks creates a highly volatile environment with technology stocks under pressure.</p><p>In the bond market, both the fading safe-haven demand after the shutdown ended and the reduction in rate cut expectations pushed Treasury yields higher. Although a weak ADP employment report caused a brief rally, U.S. Treasury prices ultimately fell (yields rose) for the week.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-US-Followor-But-With-Local-Flavor"><a href="#Europe-Japan-US-Followor-But-With-Local-Flavor" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: US Followor, But With Local Flavor"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: US Followor, But With Local Flavor</h1><p>European stocks generally outperformed the U.S. The boost from the U.S. government shutdown ending provided warmth to the European market, but the shock of falling Fed rate cut expectations was less severe here. This meant European stocks tended to follow the U.S. up, but not down as much. European bond markets also tracked U.S. Treasuries, closing slightly lower.</p><p>The UK, however, dragged the average down. News broke that the UK Chancellor of the Exchequer had abandoned tax hike plans. The market interpreted this as a lack of commitment to medium- to long-term fiscal discipline, generating fiscal anxiety that simultaneously suppressed both the UK stock and bond markets.</p><p>Japanese bonds saw yields rise slightly, driven by U.S. Treasuries, but the increase was smaller, which widened the US-Japan interest rate differential, leading the yen to depreciate slightly. The lower rise in Japanese yields was partly due to the market pushing back its expectation for the Bank of Japan’s first rate hike from December to January.</p><p>Japanese stocks continued their correlation with U.S. tech stocks, but the depreciation of the yen provided a supporting tailwind, allowing the Japanese stock market to close with a small gain for the week.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Gold-Rallies-Oil-Flat"><a href="#Commodities-Gold-Rallies-Oil-Flat" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Gold Rallies, Oil Flat"></a>Commodities: Gold Rallies, Oil Flat</h1><p>The U.S. Dollar Index weakened slightly this week. Combined with the stock market’s persistent volatility over AI valuations and a renewed demand for safe-haven and inflation-hedge assets, gold prices ended the week up by about 2% after a period of sharp fluctuation.</p><p>A monthly report from OPEC raising concerns about a slowdown in medium- to long-term demand hit market confidence. However, supply disruptions caused by geopolitical conflicts provided support. After a tug-of-war between these factors, oil prices closed the week nearly flat.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 11/09/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/11/08/summary251109/"/>
    <url>/2025/11/08/summary251109/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, major markets saw widespread corrections. As European and Japanese markets largely followed the U.S. lead, the key event driving the global downturn originated in the U.S. Let’s look at them one by one.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="red">-1.63%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-3.09%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-1.21%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="red">-1.88%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-0.07%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-1.62%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-1.49%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="red">-4.07%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.58% -&gt; <font color="green">3.57%</font></li><li>10yr          4.08% -&gt; <font color="red">4.10%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.41% -&gt; <font color="red">4.47%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.63% -&gt; <font color="red">2.67%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.42% -&gt; <font color="red">3.46%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.66% -&gt; <font color="red">1.68%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            60.9-&gt; <font color="red">59.8</font></li><li>Gold           4,103-&gt; <font color="red">4,001</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-CEO-Warnings-Spark-Correction"><a href="#U-S-Market-CEO-Warnings-Spark-Correction" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: CEO Warnings Spark Correction"></a>U.S. Market: CEO Warnings Spark Correction</h1><p>The direct catalyst for the U.S. stock market correction was comments made by the CEOs of Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley at a financial summit in Hong Kong on Tuesday. Both leaders publicly warned that the stock market could see a significant pullback of 10% to 20% over the next one to two years.</p><p>These warnings struck a chord because the stock market, led by technology stocks, had just completed a major rally, leaving valuation metrics at historically high levels. The comments acted as a fuse for a large-scale wave of profit-taking and selling pressure. U.S. stocks fluctuated throughout the week, ultimately closing with a significant loss compared to the previous week.</p><p>In the bond market, the U.S. government shutdown continued, preventing the release of official data. The market therefore focused on data from private institutions like the ADP employment report. Bond prices fluctuated based on the strength of this data—rising on weak data (increased rate cut expectation) and falling on strong data.</p><p>However, two pieces of news directly hit the bond market:</p><ul><li>Tech Giant Issuance: Major tech companies like Google issued large amounts of bonds, disrupting the supply-demand balance.</li><li>Treasury Plan: The U.S. Treasury hinted at plans to increase the issuance of long-term debt in the future, pushing long-term yields up.</li></ul><p>Under the influence of these factors, U.S. bonds closed slightly lower for the week.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Following-the-Downturn"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Following-the-Downturn" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Following the Downturn"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Following the Downturn</h1><p>European markets largely mirrored the U.S., resulting in both stock and bond declines. The Bank of England (BoE) meeting on Thursday resulted in no change, which was expected. However, four out of nine voting members favored a rate cut, which boosted expectations for a December cut. This provided some limited support for UK stocks and bonds. </p><p>In Japn, after a massive rally over the previous two weeks, Japanese stocks faced heavy profit-taking pressure. Coupled with the downturn in U.S. tech stocks, the Japanese stock market saw a significant decline this week.</p><p>Japanese bonds tracked the movements of U.S. Treasuries. The release of the detailed minutes from the BOJ’s September meeting showed that the preconditions for a rate hike are gradually being met. This increased market expectations for a BOJ rate hike, causing Japanese bond prices to fall slightly.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Small-Changes"><a href="#Commodities-Small-Changes" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Small Changes"></a>Commodities: Small Changes</h1><p>Gold prices continued their small decline this week. One reason was the ongoing profit-taking pressure after the recent massive rally. Another factor was the rise in U.S. bond yields, which increases the opportunity cost of holding non-yielding gold.</p><p>News that OPEC had suspended its plan for production increases provided some price support. However, this was ultimately overcome by the negative sentiment stemming from the stock market downturn, leading oil prices to close slightly lower for the week.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 11/02/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/11/03/summary251102/"/>
    <url>/2025/11/03/summary251102/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week is a “Super Central Bank Week”, with the Federal Reserve (Fed), Bank of Japan (BOJ), and European Central Bank (ECB) all holding policy meetings. The decisions and the resulting adjustments in interest rate expectations largely steered market movements. Let’s look at them one by one.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.71%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+2.24%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+0.75%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="red">-1.36%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.74%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-1.16%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-1.27%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+6.31%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.50% -&gt; <font color="red">3.58%</font></li><li>10yr          4.02% -&gt; <font color="red">4.08%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.43% -&gt; <font color="green">4.41%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.63% -&gt; <font color="red">2.63%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.44% -&gt; <font color="green">3.42%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.66% -&gt; <font color="green">1.66%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            61.4-&gt; <font color="red">60.9</font></li><li>Gold           4,127-&gt; <font color="red">4,103</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Rate-Cut-Trade-Deal-and-Hawkish-Tilt"><a href="#U-S-Market-Rate-Cut-Trade-Deal-and-Hawkish-Tilt" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Rate Cut, Trade Deal, and Hawkish Tilt"></a>U.S. Market: Rate Cut, Trade Deal, and Hawkish Tilt</h1><p>On Wednesday, the Fed followed through with another 0.25% rate cut and announced it would end its balance sheet reduction (Quantitative Tightening) on December 1st. While these moves were generally expected, Fed Chair Powell emphasized that a decision on whether to cut rates again in December remains unsettled, noting internal divisions within the Fed. The market interpreted this message as slightly hawkish, leading to a downward adjustment in future rate cut expectations. This pushed U.S. Treasury yields up, and bond prices down.</p><p>Despite this downward adjustment in future rate cut expectations, two major factors propelled the stock market:</p><ul><li>Trade Deal Progress: A meeting between the U.S. and Chinese presidents resulted in a trade agreement that, at the very least, prevented an escalation of the trade war, pushing market sentiment toward optimism.</li><li>Strong Earnings: As of this week, about two-thirds of S&amp;P 500 companies had released Q3 earnings, with over 80% beating expectations. This supported the optimistic mood, driving U.S. stocks higher. Large technology stocks were particularly strong, with Nvidia becoming the first company to temporarily breach the $5 trillion valuation mark (Is this a bubble or a boost? Time will tell). In contrast, small-cap stocks struggled for gains.</li></ul><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Diverging-Central-Bank-and-Political-Impacts"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Diverging-Central-Bank-and-Political-Impacts" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Diverging Central Bank and Political Impacts"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Diverging Central Bank and Political Impacts</h1><p>The ECB maintained its policy rate and stressed that its future policy path remains data-dependent, offering little new guidance. Consequently, </p><ul><li>European bond markets, particularly German bonds, largely tracked the U.S. trend, with yields rising slightly. </li><li>French bonds, still recovering from a recent sharp sell-off, saw a small gain this week.</li><li>The UK market was unique. The Prime Minister hinted in Parliament at the possibility of raising taxes to fill the fiscal hole. This supported UK bond prices but simultaneously raised concerns about the UK economy, leading the pound (GBP) to fall sharply. The depreciation of the pound, in turn, boosted UK stocks, making the UK market a clear outperformer compared to Germany and France.<ul><li>Why raising taxes boost bond price and weaken GBP?<ul><li>When the government signals fiscal consolidation (like a tax hike), it suggests that future borrowing needs will be reduced. That means the government will issue fewer new bonds (Gilts) than previously expected. A reduction in the future supply of debt puts upward pressure on bond prices.</li><li>On the other hand, higher taxes reduce disposable income for consumers and profits for businesses, leading to less spending, investment, and hiring. It will also accelerate the probability of lower interest rates from the Bank of England (BoE), which can cause a capital outflow. Thus the GBP will depreciate.</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><p>In Japan, the BOJ once again held steady and indicated it wanted to see a clear trend of rising wages next year before considering a rate hike. This weakened market expectations for a December rate hike, supporting the stock rally.</p><p>In addition, the Takaichi Trade accelerates this rally. Strong support for the new cabinet and market expectations that Japanese companies would increase investment in the U.S. following Trump’s visit drove a significant surge in Japanese stocks. The massive flow of capital into stocks somewhat offset the boost to bonds from weakened rate hike fears, resulting in Japanese bond prices seeing little change for the week.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 10/26/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/27/summary251026/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/27/summary251026/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, global markets generally saw rising stocks and slightly falling government bonds. However, the specific factors driving market performance differed across regions. Let’s dive into details for each major market.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.92%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+2.31%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+2.20%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+2.50%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+3.11%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+1.72%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+0.63%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+3.61%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.47% -&gt; <font color="red">3.50%</font></li><li>10yr          4.01% -&gt; <font color="red">4.02%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.54% -&gt; <font color="green">4.43%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.58% -&gt; <font color="red">2.63%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.36% -&gt; <font color="red">3.44%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.63% -&gt; <font color="red">1.66%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            57.6-&gt; <font color="green">61.4</font></li><li>Gold           4,268-&gt; <font color="red">4,127</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Trade-Noise-and-CPI-Cheer"><a href="#U-S-Market-Trade-Noise-and-CPI-Cheer" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Trade Noise and CPI Cheer"></a>U.S. Market: Trade Noise and CPI Cheer</h1><p>The U.S. market was heavily influenced by the ongoing U.S.-China trade negotiations. News from the U.S. side, particularly from President Donald Trump, caused market sentiment to swing back and forth from caution to optimism. However, having weathered previous rounds of tariff threats, the market generally settled on the view that the threats would ultimately be more bark than bite, leading to an overall recovery in sentiment.</p><p>A major driver of market optimism came from the CPI data released on Friday. Due to the U.S. government shutdown delaying data releases, this particular CPI report became a crucial reference point for the Federal Reserve to judge future rate cuts. The data came in slightly lower than market expectations, which boosted investor confidence that the Fed would continue its easing cycle. This momentum pushed U.S. stocks to new record highs.</p><p>Corporate Earnings also played a significant role. With Q3 earnings season coming, strong results from companies like GM and 3M led to stock surges, while Netflix’s weak performance caused its stock to fall. The performance of tech stocks like Tesla and IBM was unusual: despite disappointing earnings, their share prices, after initial drops, quickly recovered, suggesting that some long-term investors are seizing price dips as buying opportunities in the tech sector.</p><p>In the bond market, rate cut expectations provided upward pressure. However, the U.S. sanctioning of a Russian oil giant on Wednesday caused oil prices to spike, raising inflation concerns. This inflation worry brought downward pressure on U.S. bonds, which ultimately ended the week slightly lower.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Diverging-Local-Factors"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Diverging-Local-Factors" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Diverging Local Factors"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Diverging Local Factors</h1><p>The European market mirrored the U.S., with stocks generally rising and bonds falling. Because the European Central Bank’s (ECB) rate-cutting cycle is almost complete, and with relatively strong PMI data released this week, the decline in European bond prices was more pronounced than in the U.S.</p><ul><li>The UK market significantly outperformed Germany and France. This was due to two factors: <ul><li>Lower UK CPI data led the market to anticipate a potential rate cut by the Bank of England in December, which boosted UK bond prices and stocks. </li><li>The rise in oil prices lifted energy stocks, which have a larger weighting in the UK stock market.</li></ul></li></ul><p>In Japan, the “Takaichi Trade,” which had temporarily slowed, was reignited. This trade is based on the economic platform of Sanae Takaichi, which advocates for fiscal expansion and opposes rate hikes. This policy outlook (more spending, easy money) pushed Japanese stocks higher and the yen lower (See Week 10&#x2F;12&#x2F;2025 for logic behind). Simultaneously, market caution about a widening fiscal deficit and increased bond issuance pushed Japanese bond prices lower.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Oil-Rallies-Gold-Slides"><a href="#Commodities-Oil-Rallies-Gold-Slides" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Oil Rallies, Gold Slides"></a>Commodities: Oil Rallies, Gold Slides</h1><p>As mentioned above, the U.S. sanctioning of a Russian oil giant on Wednesday caused oil prices to spike. </p><p>Meanwhile, the prevailing optimistic sentiment reduced safe-haven demand. This, combined with profit-taking pressure after nine consecutive weeks of gains, caused gold prices to dip slightly this week.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 10/19/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/21/summary251019/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/21/summary251019/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, with the U.S. government shutdown persisting and delaying key economic data releases, markets were predominantly influenced by political factors and corporate earnings.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.70%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+2.14%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.56%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+2.4%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-0.77%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-1.69%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+3.24%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="red">-1.05%</font></li><li>NKD1!         <font color="green">+6.73%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.51% -&gt; <font color="green">3.47%</font></li><li>10yr          4.04% -&gt; <font color="green">4.01%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.67% -&gt; <font color="green">4.54%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.63% -&gt; <font color="green">2.58%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.48% -&gt; <font color="green">3.36%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.70% -&gt; <font color="green">1.63%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            58.2-&gt; <font color="red">57.6</font></li><li>Gold           4,015-&gt; <font color="green">4,268</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Trade-War-Eases-Earnings-Shine"><a href="#U-S-Market-Trade-War-Eases-Earnings-Shine" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Trade War Eases, Earnings Shine"></a>U.S. Market: Trade War Eases, Earnings Shine</h1><p>The central focus remained the trade war risk sparked by Donald Trump last week. After an initial spike in risk aversion, markets stabilized this week, having gained some immunity to the recurring threats. The overall sentiment improved, particularly after Trump stated on October 17th that 100% tariffs were not a long-term goal, which fueled a rebound in U.S. stocks.</p><p>Two other major factors contributed to the rally:</p><ul><li><p>Fed Signals: Fed Chair Powell suggested during a Tuesday speech that rate cuts were likely to continue and that the balance sheet reduction (quantitative tightening) could end within a few months, signaling a supportive policy environment.</p></li><li><p>Strong Earnings: Approximately 12% of S&amp;P 500 companies released earnings this week, with over 80% beating expectations. News of Broadcom’s joint development with OpenAI and strong earnings from TSMC sustained the market’s enthusiasm for the AI semiconductor industry.</p></li></ul><p>The dovish signals from the Fed also influenced the bond market, pushing U.S. Treasury yields down and prices up.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Political-Stabilization-and-Turmoil"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Political-Stabilization-and-Turmoil" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Political Stabilization and Turmoil"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Political Stabilization and Turmoil</h1><p>European bond markets largely followed the U.S. trend, seeing slight gains. Stocks, however, faced downward pressure due to lingering concerns over the trade war risk. A notable bright spot was France, where the Prime Minister survived two no-confidence motions this week. While the cabinet still faces challenges, this temporary stability boosted confidence in the French market, leading to a stock market rebound and a narrowing of the yield spread between German and French bonds.</p><p>In Japan, the political scene remains volatile. Following the split with its long-term ally, Komeito, the LDP actively sought other coalition partners this week. The “Takaichi Trade” logic—which anticipated a surge in stocks based on Takaichi’s election as LDP president—experienced several reversals. Ultimately, Japanese stocks saw a small pullback for the week, though Nikkei futures showed a large increase over the previous week’s closing price. Amidst the political confusion, the market anticipates that the Bank of Japan will be hesitant to raise rates, leading to a slight decrease in Japanese bond yields.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Gold-Rallies-Oil-Slides"><a href="#Commodities-Gold-Rallies-Oil-Slides" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Gold Rallies, Oil Slides"></a>Commodities: Gold Rallies, Oil Slides</h1><p>The trade war risk lowered the outlook for global energy demand, causing oil prices to slide further to near a six-month low.</p><p>Conversely, both the risk-averse sentiment stemming from the trade war threat and the accommodative signals released by the Fed are positive for gold. These factors combined to drive gold prices to surge dramatically, breaking the $4,000 per ounce. This spike in gold also lifted other precious metals, with silver prices on the London market hitting an all-time high this week.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 10/12/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/11/summary251012/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/11/summary251012/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, markets were primarily driven by political events, with the U.S., Japan, and Europe each facing their own unique turmoil. Let’s break down the main logic based on timeline.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="red">-2.43%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-2.27%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-2.73%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="red">-4.14%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-1.07%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-0.88%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-2.43%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+5.07%</font></li><li>NKD1!         <font color="red">-0.02%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.57% -&gt; <font color="green">3.51%</font></li><li>10yr          4.12% -&gt; <font color="green">4.04%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.69% -&gt; <font color="green">4.67%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.70% -&gt; <font color="green">2.63%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.51% -&gt; <font color="green">3.48%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.67% -&gt; <font color="red">1.70%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            60.7-&gt; <font color="red">58.2</font></li><li>Gold           3,886-&gt; <font color="green">4,015</font></li></ul><h1 id="Japan-The-“Takaichi-Trade”-and-Political-Instability"><a href="#Japan-The-“Takaichi-Trade”-and-Political-Instability" class="headerlink" title="Japan: The “Takaichi Trade” and Political Instability"></a>Japan: The “Takaichi Trade” and Political Instability</h1><p>Last weekend, Sanae Takaichi was elected as the new president of Liberal Democratic Party (LDP), making her a likely candidate for the next prime minister. This result was somewhat unexpected, triggering a “Takaichi Trade” at the start of the week.</p><p>The logic of this trade was based on Takaichi’s economic policies, which are centered on two points: fiscal expansion and opposition to rate hikes.</p><ul><li>Fiscal expansion raises the risk of a larger deficit and increased government bond issuance, which puts downward pressure on Japanese bonds.</li><li>Her opposition to rate hikes led the market to lower its expectations for a Bank of Japan rate hike, which widened the yield spread with the U.S. and caused the yen to depreciate.</li><li>For the stock market, fiscal expansion, delayed rate hikes, and a weaker yen are all positive catalysts.</li></ul><p>As a result of the “Takaichi Trade,” the Japanese stock market saw a significant rally, while Japanese bonds and the yen fell.</p><p>However, the LDP does not hold a majority in the House of Representatives on its own, so Takaichi’s election doesn’t automatically guarantee her the prime minister position. On Friday, the political situation took a dramatic turn when the LDP’s key ally, the Komeito party, indicated it might not vote for Takaichi in the upcoming prime ministerial election. This uncertainty shook the foundation of the “Takaichi Trade,” causing a reversal in market trends and leading to a sharp drop in Nikkei stock futures on Friday night.</p><h1 id="U-S-and-Europe-Politics-Drive-Risk-Off-Sentiment"><a href="#U-S-and-Europe-Politics-Drive-Risk-Off-Sentiment" class="headerlink" title="U.S. and Europe: Politics Drive Risk-Off Sentiment"></a>U.S. and Europe: Politics Drive Risk-Off Sentiment</h1><p>The U.S. government remains in a partial shutdown due to budget disagreements, which continues to prevent the release of key economic data. In this environment, markets are highly sensitive to policy developments. On Friday, Donald Trump sent a series of posts threatening to impose tariffs on China, triggering market fears of a new trade war. This caused a shift toward risk-averse sentiment.</p><p>This flight to safety pushed U.S. bonds higher and stocks lower, a trend that also spread to European markets. European markets largely mirrored the U.S., with bonds rising and stocks falling.</p><p>In France, the Prime Minister resigned again due to an inability to pass the fiscal budget. While President Macron re-appointed him on Friday, the underlying issues of political division and fiscal deadlock remain. Consequently, both the French stock and bond markets continue to lag behind the UK and Germany.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Geopolitical-Risks-and-a-Stronger-Gold"><a href="#Commodities-Geopolitical-Risks-and-a-Stronger-Gold" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Geopolitical Risks and a Stronger Gold"></a>Commodities: Geopolitical Risks and a Stronger Gold</h1><p>The commodity market saw significant volatility. The Middle East risk premium has fallen due to the Gaza ceasefire agreement. OPEC and the Americas are still expected to increase production. Plus, Trump’s trade war threats significantly lowered the outlook for energy demand. All these factors ultimately cause oil prices to fall to a near six-month low.</p><p>Gold prices, on the other hand, continued to rise sharply, breaking the $4,000 mark, primarily driven by the market’s risk-averse sentiment. The surge in gold also boosted other precious metals, with silver prices on the London market hitting a new record high this week.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 10/05/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/10/05/summary251005/"/>
    <url>/2025/10/05/summary251005/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, the big news was the U.S. government shutdown. Since the U.S. fiscal year begins on October 1st, and the Republican and Democratic parties failed to agree on a new budget, the U.S. government entered a partial shutdown. </p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.08%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+1.15%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.10%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+1.66%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+1.94%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+2.72%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+2.68%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.91%</font></li><li>TOPIX         <font color="red">-1.82%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.65% -&gt; <font color="green">3.57%</font></li><li>10yr          4.18% -&gt; <font color="green">4.12%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.76% -&gt; <font color="green">4.69%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.75% -&gt; <font color="green">2.70%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.57% -&gt; <font color="green">3.51%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.66% -&gt; <font color="red">1.67%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            65.2-&gt; <font color="red">60.7</font></li><li>Gold           3,754-&gt; <font color="green">3,886</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Missing-Major-Economics-Data"><a href="#U-S-Market-Missing-Major-Economics-Data" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Missing Major Economics Data"></a>U.S. Market: Missing Major Economics Data</h1><p>The government shutdown had an immediate effect on the market: the U.S. Census Bureau couldn’t operate normally, so two key economic reports—weekly unemployment claims and non-farm payrolls—were not released on schedule. Without this key data, the market’s attention shifted to the secondary ADP employment report and the ISM services PMI, both of which came in weaker than expected.</p><p>Weaker-than-expected data often signals a slowing economy and strengthens the expectation of a Fed rate cut. This increased prospect of a rate cut, combined with the flight of capital to safe-haven assets due to the shutdown, pushed U.S. Treasury bonds up.</p><p>The logic for the stock market was a bit different: bad news is good news. Weaker economic data, by reinforcing rate cut expectations, helped to fuel optimistic sentiment in the stock market. This logic propelled major U.S. and UK stock indices to new record highs.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Following-US-and-LDP-Presidential-Election"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Following-US-and-LDP-Presidential-Election" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Following US and LDP Presidential Election"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Following US and LDP Presidential Election</h1><p>Both bond and stock markets of EU follows the movement of US.</p><p>And for Japan, in a speech this week, the Bank of Japan (BOJ) Governor stated that the Japanese economy still faces many uncertainties and showed no eagerness to raise interest rates. Despite this, Japanese bond auctions this week showed weak demand, causing Japanese bond prices to fall slightly. The stock market was supported by the rally in U.S. equities, but some investors remained cautious ahead of the LDP presidential election. The Nikkei index continued its rise to a new record high, while the Topix index saw a small decline.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Navigating-Uncertainty"><a href="#Commodities-Navigating-Uncertainty" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Navigating Uncertainty"></a>Commodities: Navigating Uncertainty</h1><p>The U.S. government shutdown and the stronger rate cut expectations both contributed to a slight depreciation of the U.S. dollar, which is generally positive for gold. Fueled by these factors, gold prices rose sharply, once again hitting a new all-time high.</p><p>A Reuters report that OPEC would continue to increase production in November sent oil prices plunging at the beginning of the week. This increased supply outlook put significant downward pressure on oil. </p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 9/28/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/09/28/summary250928/"/>
    <url>/2025/09/28/summary250928/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, with few major news events, the market continued to digest the Federal Reserve’s recent rate cut while adjusting expectations for future cuts based on new economic data and Fed officials’ statements.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="red">-0.31%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-0.5%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-0.15%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="red">+2.16%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.85%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.42%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+0.15%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.69%</font></li><li>TOPIX         <font color="green">+1.25%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.58% -&gt; <font color="red">3.65%</font></li><li>10yr          4.13% -&gt; <font color="red">4.18%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.71% -&gt; <font color="red">4.76%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.75% -&gt; <font color="green">2.74%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.56% -&gt; <font color="red">3.57%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.64% -&gt; <font color="red">1.66%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            62.7-&gt; <font color="green">65.2</font></li><li>Gold           3,682-&gt; <font color="green">3,754</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Strong-Data-and-Hawkish-Comments"><a href="#U-S-Market-Strong-Data-and-Hawkish-Comments" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Strong Data and Hawkish Comments"></a>U.S. Market: Strong Data and Hawkish Comments</h1><p>Economic data was generally robust this week. The September PMI data came in below expectations, but other indicators, including new home sales, unemployment claims, and Q2 GDP, were strong. The Q2 GDP data, in particular, eased market fears of a recession.</p><p>This economic strength reduced the pressure on the Fed to cut rates quickly. Fed officials’ comments this week reinforced this conservative stance. On Tuesday, Fed Chair Powell reiterated his vigilance against inflation in a speech, which the market interpreted as slightly hawkish. Other Fed officials’ remarks were also generally hawkish, with the exception of Trump’s confidant, Miran.</p><p>The combination of strong economic data and hawkish comments led the market to lower its expectations for the future pace of rate cuts. This caused U.S. bonds to fall and put the brakes on the stock market’s upward momentum. Following a long rally, a wave of profit-taking selling pressure led to small declines in major stock indices. The week started with a brief rise in tech stocks after news broke of Nvidia’s investment in OpenAI to build an AI data center, but the rally was short-lived.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Following-Their-Own-Leads"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Following-Their-Own-Leads" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Following Their Own Leads"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Following Their Own Leads</h1><p>There was little major news in Europe this week. The bond market largely followed the trend of falling U.S. bonds, with European bonds also experiencing a slight decline. Stock markets saw little change, although the UK market, with its higher proportion of energy stocks, slightly outperformed Germany and France due to the rise in oil prices.</p><p>Weak Tokyo CPI data led the market to lower its expectations for a rate hike from the Bank of Japan. This caused the yen to depreciate slightly, providing some upward momentum for the Japanese stock market. However, the Japanese bond market faced conflicting pressures. The lower CPI reduced rate hike expectations, pushing bond prices up, but mounting concerns over a new cabinet’s potential fiscal expansion and the downward pull from U.S. bonds caused Japanese bonds to fall. The yield on 10-year Japanese bonds reached its highest level in nearly 17 years.</p><ul><li>Why lowering its expectations for a rate hike will cause the depreciation of Yen and provide upward momentum for stock market?<ul><li>A currency becomes less attractive when you are told its yield will remain low for the foreseeable future compared to its peers. Lower demand for a currency means a lower price.</li><li>Japan is a major export economy. Its corporate giants (like Toyota, Sony, Nintendo, Canon, etc.) earn a massive portion of their revenue in foreign currencies. When the Yen is weak, the overseas profits of these companies, when converted back into Yen, become significantly larger.</li><li>A weaker Yen makes Japanese products cheaper for foreign buyers. This can lead to an increase in sales volume, gaining market share from competitors in countries with stronger currencies. This provides a double boost: higher volumes and higher Yen-denominated revenue per unit.</li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Commodities-Slow-Reaction"><a href="#Commodities-Slow-Reaction" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Slow Reaction"></a>Commodities: Slow Reaction</h1><p>Gold prices continued to rise, reaching a new all-time high. It seems the gold market is still digesting the full implications of the Fed’s recent rate cut.</p><p>Oil prices were primarily influenced by supply-side concerns. News of an attack on a Russian oil facility and Trump’s call for the EU to ban the purchase of oil led to a decrease in expected oil supply, causing prices to rise slightly.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Will the Recent Gold Rally Last Long?</title>
    <link href="/2025/09/21/note-gold/"/>
    <url>/2025/09/21/note-gold/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Gold has been on an impressive run, with prices more than doubling from $1,429 per ounce in November 2022 to $3,700 per ounce by today, a 30% compound annual growth rate. This surge has captured a lot of attention, and for good reason. But with gold breaking new highs, many investors are asking a crucial question: What is the next for gold?</p><p>To understand the risks, we can look to two recent analyses: <a href="https://www.gold.org/goldhub/research/whats-a-bear-case-for-gold">a detailed historical review from the World Gold Council (WGC)</a> and <a href="https://www.deshaw.com/library/worth-its-weight">an article from D.E. Shaw</a>.</p><h1 id="The-World-Gold-Council’s-Historical-View"><a href="#The-World-Gold-Council’s-Historical-View" class="headerlink" title="The World Gold Council’s Historical View"></a>The World Gold Council’s Historical View</h1><p>The World Gold Council’s report on the bear case for gold analyzes five major pullbacks in its price since the 1971 Bretton Woods collapse. These historical declines were generally driven by three main factors: rising opportunity costs, cooling risks and uncertainty, and structural supply changes.</p><p>Here is a summary of each pullback:</p><ul><li><strong>1st Bear Run (1974-1976): The Establish of Petrodollar</strong><br>The anchor of dollar changed from gold to oil, which strengthened the dollar again and as a result, gold price pullbacked.</li></ul><!-- ![image](./note-gold/1st%20gold%20pullback.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/1st%20gold%20pullback.png" class=""><ul><li><strong>2nd &amp; 3rd Bear Run (1980-1982 &amp; 1983-1985): Hike Rates to Fight Inflation</strong><br>Although the report separates two pullbacks, I personally believe these two were both the result of then-Fed Chair Paul Volcker rates hiking for inflation cool down. The sharp rise in real interest rates caused the dollar to strengthen</li></ul><!-- ![image](./note-gold/2nd&3rd%20gold%20pullback.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/2nd&3rd%20gold%20pullback.png" class=""><ul><li><strong>4th Bear Run (1987-1999): Formation of Unipolar Hegemony</strong><br>This was the longest bear run in history. The collapse of the Soviet Union marked the end of Cold War, which significantly reduced geopolitical risk. Dollar become the only worldwide currency and all central banks generally believed that gold has lost its monetary properties and started to sell over the years.</li></ul><!-- ![image](./note-gold/4th%20gold%20pullback.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/4th%20gold%20pullback.png" class=""><ul><li><strong>5th Bear Run (2011-2015): Rising Real Interest Rate</strong><br>After the Fed ended its quantitative easing program, the real yield rose and dollar became strengthed.</li></ul><!-- ![image](./note-gold/5th%20gold%20pullback.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/5th%20gold%20pullback.png" class="">  <p>It is obvious that the underlying reason for a pullback is <strong>the stengthen of dollar</strong>, either confidence level (Petrodollar, Unipolar Hegemony) or fundamental level (increase in real interest rate, decrease in inflation, economic strength)</p><p>This report also mentioned the near-term and long-term risk for gold price weakness.</p><!-- ![image](./note-gold/near%20term%20risk.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/near%20term%20risk.png" class=""><!-- ![image](./note-gold/long%20term%20risk.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/long%20term%20risk.png" class=""><h1 id="D-E-Shaw’s-Portfolio-Optimization-Aspect-of-Gold"><a href="#D-E-Shaw’s-Portfolio-Optimization-Aspect-of-Gold" class="headerlink" title="D.E. Shaw’s Portfolio Optimization Aspect of Gold"></a>D.E. Shaw’s Portfolio Optimization Aspect of Gold</h1><p>D.E. Shaw tackles the issue from a different angle, addressing the problem of valuing gold. Unlike stocks or bonds, which have future cash flows, gold is a non-productive store of value (NPSOV). This makes it impossible to price using traditional methods like discounted cash flow.</p><p>Instead, D.E. Shaw proposes a model based on gold’s relationship with other assets and use optimizer to illustrate the ideal time to add gold to a portfolio.</p><ol><li>In a positive stock-bond correlation environment, the potential portfolio utility of gold increases, even if our forecast for gold remains unchanged.</li><li>A strong expectation of high inflation and a looming stock market crash</li></ol><p>These were further comfirmed by optimizer for portfolio  allocation. Specifically, the more exposed the portfolio is to risks like a positive stock-bond correlation, equity crashes, or inflation shocks, the more value the optimizer assigns to gold’s diversification benefits.</p><!-- ![image](./note-gold/optimizer.png) --><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/optimizer.png" class=""><h1 id="Synthesis-Why-a-Bear-Case-is-Unlikely-Now"><a href="#Synthesis-Why-a-Bear-Case-is-Unlikely-Now" class="headerlink" title="Synthesis: Why a Bear Case is Unlikely Now"></a>Synthesis: Why a Bear Case is Unlikely Now</h1><p>Combining the insights from both reports, a powerful picture emerges. The factors that have historically driven gold into a bear market—a strong U.S. dollar and cooling geopolitical risks—are not currently present.</p><p>The U.S. economy faces a unique situation where both “weak dollar” and “de-dollarization” forces are active. “Weak dollar” is a deliberate action by the U.S. to devalue its currency to stimulate a soft economy and manufacturing. “De-dollarization” is a trend among other countries to reduce their reliance on the dollar for trade, often due to concerns over its use as a tool for sanctions. When both the producer of the dollar (the U.S.) and its major consumers (other export-heavy nations) are moving away from the currency, the result is a powerful “double kill” that prevents the dollar from fundamentally strengthening.</p><p>Therefore, given the current macro environment, the historical conditions for a gold bear run simply do not exist. While short-term pullbacks are always possible, the core factors that have fueled gold’s bull run—high geopolitical risk, a weak dollar, and fears of inflation—remain firmly in place.</p><h1 id="Some-Personal-Thoughts"><a href="#Some-Personal-Thoughts" class="headerlink" title="Some Personal Thoughts"></a>Some Personal Thoughts</h1><p>The traditional framework for gold analysis depends on <strong>real interest rate + overall returns of other asset classes</strong>. </p><ul><li>The lower real interest rate, the higher gold price. <ul><li>Econ 101 tells us the real interest rate &#x3D; norminal interest rate - inflation. It’s very easy to get the relationship between inflation and gold price.</li><li>In the real market, traders also consider expectation, ie. real interest rate &#x3D; (realized norminal interest rate + expected norminal interest rate) - (realized inflation + expected inflation). That makes things a bit complex.</li></ul></li><li>The higher other asset classes returns, the lower gold price</li></ul><p>But since 2022, the framework no longer holds. The main reason is that we have a lower boundery for real interest rate. We cannot go below 0 for too long. However, the gold has no up ceiling. </p><!-- ![image](./note-gold/gold&real%20interest%20rate.png)--><img src="/2025/09/21/note-gold/gold&real%20interest%20rate.png" class=""><p>Now, the new logic behind the all-time high gold price is the global debt and credit, especially US government credit problem and debt monetization. There are only two ways to alleviate the current crisis.</p><ol><li>War</li><li>Technological progress + reshoring of high-value-added manufacturing<ul><li>the problem is reshoring of manufacturing impacts China’s interests and unavoidablely, this can cause the conflict between these two big countries.</li></ul></li></ol><p>Thus, as long as the credit problem is not solved, the gold price won’t come down.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Financial Notes</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Macro</tag>
      
      <tag>Gold</tag>
      
      <tag>Commodity</tag>
      
      <tag>NPSOV</tag>
      
      <tag>D.E. Shaw</tag>
      
      <tag>World Gold Council</tag>
      
      <tag>Portfolio Management</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 9/21/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/09/21/summary250921/"/>
    <url>/2025/09/21/summary250921/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week was dominated by central banks, with the U.S., UK, and Japan all holding key policy meetings.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.22%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+2.22%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.05%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+2.16%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-0.46%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-0.25%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+0.36%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.62%</font></li><li>TOPIX         <font color="red">-0.41%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.56% -&gt; <font color="red">3.58%</font></li><li>10yr          4.07% -&gt; <font color="red">4.13%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.68% -&gt; <font color="red">4.71%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.70% -&gt; <font color="red">2.75%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.51% -&gt; <font color="red">3.56%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.60% -&gt; <font color="red">1.64%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            62.6-&gt; <font color="green">62.7</font></li><li>Gold           3,644-&gt; <font color="green">3,682</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Rate-Cut-and-Record-Highs"><a href="#U-S-Market-Rate-Cut-and-Record-Highs" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Rate Cut and Record Highs"></a>U.S. Market: Rate Cut and Record Highs</h1><p>On Wednesday, the Federal Reserve cut interest rates by 0.25%, the first cut in nine months and a move that was in line with market expectations. The dot plot, which forecasts the future path of interest rates, showed the potential for two more cuts by the end of the year.</p><p>Fed Chair Powell described this as a “risk management” cut, suggesting that although economic data hadn’t significantly deteriorated and inflation remained a concern, the job market seemed to be weakening. Historically, rate-cutting cycles that begin before a full-blown economic downturn are often favorable for stocks. This sentiment, combined with other positive news like Nvidia’s investment in Intel, fueled an optimistic mood. As a result, the S&amp;P 500, Nasdaq, and Dow Jones all hit new record highs.</p><p>In contrast to the stock market, the bond market was more conservative. Since the Fed’s decision—both the size of the cut and the future forecast—didn’t exceed market expectations, and because weekly retail and employment data showed some improvement, U.S. Treasury yields rose slightly, causing bond prices to dip.</p><ul><li>Why does bond price go down after the interest rate cut?<ul><li>It is often called ‘buy the rumor, sell the news’. The market has already anticipate for almost 100% chance that the Fed will cut the rate. Thus, traders and investors had already bought bonds, pushing their prices up and yields down, in anticipation of the move (Check the yield curve for the past month, the yield keep going down).</li><li>When the Fed delivered exactly what was expected, there was no new information to cause a further rally. Instead, some traders likely “sold the news,” locking in profits from the anticipated rate cut.</li><li>The improving economic data contradicted the recession fears that had been building<ul><li>Retail Sales: The data showed that retail spending was improving, indicating that consumer demand remained resilient</li><li>Unemployment Claims: The number of new unemployment claims fell significantly for the week, pushing back against recent concerns of a rapid labor market deterioration</li></ul></li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Relative-Peacefull-Markets"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Relative-Peacefull-Markets" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Relative Peacefull Markets"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Relative Peacefull Markets</h1><p>There was little major news impacting Europe this week. The decline in U.S. bonds and news of an increase in German bond issuance pushed European bond prices down slightly. On Thursday, the Bank of England chose not to cut rates, and the UK’s fiscal deficit came in higher than expected. This raised market concerns about a potential fiscal crisis, leading to declines in both UK bonds and stocks.</p><p>Japan: On Friday, the Bank of Japan (BOJ) kept its interest rate unchanged, which was expected. However, the vote was split 7-2, with two members arguing for an immediate rate hike. This strengthened market expectations that the BOJ will resume rate hikes within the year, pushing Japanese bond yields higher and prices down. The BOJ also made an unexpected announcement that it would begin selling its vast holdings of ETFs and REITs. This decision put some downward pressure on the Japanese stock market. As a result, despite the positive momentum from U.S. stocks, the Nikkei index only saw a small gain, while the Topix index saw a slight loss.</p><ul><li>What the difference between Nikkei index and Topix index?<ul><li>Nikkei Index covers 225 the most liquid, blue-chip companies listed on the Tokyo Stock Exchange (TSE). It’s a price-weighted index</li><li>Topix Index covers all domestic stocks listed on the Tokyo Stock Exchange with market capitalization weight. Each individual stock influence is capped at 10%.</li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Commodities-Clear-Logic"><a href="#Commodities-Clear-Logic" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Clear Logic"></a>Commodities: Clear Logic</h1><p>The logic for commodities was clear. The Fed’s rate cut boosted market sentiment and lowered the opportunity cost of holding gold, pushing gold prices to a new all-time high.</p><p>Important news affecting oil prices was scarce this week. Oil prices fluctuated slightly in response to changes in supply expectations for Russian crude but ultimately closed the week unchanged.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 9/14/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/09/13/summary250914/"/>
    <url>/2025/09/13/summary250914/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, several major events influenced the market, but the logic was very clear. Simply put, the U.S. pays attention to the data, while Europe and Japan focus on the events. Let’s take a look at each region.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+1.59%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+1.86%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+0.95%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+0.24%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.47%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.43%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+1.96%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+4.07%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.52% -&gt; <font color="red">3.56%</font></li><li>10yr          4.08% -&gt; <font color="green">4.07%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.65% -&gt; <font color="red">4.68%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.66% -&gt; <font color="red">2.7%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.45% -&gt; <font color="red">3.50%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.57% -&gt; <font color="red">1.60%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            62.2-&gt; <font color="green">62.6</font></li><li>Gold           3,590-&gt; <font color="green">3,642</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Data-Driven-Optimism"><a href="#U-S-Market-Data-Driven-Optimism" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Data-Driven Optimism"></a>U.S. Market: Data-Driven Optimism</h1><p>This week, the U.S. released the final batch of key economic data before the next Federal Reserve meeting. Inflation data showed that PPI was lower than expected, while CPI was slightly higher. Employment data remained weak, with a significant downward revision to annual non-farm employment and a much higher-than-expected number of new unemployment claims.</p><p>This data further solidified the market’s expectation of a Fed rate cut, fueling optimistic sentiment and providing upward momentum for U.S. stocks. The S&amp;P 500, Nasdaq, and Dow Jones all hit new record highs. U.S. stock gains also drove a rally in European markets.</p><ul><li>why market believe unemployment rate is more important for FED rate decision?<ul><li>Let’s first break down the CPI data. <ul><li>Core consumer prices, which exclude food and energy, rose by 0.3% from the previous month in August of 2025, the same pace as in July, in line with market forecasts.</li><li>The major pushup factor is shelter, 0.4%. But the data of shelter in CPI is very lagged. If you check Zillow Rent Index or New Tennant Rent Index, they are actually much lower, which indicates that in the future CPI calculation, shelter will not be a big concern for inflation.</li><li>Import Prices MoM is 0.4, which is mainly caused by Tariffs. But it takes time to pass this cost to consumers. Also, corporations will absort some cost changes and this won’t be fully reflected to the price.</li></ul></li><li>The rising unemployment rate and slowing job growth can be viewed as a leading indicator that inflation will naturally come down on its own. Here’s the logic:<ul><li>A weakening labor market means less wage growth.</li><li>Less wage growth means consumers have less money to spend.</li><li>Reduced consumer demand puts downward pressure on businesses to lower prices to attract customers.</li></ul></li><li>Overall, unemployment issue is the most important for FED to make decision.</li></ul></li></ul><p>Another major force behind the U.S. stock rally was the continued excitement over AI investment. This week, Oracle released its earnings report, and its recent major contracts—including several from OpenAI—sent its stock soaring. This surge briefly pushed Oracle’s founder, Larry Ellison, to the top of the list of the world’s wealthiest people.</p><p>Since the expectation of a September rate cut was already priced into U.S. Treasury bonds, their prices saw little change this week.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Event-Driven-Concern"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Event-Driven-Concern" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Event-Driven Concern"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Event-Driven Concern</h1><p>In France, the Béroux cabinet ultimately failed to pass a no-confidence vote. President Macron appointed Lecomte as the new Prime Minister, but the new government still faces a fiscal challenge with the budget. The market, wary of a potential French fiscal crisis, saw French bonds come under further selling pressure. On Thursday, the European Central Bank (ECB) kept its policy rate unchanged, which was in line with expectations. However, it also slightly raised its economic forecast, a move interpreted as a hawkish signal that the rate-cutting cycle may be ending. This also contributed to the decline in European bond prices.</p><p>In Japan, Shigeru Ishiba announced his resignation as Prime Minister on Sunday evening. The market is now anticipating that the next leader may pursue a more aggressive fiscal policy. This, combined with the rally in U.S. stocks, fueled a significant surge in Japanese stocks. The prospect of fiscal expansion and increased bond issuance put downward pressure on Japanese bond prices, but speculation that political uncertainty might delay a rate hike by the Bank of Japan provided some counterbalance. As a result, Japanese bonds only saw a slight decline.</p><ul><li>What is Shigeru Ishiba’s political stand? And why his stepdown impact Japanese market in this direction?<ul><li>Shigeru Ishiba is a Japanese politician known for his fiscally conservative and against the ultra-loose monetary policy. </li><li>The market viewed Ishiba’s resignation as an opportunity for the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP) to select a new leader who would pursue a more aggressive fiscal policy, which can boost economic growth and has a positive catalyst for equities. </li><li>When a government increases spending, it must issue more bonds to cover the deficit. This increase in the supply of bonds can overwhelm market demand, causing their prices to fall and their yields to rise.</li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences"><a href="#Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences"></a>Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences</h1><p>This week, both the Russia-Ukraine and Middle East conflicts escalated, with the resulting supply-side security concerns putting upward pressure on oil prices. However, weak U.S. employment data raised fears of an economic slowdown and a reduction in energy demand, which curbed the price rally. As a result, oil prices saw only a small increase.</p><p>Gold prices, primarily driven by U.S. rate cut expectations, continued their ascent and hit a new record high.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 9/7/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/09/07/summary250907/"/>
    <url>/2025/09/07/summary250907/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, global markets were primarily driven by U.S. employment data. However, since the data releases were concentrated from Wednesday onwards, the beginning of the week was dominated by concerns over fiscal deterioration in various countries.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.33%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+1.01%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-0.32%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+1.04%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.34%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-1.28%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-0.42%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.70%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.64% -&gt; <font color="green">3.52%</font></li><li>10yr          4.26% -&gt; <font color="green">4.08%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.72% -&gt; <font color="green">4.65%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.72% -&gt; <font color="green">2.67%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.51% -&gt; <font color="green">3.45%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.60% -&gt; <font color="green">1.58%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            64.0-&gt; <font color="red">62.0</font></li><li>Gold           3,448-&gt; <font color="green">3,587</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-Tariffs-and-Employment-Reports"><a href="#U-S-Market-Tariffs-and-Employment-Reports" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: Tariffs and Employment Reports"></a>U.S. Market: Tariffs and Employment Reports</h1><p>Early in the week, a court ruling that Trump’s reciprocal tariffs were unconstitutional sparked concerns that a final verdict would force the government to refund tariffs, widening the fiscal deficit. These worries led to </p><ul><li>a drop in U.S. bond prices <ul><li>reasons:<ol><li>Increased Supply of Bonds: To refund the billions of dollars in tariffs, the U.S. government would need to borrow money by issuing more Treasury bonds. </li><li>Decreased Demand of Bonds: A widening fiscal deficit can raise concerns about the government’s long-term fiscal health. Thus reducing the bond demand. To compensate for this increased risk, investors would demand a higher return, which also pushes bond yields up and prices down</li></ol></li></ul></li><li>downward pressure on the stock market.<ul><li>reasons: <ol><li>Rising Interest Rates: When Treasury yields rise, all other interest rates, including those for corporate and personal loans, hikes as well. Higher borrowing costs for companies can cut into their profits and slow down expansion plans. For consumers, higher interest rates on mortgages, auto loans, and other credit can dampen spending. Thus the whole economy will slow down.</li><li>Impact on Valuation: Higher interest rates also make stocks less attractive to investors. A higher discount rate means a lower present value for the stock, putting downward pressure on stock prices.</li><li>Reduced Investor Confidence: A new element of political and economic uncertainty is introduced. This “uncertainty tax” can cause businesses to delay investment and consumers to become more cautious, both of which can lead to a slowing economy. Such a pessimistic outlook makes investors more risk-averse, prompting a flight from stocks into safer assets.</li></ol></li></ul></li></ul><p>However, the trend was dramatically reversed from Wednesday to Friday with a series of three weak U.S. employment reports. The data showed a decline in job openings, lower-than-expected payroll growth, and an increase in unemployment claims. The deteriorating employment picture intensified market expectations for a Federal Reserve rate cut. The market is now highly confident of a rate cut in September, with some even anticipating an aggressive 0.5% reduction. This concern leads to</p><ul><li>Treasury yields are pushed down<ul><li>reasons:<ol><li>the Fed Fund rate is the major impact of the treasury yield, especially the short term.</li></ol></li></ul></li><li>The impact on stocks was more mixed. On one hand, rate cut expectations served as a catalyst, but on the other, the consecutive weak employment reports fueled fears of an economic recession. Amid this push and pull, U.S. stocks ended the week slightly higher.<ul><li>A major driver for the tech sector was Google’s legal victory in an antitrust case, which prevented its Chrome browser business from being broken up. This win was a “win-win” for both Google and Apple, securing a key business for Google and protecting its lucrative deal to be the default search engine on Apple devices. The news boosted both companies’ share prices and propelled the Nasdaq index.</li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Political-and-Economic-Tensions"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Political-and-Economic-Tensions" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Political and Economic Tensions"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Political and Economic Tensions</h1><p>Like the U.S., European markets were initially weighed down by fiscal worries, including a potential no-confidence vote in the French government and the UK’s challenging budget discussions. However, they were eventually lifted by the positive spillover from the U.S. bond and stock rallies.</p><p>Both the Japanese bond and stock markets ended the week higher.</p><ul><li>Bond: Calls for an early leadership election within the Liberal Democratic Party to oust fiscally conservative Prime Minister Ishiba raised concerns about potential fiscal expansion. This put downward pressure on Japanese bonds, but the stronger influence of rising U.S. bond prices ultimately led to a small gain.<ul><li>Why concerns about potential fiscal expansion can put downward pressure on Japanese bond prices <ol><li>Suppy &amp; Demand: Fiscal expansion comes alone with issuing new government bonds. This increase in the supply of bonds in the market can overwhelm demand, causing bond prices to fall.</li><li>Inflationary Expectations: Significant fiscal expansion can be seen as inflationary. By injecting more money into the economy, it can lead to higher prices. Bondholders are particularly sensitive to inflation because it erodes the future purchasing power of their fixed interest payments. To compensate for this risk, investors will sell their existing bonds, driving down prices and pushing up yields.</li></ol></li></ul></li><li>Stocks: Japanese stocks were boosted by the rally in U.S. tech stocks and the finalization of a U.S. tariff on Japan at a moderate 15%, which was less severe than the market had initially feared.<ul><li>Why the finalization of a U.S. tariff on Japan at a moderate 15% boosted Japanese stocks<ol><li>Removal of Uncertainty: Markets dislike uncertainty. The finalization of a rate, even a punitive one, allows businesses to plan and adjust. The absence of this major unknown is a positive for market stability and investor confidence. Plus, the initial fears of the possibility of a much higher tarrif rate, possibly as high as 25% or more, or a broader range of products being targeted, creates a positive surprise comparing to this moderate 15%.</li><li>Managed Economic Impact: A 15% tariff, while not ideal, is a manageable headwind for many Japanese export-oriented companies. They can potentially absorb some of the cost, pass a portion on to consumers, or adjust their supply chains to mitigate the impact. A higher tariff could have been a catastrophic shock, but a moderate one is a challenge that can be overcome, which reassures investors about the profitability and stability of Japanese corporations.</li></ol></li></ul></li></ul><h1 id="Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences"><a href="#Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences"></a>Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences</h1><p>The expectation of a rate cut lowered the opportunity cost of holding gold, while mounting fears of a recession increased demand for safe-haven assets. These two factors combined to drive a significant increase in gold prices.</p><p>Oil prices, on the other hand, fell. The market is anticipating that OPEC may decide to increase production at its September 7th ministerial meeting, while recession fears have lowered demand expectations. The combination of increased supply and decreased demand put strong downward pressure on oil prices.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Structure of FOMC and Who Are Trump&#39;s People</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/31/note-FED/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/31/note-FED/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Fed’s primary monetary policy-making body, the Federal Open Market Committee (FOMC), has 12 voting members. Of these, seven seats are permanently held by the seven members of the Board of Governors. The remaining five seats rotate among the presidents of the 12 regional Federal Reserve banks.</p><p>A governor’s term is an extensive 14 years, with a new seat expiring every two years. This staggered system ensures a degree of policy continuity. Under this design, a president can, in theory, appoint at least two governors during a single term, allowing them to shape the Fed’s long-term policy direction.</p><p>So, who on the current Board of Governors can be considered “Trump’s people?”</p><p>During his first term, Trump appointed two governors: Michelle Bowman and Christopher Waller. Both of them voted in favor of a rate cut at the July meeting. However, it’s clear that the current Fed, led by Chairman Jerome Powell (also a Trump appointee in 2018), has not fully aligned with Trump’s aggressive push for rapid rate cuts to stimulate the economy and ease the government’s interest burden.</p><p>It’s precisely this lack of full alignment that has made Trump eager to exert greater influence through new appointments.</p><p>Based on the staggered term schedule, Trump has two theoretical opportunities to appoint new governors during his second term:</p><ul><li>The first opportunity is in January 2026.</li><li>The second is when Powell’s term as a governor expires in 2028.</li></ul><p>However, waiting until 2028 is not an ideal option if he wants to see immediate policy changes. This timeline explains his recent urgency to find additional opportunities to place his own people on the board and steer the Fed toward his desired course.</p><table><thead><tr><th>Name &amp; Position</th><th>Governor Term</th><th>Appointing President</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td>Jerome H. Powell (Chair)</td><td>May 2012 (Jun 2014 reappointment) - Jan 2028</td><td>Donald Trump</td></tr><tr><td>Philip N. Jefferson: (Vice Chair)</td><td>May 2022 - Jan 2036</td><td>Joe Biden</td></tr><tr><td>Michelle W. Bowman: (Vice Chair for Supervision)</td><td>Nov 2018 (Feb 2020 reappointment) - Jan 2034</td><td>Donald Trump</td></tr><tr><td>Lisa D. Cook</td><td>May 2022 (Feb 2024 reappointment) - Jan 2038</td><td>Joe Biden</td></tr><tr><td>Michael S. Barr</td><td>Jul 2022 - Jan 2032</td><td>Joe Biden</td></tr><tr><td>Christopher J. Waller</td><td>Dec 2020 - Jan 2030</td><td>Donald Trump</td></tr><tr><td>Vacant</td><td>TBD</td><td>TBD</td></tr></tbody></table>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Financial Notes</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>FED</tag>
      
      <tag>FOMC</tag>
      
      <tag>Interest Rate</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/31/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/31/summary250831/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/31/summary250831/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week was light on major economic data, but a pair of big stories broke on Monday, one in the U.S. and one in Europe. In the U.S., Donald Trump fired Federal Reserve Governor Lisa Cook. In Europe, the French Prime Minister initiated a no-confidence vote in the government. These two events became the central themes for their respective markets this week. Let’s break down the details.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="red">-0.10%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-0.35%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-0.19%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+0.19%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-1.55%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-1.89%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-3.34%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.20%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.71% -&gt; <font color="green">3.63%</font></li><li>10yr          4.26% -&gt; <font color="green">4.23%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.70% -&gt; <font color="red">4.72%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.75% -&gt; <font color="green">2.72%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.42% -&gt; <font color="red">3.51%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.62% -&gt; <font color="green">1.61%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            63.7-&gt; <font color="green">64.0</font></li><li>Gold           3,367-&gt; <font color="green">3,448</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-The-Fed-Controversy"><a href="#U-S-Market-The-Fed-Controversy" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: The Fed Controversy"></a>U.S. Market: The Fed Controversy</h1><p>The drama surrounding the firing of Fed Governor Lisa Cook, a recent Biden appointee with a term lasting until 2038, quickly took center stage. Trump accused her of fraud during a mortgage application and fired her. It is very clear attempt by Trump to create an open seat for a loyalist he could appoint (For more details on FOMC Committee. Check this <a href="https://harrisonpan1.github.io/2025/08/31/note-FED/">post</a>).</p><p>From a short-term perspective, Trump’s move to exert greater control over the Fed was seen as a push for his rate-cutting agenda. This strengthened market expectations for a rate cut and boosted U.S. bond prices. However, this action also compromises the Fed’s independence, which increases long-term inflation risk. This put pressure on the long end of the yield curve. As a result, U.S. bonds saw overall price increases, but the yield curve became steeper.</p><p>Other news included Friday’s PCE data, which largely met expectations and had little impact on rate cut forecasts. The auctions for 2, 5, and 7-year Treasury notes also showed relatively solid demand.</p><p>On the stock side, U.S. markets were already facing significant profit-taking pressure after recent gains. The modest NVDA’s earning outlook also added the downward pressure. Thus, despite the support from rate cut expectations, these combined factors led to a slight decline in U.S. stocks for the week.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Political-and-Economic-Tensions"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Political-and-Economic-Tensions" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Political and Economic Tensions"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Political and Economic Tensions</h1><p>The French no-confidence vote, triggered by a budget impasse, created the risk of the Bayrou government collapsing. The market, fearing political chaos and a potential fiscal crisis, put selling pressure on both French bonds and stocks, which in turn dragged down the broader European market. Money fleeing France for safer havens caused the yield spread between German and French bonds to widen. The minutes from the European Central Bank (ECB) meeting, which showed a more cautious stance on rate cuts, along with slightly higher-than-expected German inflation data, also contributed to the decline in European bond prices.</p><p>In Japan, the stock market saw little change, while facing the selling pressure from month-end portfolio rebalancing. In the bond market, the Bank of Japan governor’s speech at last week’s central banking conference hinted at a continued rate cut path, which should have pushed bond yields higher. However, market expectations that the government would reduce the issuance of super-long-term bonds offset this, resulting in a slight weekly decline in yields (a small price increase).</p><h1 id="Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences"><a href="#Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences"></a>Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences</h1><p>The news of Ukrainian strikes on Russian energy facilities triggered supply concerns, ultimately causing oil prices to rise slightly.</p><p>Gold prices also moved higher, largely benefiting from the Fed controversy. The firing of the governor strengthened expectations for a rate cut, increased long-term inflation risk, and damaged the Fed’s independence. All three of these factors served to push gold prices higher.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/24/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/24/summary250824/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/24/summary250824/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, the market’s primary focus was on two key developments: Jerome Powell’s Jackson Hole talk and the ongoing situation in Ukraine. Let’s break down the details.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.36%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-0.44%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.66%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+3.22%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+2.10%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.02%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+0.58%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="red">-2.26%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.76% -&gt; <font color="green">3.71%</font></li><li>10yr          4.32% -&gt; <font color="green">4.26%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.70% -&gt; <font color="green">4.70%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.79% -&gt; <font color="green">2.73%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.47% -&gt; <font color="green">3.42%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.59% -&gt; <font color="red">1.62%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            63.2-&gt; <font color="green">63.7</font></li><li>Gold           3,335-&gt; <font color="green">3,371</font></li></ul><h1 id="US-Markets-The-Anticipation-and-Reveal"><a href="#US-Markets-The-Anticipation-and-Reveal" class="headerlink" title="US Markets: The Anticipation and Reveal"></a>US Markets: The Anticipation and Reveal</h1><p>For the past few weeks, a prevailing market narrative has been the expectation of a Fed rate cut in September. This was fueled by a combination of weakening U.S. economic data and the realization that inflation from tariffs wasn’t as high as initially feared. However, this was just market speculation. The real validation had to come from the Fed itself. </p><p>Thus from Monday to Thursday, the market was in a state of cautious observation. The S&amp;P 500, having seen significant gains recently, faced selling pressure and registered four consecutive days of small declines.</p><p>On Friday, however, Powell’s speech revealed the Fed’s stance. He stated that the current policy rate is tight and that employment-related risks are significant, making a policy adjustment a “reasonable option.” While the wording was cautious, the market immediately caught the signal of a coming rate cut. In response, U.S. Treasury yields fell, and bond prices rose.</p><p>The mood in the U.S. stock market returned to optimism, and markets put the odds of a September cut at 90%. All previous downward trend sharply reversed on Friday. Most major U.S. indices saw gains, with the Nasdaq being the only exception. Despite a strong Friday rebound, it still closed slightly down for the week after its earlier sharp declines.</p><h1 id="European-Japanese-Markets-Divergent-Paths"><a href="#European-Japanese-Markets-Divergent-Paths" class="headerlink" title="European &amp; Japanese Markets: Divergent Paths"></a>European &amp; Japanese Markets: Divergent Paths</h1><p>European markets, in addition to being affected by the Fed’s rate cut signals, also closely watched developments in the Ukraine-Russia situation. On Monday, European and Ukrainian leaders met with Donald Trump, and the market’s hope for a swift resolution to the conflict helped boost European stocks. However, after several weeks of continuous gains, the stock markets in Germany and France showed some fatigue and struggled to rise further.</p><p>The anticipated de-escalation of the conflict should have, in theory, reduced safe-haven demand and pushed European bond prices lower. However, the market adopted a wait-and-see approach, so the downward pressure on bonds was limited. Instead, the rally in U.S. bonds had a more pronounced effect, pulling European bonds higher. The notable exception was the UK, where higher-than-expected CPI data reduced expectations of a Bank of England rate cut, causing UK bonds to underperform their German and French counterparts.</p><p>n Japan, both government bonds and stocks saw declines, showing a trend opposite to that of Europe. This was partly due to the time difference—the Fed’s signal came too late to fully impact the Japanese market. Another key factor was internal: after hitting a record high the previous week, the Japanese stock market faced significant selling pressure. This, combined with the decline in U.S. tech stocks, led to a weekly drop. The decline in Japanese government bonds primarily reflected market caution about fiscal expansion, which was evident in weak demand during this week’s bond auctions and the Bank of Japan’s bond purchase operations.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Riding-the-Wave"><a href="#Commodities-Riding-the-Wave" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Riding the Wave"></a>Commodities: Riding the Wave</h1><p>The Fed’s rate cut signal, along with general market optimism, boosted demand expectations and contributed to a small increase in oil prices.</p><p>Gold also saw a modest rise, mainly influenced by U.S. Treasury yields. Since bond yields reflect the opportunity cost of holding gold, falling U.S. Treasury yields make gold relatively more attractive, thus pushing its price higher.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/17/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/17/summary250817/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/17/summary250817/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market trend was largely a continuation of the previous week’s momentum.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.94%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+0.81%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.74%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+3.07%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.47%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.81%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+2.33%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+3.73%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.77% -&gt; <font color="green">3.76%</font></li><li>10yr          4.29% -&gt; <font color="red">4.32%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.60% -&gt; <font color="red">4.70%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.69% -&gt; <font color="red">2.79%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.35% -&gt; <font color="red">3.46%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.49% -&gt; <font color="red">1.56%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            63.4-&gt; <font color="red">63.2</font></li><li>Gold           3,458-&gt; <font color="red">3,382</font></li></ul><h1 id="US-Markets"><a href="#US-Markets" class="headerlink" title="US Markets"></a>US Markets</h1><p>After a significant downward revision of U.S. employment data two weeks ago, the market broadly anticipated that the Federal Reserve would resume interest rate cuts in September. Last week’s weaker economic data further strengthened this expectation, leading to the current bullish sentiment and rising stock prices.</p><p>This week the increase in core CPI and a higher-than-expected PPI reading both reminded that the  inflationary pressure still exists. Consequently, inflation concerns pushed long-term yields higher, while rate cut expectations drove short-term yields lower, resulting in a steeper U.S. Treasury yield curve.</p><p>The stock market, however, focused more on the potential for a near-term rate cut, making the CPI data a positive catalyst for U.S. stocks. The additional news that Trump extended China tariff deadline by 90 days further eased trade war concerns. This combination of factors fueled optimism, pushing the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq to new record highs.</p><h1 id="European-and-Japanese-Markets"><a href="#European-and-Japanese-Markets" class="headerlink" title="European and Japanese Markets"></a>European and Japanese Markets</h1><p>Following the lead of the U.S. market, European stock markets generally rose, while government bond prices fell. Another key factor influencing European markets was the Trump-Putin meeting on Friday. Although the meeting took place after the European market close, the week’s rising expectation of a de-escalation in the Russia-Ukraine situation contributed to the rally in European stocks. The reduction in safe-haven demand, in turn, drove down European bond prices.</p><p>In Japan, the market experienced a similar trend of rising stocks and falling bonds, with the Nikkei 225 once again reaching a new historical high. The reasons behind this, in addition to the momentum from the U.S. market, included better-than-expected Q2 GDP growth, which boosted market confidence. This strong GDP data suggested that the Bank of Japan would have more room to consider resuming rate hikes. This, combined with high market sentiment and the flow of capital from bonds to stocks, collectively pushed Japanese government bond yields higher and prices lower.</p><h1 id="Commodities"><a href="#Commodities" class="headerlink" title="Commodities"></a>Commodities</h1><p>EIA (Energy Information Administration) data this week indicated an increase in oil inventories. On Friday, China’s industrial production and retail sales data raised market concerns about weakening energy demand. These two factors together caused a slight dip in oil prices.</p><p>For gold, the tariff-related turmoil that had temporarily boosted prices last week subsided. This week, rising government bond yields increased the opportunity cost of holding gold, putting downward pressure on its price. As a result, gold saw a small decline.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/10/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/10/summary250810/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/10/summary250810/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market trend was reversed from last week. European and US stocks bounced back and government bonds fell. This was largely due to shifting expectations around the Fed’s next move.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+2.43%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+3.73%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.35%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+2.67%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.3%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+3.15%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+2.59%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+2.5%</font></li><li>NK1!          <font color="green">+2.4%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.70% -&gt; <font color="red">3.77%</font></li><li>10yr          4.23% -&gt; <font color="red">4.29%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.53% -&gt; <font color="red">4.60%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.68% -&gt; <font color="red">2.69%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.35% -&gt; <font color="red">3.35%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.51% -&gt; <font color="green">1.49%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            67.3-&gt; <font color="red">63.8</font></li><li>Gold           3426-&gt; <font color="green">3491</font></li></ul><h1 id="The-Fed-and-US-Markets"><a href="#The-Fed-and-US-Markets" class="headerlink" title="The Fed and US Markets"></a>The Fed and US Markets</h1><p>The primary driver this week was a major shift in Fed rate cut expectations. Last Friday, weaker-than-expected Non-Farm Payroll (NFP) data led to a market sell-off, as investors worried about a potential recession. This week, however, investors focused on the silver lining: the weak data solidified expectations that the Fed would need to restart rate cuts soon to stimulate the economy.</p><p>Further weak economic data this week reinforced this sentiment (weaker ISM Services PMI &amp; higher Continuing Jobless Claims). As a result, the market now prices in an almost 90% probability of a Fed rate cut in September. Some analysts are even suggesting a “double-speed” cut of 0.5% if August and September data continue to be disappointed.</p><p>This optimistic outlook, combined with the weekend cooling off of last week’s panic, fueled a significant rally in US stocks. The Nasdaq, in particular, broke a new all-time high, largely driven by strong performance in technology stocks like Apple, which saw its share price surge on news it might be exempt from certain chip tariffs.</p><p>On the bond side, US Treasury yields rose this week (prices fell). While rate cut expectations typically support bonds, the market stepped back. This was partly due to caution over new tariffs that went into effect on August 7th and their potential impact on inflation. Additionally, news that Fed Governor Christopher Waller, a moderate on rate cuts, is a potential candidate for the next Fed Chair dampened expectations for a more aggressive easing cycle after 2025. These factors, along with poor performance in this week’s Treasury auctions, led to a pullback in bond prices.</p><h1 id="European-and-Japanese-Markets"><a href="#European-and-Japanese-Markets" class="headerlink" title="European and Japanese Markets"></a>European and Japanese Markets</h1><p>European markets largely followed the US trend, with stocks rising and bond yields climbing. News about ceasefire in the Russia-Ukraine conflict and a planned meeting between President Trump and the two leaders, also helped boost European stock sentiment.</p><p>The Bank of England (BoE) cut rates as expected this week, but the vote was close, with four of the nine committee members opposing the move. This led the market to lower its expectations for the future pace of rate cuts, causing the UK market to underperform its German and French counterparts.</p><p>The Japanese market also saw a significant rally, with the TOPIX index hitting a new all-time high. This was driven by a strong round of corporate earnings reports from major Japanese companies like SoftBank and Sony, as well as the positive spillover effect from the US market’s rally. Japanese government bonds, however, moved slightly higher in price (yields fell slightly), running counter to the trend in the US and Europe. This was mainly due to the time difference; the Japanese bond market’s performance still largely reflected the safe-haven sentiment from last Friday’s weak US jobs report.</p><h1 id="Commodities"><a href="#Commodities" class="headerlink" title="Commodities"></a>Commodities</h1><p>Gold prices saw a slight increase. The Fed’s expected rate cuts weakened the US dollar, which often provides upward momentum for gold. Additionally, new tariffs announced on Friday also contributed to gold’s safe-haven appeal.</p><p>Oil prices fell slightly this week. Weak US economic data lowered demand expectations, while the potential for a Russia-Ukraine ceasefire increased supply expectations. These two factors combined to push prices down.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/3/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/03/summary250803/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/03/summary250803/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market dynamics can be traced along two main threads: <strong>trade negotiations</strong> and <strong>central banks policies</strong>.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        -2.46%</li><li>Nasdaq        -2.57%</li><li>Dow30         -2.75%</li><li>Russell2000   -4.09%</li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       -0.57%</li><li>DAX           -3.27%</li><li>CAC           -3.68%</li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         -1.19%</li><li>NK            -2.65%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.94% -&gt; 3.70%</li><li>10yr          4.40% -&gt; 4.225%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.61% -&gt; 4.53%</li><li>DE10yr        2.73% -&gt; 2.67%</li><li>FR10yr        3.39% -&gt; 3.35%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.60% -&gt; 1.55%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI           65.34 -&gt; 67.25</li><li>Gold          3331 -&gt; 3363</li></ul><h1 id="Trade-Negotiations"><a href="#Trade-Negotiations" class="headerlink" title="Trade Negotiations"></a>Trade Negotiations</h1><p>This week saw a series of trade talks involving the US-EU, US-China, and US-South Korea. From the perspective of avoiding an escalation of the trade war, this was positive news.</p><p>However, the market had already priced in these agreements. Instead, attention shifted to the potential impact of the new tariffs on the global economy, leading to cautious sentiment. This is one of the main reasons European stocks fell instead of rising after the deals were announced.</p><p>As the August 1st deadline approached, President Trump signed a new tariff order on July 31st, further heightening market anxiety and putting downward pressure on US stocks.</p><h1 id="Fed-Reserve-and-Economic-Data"><a href="#Fed-Reserve-and-Economic-Data" class="headerlink" title="Fed Reserve and Economic Data"></a>Fed Reserve and Economic Data</h1><p>On Wednesday, the Fed kept interest rates unchanged (as expected), but the Fed Chair downplayed expectations for a September rate cut during the press conference. This hit the stock market and also put downward pressure on bond prices (pushing yields up).</p><p>However, on Friday, both the Non-Farm Payroll (NFP) and PMI data came in weaker than expected. Meanwile, the NFP of May and June were revised down about 90%, way larger than normal. This led the market to believe the Fed would have to restart rate cuts sooner to counter the risk of an economic recession.</p><p>This reversal in expectations ultimately led to US bond yields falling (prices rising). At the same time, concerns about a recession intensified selling pressure on stocks, causing the US market to pull back significantly from its highs.</p><p>This also impact the Europe stock and bond market. Both European bond yields and stocks trended lower on Friday.</p><h1 id="Japanese-Market"><a href="#Japanese-Market" class="headerlink" title="Japanese Market"></a>Japanese Market</h1><p>On Thursday, the Bank of Japan (BoJ) announced that it would not raise interest rates for now and raised its inflation forecast for this year and next.</p><p>Governor Kazuo Ueda’s comments were also conservative. This pushed Japanese government bond yields slightly lower (prices rose slightly). He also mentioned that the current yen Exchange Rates has not deviated significantly from the Bank of Japan’s expectations and will not have a significant impact on the price outlook. This was interpreted by the market as the BoJ tolerating a weaker yen, which triggered a yen sell-off.</p><p>In theory, no rate hike and a weaker yen are positive for Japanese stocks. However, two stronger factors dominated: profit-taking pressure after last week’s major rally and the drag from falling US stocks. Therefore, Japanese stocks ended the week lower.</p><p><strong><em>NOTE:</em></strong> Due to the time difference, the closing price of the Japanese market on Friday did not fully reflect the negative sentiment from the late-day drop in US stocks caused by weak data. If you look at the performance of Nikkei futures, their decline was comparable to that of US and European markets.</p><h1 id="Crude-Oil"><a href="#Crude-Oil" class="headerlink" title="Crude Oil"></a>Crude Oil</h1><p>Prices rose slightly, driven by two factors:</p><ul><li><p>Demand Side: Progress in trade negotiations reduced uncertainty about demand.</p></li><li><p>Supply Side: News that President Trump would advance sanctions on Russian energy exports created supply-side anxiety.</p></li></ul><h1 id="Gold"><a href="#Gold" class="headerlink" title="Gold"></a>Gold</h1><p>Prices increased slightly, mainly influenced by US Treasury yields. Holding gold does not generate interest, so government bond yields represent the opportunity cost of holding gold. Thus, the decline in US Treasury yields this week lowered the opportunity cost of investing in gold, pushing its price higher.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Robinhood Trading Risk Management Tool</title>
    <link href="/2025/07/30/Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management/"/>
    <url>/2025/07/30/Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Level-Up-Your-Robinhood-Trading-A-Free-Open-Source-Journal-and-Risk-Manager"><a href="#Level-Up-Your-Robinhood-Trading-A-Free-Open-Source-Journal-and-Risk-Manager" class="headerlink" title="Level Up Your Robinhood Trading: A Free, Open-Source Journal and Risk Manager"></a>Level Up Your Robinhood Trading: A Free, Open-Source Journal and Risk Manager</h2><p>Trading on Robinhood is a double-edged sword. The accessibility is incredible, but for the new age of investors diving into high-risk, high-reward options and volatile stocks, there’s a distinct lack of professional-grade tools to manage that risk. When you’re making complex plays, flying blind is the fastest way to crash.</p><p>That’s why I’m excited to share the <a href="https://github.com/harrisonpan1/Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management.git">Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management</a>, a free, open-source project built with Python. It can help to keep track of your trading logs and portfolio option greek risk.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-developed Project</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Option</tag>
      
      <tag>Risk Management</tag>
      
      <tag>Robinhood</tag>
      
      <tag>Trading</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 7/27/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/07/27/summary250727/"/>
    <url>/2025/07/27/summary250727/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market logic is quite clear, though the details can get a bit complex. Let’s break it down.</p><h1 id="Japan-Election-Upset-and-the-Bond-Market-Paradox"><a href="#Japan-Election-Upset-and-the-Bond-Market-Paradox" class="headerlink" title="Japan Election Upset and the Bond Market Paradox"></a>Japan Election Upset and the Bond Market Paradox</h1><p>The week’s biggest story started in Japan. Over the weekend, the ruling coalition led by Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba suffered a major defeat in the upper house election, losing its majority. This turns the Ishiba cabinet into a minority government, sparking media speculation that the Prime Minister might resign.</p><p>From a market perspective, this created a complex reaction to Japanese Government Bonds (JGBs):</p><ul><li><strong>Pre-Election Jitters:</strong> Markets had already anticipated an imminent opposition victory. Because the opposition parties generally advocate for expansionary fiscal policy, investors grew concerned about Japan’s deficit and the potential for an over-issuance of government bonds. This led to a sell-off in JGBs starting from early this month.</li><li><strong>Post-Election Reversal:</strong> While the ruling coalition lost, the defeat wasn’t as severe as many had feared. This eased concerns about runaway fiscal spending, which in turn reduced the pressure to sell JGBs.</li><li><strong>Political Risk:</strong> At the same time, the prospect of a minority government and a potential prime minister resignation increased political uncertainty. This boosted safe-haven demand, creating buying pressure for JGBs.</li></ul><p>Based on these factors, one would expect JGB prices to rise. So why did they fall (<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/JP10Y-JP">JP10y 1.532% -&gt; 1.603%</a>)?</p><h1 id="The-Game-Changer-The-US-Japan-Trade-Agreement"><a href="#The-Game-Changer-The-US-Japan-Trade-Agreement" class="headerlink" title="The Game Changer: The US-Japan Trade Agreement"></a>The Game Changer: The US-Japan Trade Agreement</h1><p>The answer lies in the week’s other major news story. On the evening of July 22nd, President Trump announced that the US and Japan had reached a trade agreement. Key terms include a $550 billion investment by Japan in the United States and a reduction of US tariffs on Japanese goods to 15%.</p><p>This news injected a massive dose of optimism into the market:</p><ul><li><strong>Japanese and US Stocks Soared:</strong> Japanese stocks, particularly in the auto sector, surged on the news. This optimism spread to the US, where strong earnings reports (with over 80% of companies beating profit expectations) also helped push the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq to new record highs.</li><li><strong>Safe-Haven Demand Faded:</strong> The positive sentiment caused capital to flow from the safety of bonds into equities. For Japan, the stable trade environment also increased the likelihood that the Bank of Japan could consider restarting interest rate hikes in the future. This created immense downward pressure on Japanese bonds, ultimately overwhelming the upward push from the election results.</li></ul><p>Consequently, JGB yields rose significantly (ie. prices fell).</p><h1 id="US-Treasuries-and-The-Fed"><a href="#US-Treasuries-and-The-Fed" class="headerlink" title="US Treasuries and The Fed"></a>US Treasuries and The Fed</h1><p>On Thursday, President Trump visited the Federal Reserve in Washington, D.C., to review building renovations. He tried to use the $2 billion renovation costs to ramp up political pressure on Chairman Jerome Powell to lower the benchmark interest rate. <a href="https://www.ustreasuryyieldcurve.com/b/gsThlo">This reversed the logic from the previous week, causing the US Treasury yield curve to flatten, as long-term yields fell.</a></p><h1 id="A-Look-at-Europe"><a href="#A-Look-at-Europe" class="headerlink" title="A Look at Europe"></a>A Look at Europe</h1><ul><li><strong>ECB:</strong> The European Central Bank held interest rates steady at 2% on Thursday, pausing its year-long policy easing cycle and adopting a “wait-and-see” approach on future rate cuts. This was in line with expectations and had little market impact.</li><li><strong>Bonds:</strong> Amid the global optimism, German and French bond spreads tightened. In the UK, however, weak retail sales data and the Chancellor’s commitment to fiscal control helped push UK government bonds slightly higher.</li><li><strong>Stocks:</strong> UK stocks rose, driven primarily by corporate earnings. German and French stocks remained largely unchanged as investors await progress on US-EU trade negotiations.</li></ul><h1 id="Dollar-and-Commodities"><a href="#Dollar-and-Commodities" class="headerlink" title="Dollar and Commodities"></a>Dollar and Commodities</h1><ul><li><strong>US Dollar:</strong> Since President Trump’s tariff wars had the effect of strengthening the dollar. A trade agreement, therefore, has the opposite effect. The de-escalation of trade tensions pushed the US dollar lower(<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/%40DX.1?qsearchterm=dollar%20index">-0.79(-0.8%)</a>).</li><li><strong>Gold:</strong> A weaker dollar is typically bullish for gold. However, the dominant force this week was market optimism, which reduces demand for safe-haven assets. As a result, gold finished the week slightly down (<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/XAU%3D?qsearchterm=xau">-$12.61(-0.38%)</a>).</li><li><strong>Oil:</strong> While market optimism provided a tailwind for oil prices, supply-side news created stronger headwinds. Reports indicated that OPEC+ will decide to continue production at its upcoming meeting, the US eased restrictions on Venezuelan oil, and Chinese economic data raised concerns about future energy demand. The downward pressure from supply ultimately won out, and oil prices fell modestly (<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/%40CL.1?qsearchterm=wti%20crude%20">-0.89(-1.35%)</a>).</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
