<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/31/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/31/summary250831/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/31/summary250831/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week was light on major economic data, but a pair of big stories broke on Monday, one in the U.S. and one in Europe. In the U.S., Donald Trump fired Federal Reserve Governor Lisa Cook. In Europe, the French Prime Minister initiated a no-confidence vote in the government. These two events became the central themes for their respective markets this week. Let’s break down the details.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="red">+-0.10%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-0.35%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="red">-0.19%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+0.19%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="red">-1.55%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="red">-1.89%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="red">-3.34%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+0.20%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.71% -&gt; <font color="green">3.63%</font></li><li>10yr          4.26% -&gt; <font color="green">4.23%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.70% -&gt; <font color="red">4.72%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.75% -&gt; <font color="green">2.72%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.42% -&gt; <font color="red">3.51%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.62% -&gt; <font color="green">1.61%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            63.7-&gt; <font color="green">64.0</font></li><li>Gold           3,367-&gt; <font color="green">3,448</font></li></ul><h1 id="U-S-Market-The-Fed-Controversy"><a href="#U-S-Market-The-Fed-Controversy" class="headerlink" title="U.S. Market: The Fed Controversy"></a>U.S. Market: The Fed Controversy</h1><p>The drama surrounding the firing of Fed Governor Lisa Cook, a recent Biden appointee with a term lasting until 2038, quickly took center stage. Trump accused her of fraud during a mortgage application and fired her. It is very clear attempt by Trump to create an open seat for a loyalist he could appoint.</p><p>From a short-term perspective, Trump’s move to exert greater control over the Fed was seen as a push for his rate-cutting agenda. This strengthened market expectations for a rate cut and boosted U.S. bond prices. However, this action also compromises the Fed’s independence, which increases long-term inflation risk. This put pressure on the long end of the yield curve. As a result, U.S. bonds saw overall price increases, but the yield curve became steeper.</p><p>Other news included Friday’s PCE data, which largely met expectations and had little impact on rate cut forecasts. The auctions for 2, 5, and 7-year Treasury notes also showed relatively solid demand.</p><p>On the stock side, U.S. markets were already facing significant profit-taking pressure after recent gains. The modest NVDA’s earning outlook also added the downward pressure. Thus, despite the support from rate cut expectations, these combined factors led to a slight decline in U.S. stocks for the week.</p><h1 id="Europe-Japan-Political-and-Economic-Tensions"><a href="#Europe-Japan-Political-and-Economic-Tensions" class="headerlink" title="Europe &amp; Japan: Political and Economic Tensions"></a>Europe &amp; Japan: Political and Economic Tensions</h1><p>The French no-confidence vote, triggered by a budget impasse, created the risk of the Bayrou government collapsing. The market, fearing political chaos and a potential fiscal crisis, put selling pressure on both French bonds and stocks, which in turn dragged down the broader European market. Money fleeing France for safer havens caused the yield spread between German and French bonds to widen. The minutes from the European Central Bank (ECB) meeting, which showed a more cautious stance on rate cuts, along with slightly higher-than-expected German inflation data, also contributed to the decline in European bond prices.</p><p>In Japan, the stock market saw little change, while facing the selling pressure from month-end portfolio rebalancing. In the bond market, the Bank of Japan governor’s speech at last week’s central banking conference hinted at a continued rate cut path, which should have pushed bond yields higher. However, market expectations that the government would reduce the issuance of super-long-term bonds offset this, resulting in a slight weekly decline in yields (a small price increase).</p><h1 id="Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences"><a href="#Commodities-Geopolitical-and-Policy-Influences" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences"></a>Commodities: Geopolitical and Policy Influences</h1><p>The news of Ukrainian strikes on Russian energy facilities triggered supply concerns, ultimately causing oil prices to rise slightly.</p><p>Gold prices also moved higher, largely benefiting from the Fed controversy. The firing of the governor strengthened expectations for a rate cut, increased long-term inflation risk, and damaged the Fed’s independence. All three of these factors served to push gold prices higher.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/24/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/24/summary250824/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/24/summary250824/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week, the market’s primary focus was on two key developments: Jerome Powell’s Jackson Hole talk and the ongoing situation in Ukraine. Let’s break down the details.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.36%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="red">-0.44%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.66%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+3.22%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+2.10%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.02%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+0.58%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="red">-2.26%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.76% -&gt; <font color="green">3.71%</font></li><li>10yr          4.32% -&gt; <font color="green">4.26%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.70% -&gt; <font color="green">4.70%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.79% -&gt; <font color="green">2.73%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.47% -&gt; <font color="green">3.42%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.59% -&gt; <font color="red">1.62%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            63.2-&gt; <font color="green">63.7</font></li><li>Gold           3,335-&gt; <font color="green">3,371</font></li></ul><h1 id="US-Markets-The-Anticipation-and-Reveal"><a href="#US-Markets-The-Anticipation-and-Reveal" class="headerlink" title="US Markets: The Anticipation and Reveal"></a>US Markets: The Anticipation and Reveal</h1><p>For the past few weeks, a prevailing market narrative has been the expectation of a Fed rate cut in September. This was fueled by a combination of weakening U.S. economic data and the realization that inflation from tariffs wasn’t as high as initially feared. However, this was just market speculation. The real validation had to come from the Fed itself. </p><p>Thus from Monday to Thursday, the market was in a state of cautious observation. The S&amp;P 500, having seen significant gains recently, faced selling pressure and registered four consecutive days of small declines.</p><p>On Friday, however, Powell’s speech revealed the Fed’s stance. He stated that the current policy rate is tight and that employment-related risks are significant, making a policy adjustment a “reasonable option.” While the wording was cautious, the market immediately caught the signal of a coming rate cut. In response, U.S. Treasury yields fell, and bond prices rose.</p><p>The mood in the U.S. stock market returned to optimism, and markets put the odds of a September cut at 90%. All previous downward trend sharply reversed on Friday. Most major U.S. indices saw gains, with the Nasdaq being the only exception. Despite a strong Friday rebound, it still closed slightly down for the week after its earlier sharp declines.</p><h1 id="European-Japanese-Markets-Divergent-Paths"><a href="#European-Japanese-Markets-Divergent-Paths" class="headerlink" title="European &amp; Japanese Markets: Divergent Paths"></a>European &amp; Japanese Markets: Divergent Paths</h1><p>European markets, in addition to being affected by the Fed’s rate cut signals, also closely watched developments in the Ukraine-Russia situation. On Monday, European and Ukrainian leaders met with Donald Trump, and the market’s hope for a swift resolution to the conflict helped boost European stocks. However, after several weeks of continuous gains, the stock markets in Germany and France showed some fatigue and struggled to rise further.</p><p>The anticipated de-escalation of the conflict should have, in theory, reduced safe-haven demand and pushed European bond prices lower. However, the market adopted a wait-and-see approach, so the downward pressure on bonds was limited. Instead, the rally in U.S. bonds had a more pronounced effect, pulling European bonds higher. The notable exception was the UK, where higher-than-expected CPI data reduced expectations of a Bank of England rate cut, causing UK bonds to underperform their German and French counterparts.</p><p>n Japan, both government bonds and stocks saw declines, showing a trend opposite to that of Europe. This was partly due to the time difference—the Fed’s signal came too late to fully impact the Japanese market. Another key factor was internal: after hitting a record high the previous week, the Japanese stock market faced significant selling pressure. This, combined with the decline in U.S. tech stocks, led to a weekly drop. The decline in Japanese government bonds primarily reflected market caution about fiscal expansion, which was evident in weak demand during this week’s bond auctions and the Bank of Japan’s bond purchase operations.</p><h1 id="Commodities-Riding-the-Wave"><a href="#Commodities-Riding-the-Wave" class="headerlink" title="Commodities: Riding the Wave"></a>Commodities: Riding the Wave</h1><p>The Fed’s rate cut signal, along with general market optimism, boosted demand expectations and contributed to a small increase in oil prices.</p><p>Gold also saw a modest rise, mainly influenced by U.S. Treasury yields. Since bond yields reflect the opportunity cost of holding gold, falling U.S. Treasury yields make gold relatively more attractive, thus pushing its price higher.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/17/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/17/summary250817/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/17/summary250817/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market trend was largely a continuation of the previous week’s momentum.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+0.94%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+0.81%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.74%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+3.07%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.47%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+0.81%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+2.33%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+3.73%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.77% -&gt; <font color="green">3.76%</font></li><li>10yr          4.29% -&gt; <font color="red">4.32%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.60% -&gt; <font color="red">4.70%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.69% -&gt; <font color="red">2.79%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.35% -&gt; <font color="red">3.46%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.49% -&gt; <font color="red">1.56%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            63.4-&gt; <font color="red">63.2</font></li><li>Gold           3,458-&gt; <font color="red">3,382</font></li></ul><h1 id="US-Markets"><a href="#US-Markets" class="headerlink" title="US Markets"></a>US Markets</h1><p>After a significant downward revision of U.S. employment data two weeks ago, the market broadly anticipated that the Federal Reserve would resume interest rate cuts in September. Last week’s weaker economic data further strengthened this expectation, leading to the current bullish sentiment and rising stock prices.</p><p>This week the increase in core CPI and a higher-than-expected PPI reading both reminded that the  inflationary pressure still exists. Consequently, inflation concerns pushed long-term yields higher, while rate cut expectations drove short-term yields lower, resulting in a steeper U.S. Treasury yield curve.</p><p>The stock market, however, focused more on the potential for a near-term rate cut, making the CPI data a positive catalyst for U.S. stocks. The additional news that Trump extended China tariff deadline by 90 days further eased trade war concerns. This combination of factors fueled optimism, pushing the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq to new record highs.</p><h1 id="European-and-Japanese-Markets"><a href="#European-and-Japanese-Markets" class="headerlink" title="European and Japanese Markets"></a>European and Japanese Markets</h1><p>Following the lead of the U.S. market, European stock markets generally rose, while government bond prices fell. Another key factor influencing European markets was the Trump-Putin meeting on Friday. Although the meeting took place after the European market close, the week’s rising expectation of a de-escalation in the Russia-Ukraine situation contributed to the rally in European stocks. The reduction in safe-haven demand, in turn, drove down European bond prices.</p><p>In Japan, the market experienced a similar trend of rising stocks and falling bonds, with the Nikkei 225 once again reaching a new historical high. The reasons behind this, in addition to the momentum from the U.S. market, included better-than-expected Q2 GDP growth, which boosted market confidence. This strong GDP data suggested that the Bank of Japan would have more room to consider resuming rate hikes. This, combined with high market sentiment and the flow of capital from bonds to stocks, collectively pushed Japanese government bond yields higher and prices lower.</p><h1 id="Commodities"><a href="#Commodities" class="headerlink" title="Commodities"></a>Commodities</h1><p>EIA (Energy Information Administration) data this week indicated an increase in oil inventories. On Friday, China’s industrial production and retail sales data raised market concerns about weakening energy demand. These two factors together caused a slight dip in oil prices.</p><p>For gold, the tariff-related turmoil that had temporarily boosted prices last week subsided. This week, rising government bond yields increased the opportunity cost of holding gold, putting downward pressure on its price. As a result, gold saw a small decline.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/10/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/10/summary250810/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/10/summary250810/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market trend was reversed from last week. European and US stocks bounced back and government bonds fell. This was largely due to shifting expectations around the Fed’s next move.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        <font color="green">+2.43%</font></li><li>Nasdaq        <font color="green">+3.73%</font></li><li>Dow30         <font color="green">+1.35%</font></li><li>Russell2000   <font color="green">+2.67%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       <font color="green">+0.3%</font></li><li>DAX           <font color="green">+3.15%</font></li><li>CAC           <font color="green">+2.59%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         <font color="green">+2.5%</font></li><li>NK1!          <font color="green">+2.4%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.70% -&gt; <font color="red">3.77%</font></li><li>10yr          4.23% -&gt; <font color="red">4.29%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.53% -&gt; <font color="red">4.60%</font></li><li>DE10yr        2.68% -&gt; <font color="red">2.69%</font></li><li>FR10yr        3.35% -&gt; <font color="red">3.35%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.51% -&gt; <font color="green">1.49%</font></li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI            67.3-&gt; <font color="red">63.8</font></li><li>Gold           3426-&gt; <font color="green">3491</font></li></ul><h1 id="The-Fed-and-US-Markets"><a href="#The-Fed-and-US-Markets" class="headerlink" title="The Fed and US Markets"></a>The Fed and US Markets</h1><p>The primary driver this week was a major shift in Fed rate cut expectations. Last Friday, weaker-than-expected Non-Farm Payroll (NFP) data led to a market sell-off, as investors worried about a potential recession. This week, however, investors focused on the silver lining: the weak data solidified expectations that the Fed would need to restart rate cuts soon to stimulate the economy.</p><p>Further weak economic data this week reinforced this sentiment (weaker ISM Services PMI &amp; higher Continuing Jobless Claims). As a result, the market now prices in an almost 90% probability of a Fed rate cut in September. Some analysts are even suggesting a “double-speed” cut of 0.5% if August and September data continue to be disappointed.</p><p>This optimistic outlook, combined with the weekend cooling off of last week’s panic, fueled a significant rally in US stocks. The Nasdaq, in particular, broke a new all-time high, largely driven by strong performance in technology stocks like Apple, which saw its share price surge on news it might be exempt from certain chip tariffs.</p><p>On the bond side, US Treasury yields rose this week (prices fell). While rate cut expectations typically support bonds, the market stepped back. This was partly due to caution over new tariffs that went into effect on August 7th and their potential impact on inflation. Additionally, news that Fed Governor Christopher Waller, a moderate on rate cuts, is a potential candidate for the next Fed Chair dampened expectations for a more aggressive easing cycle after 2025. These factors, along with poor performance in this week’s Treasury auctions, led to a pullback in bond prices.</p><h1 id="European-and-Japanese-Markets"><a href="#European-and-Japanese-Markets" class="headerlink" title="European and Japanese Markets"></a>European and Japanese Markets</h1><p>European markets largely followed the US trend, with stocks rising and bond yields climbing. News about ceasefire in the Russia-Ukraine conflict and a planned meeting between President Trump and the two leaders, also helped boost European stock sentiment.</p><p>The Bank of England (BoE) cut rates as expected this week, but the vote was close, with four of the nine committee members opposing the move. This led the market to lower its expectations for the future pace of rate cuts, causing the UK market to underperform its German and French counterparts.</p><p>The Japanese market also saw a significant rally, with the TOPIX index hitting a new all-time high. This was driven by a strong round of corporate earnings reports from major Japanese companies like SoftBank and Sony, as well as the positive spillover effect from the US market’s rally. Japanese government bonds, however, moved slightly higher in price (yields fell slightly), running counter to the trend in the US and Europe. This was mainly due to the time difference; the Japanese bond market’s performance still largely reflected the safe-haven sentiment from last Friday’s weak US jobs report.</p><h1 id="Commodities"><a href="#Commodities" class="headerlink" title="Commodities"></a>Commodities</h1><p>Gold prices saw a slight increase. The Fed’s expected rate cuts weakened the US dollar, which often provides upward momentum for gold. Additionally, new tariffs announced on Friday also contributed to gold’s safe-haven appeal.</p><p>Oil prices fell slightly this week. Weak US economic data lowered demand expectations, while the potential for a Russia-Ukraine ceasefire increased supply expectations. These two factors combined to push prices down.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 8/3/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/08/03/summary250803/"/>
    <url>/2025/08/03/summary250803/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market dynamics can be traced along two main threads: <strong>trade negotiations</strong> and <strong>central banks policies</strong>.</p><h1 id="Quick-Take"><a href="#Quick-Take" class="headerlink" title="Quick Take"></a>Quick Take</h1><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">US Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>S&amp;P500        -2.46%</li><li>Nasdaq        -2.57%</li><li>Dow30         -2.75%</li><li>Russell2000   -4.09%</li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">EU Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>FTSE100       -0.57%</li><li>DAX           -3.27%</li><li>CAC           -3.68%</li></ul><p><a href="https://www.google.com/finance/">Japan Stock</a>:</p><ul><li>NI225         -1.19%</li><li>NK            -2.65%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">US Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>2yr           3.94% -&gt; 3.70%</li><li>10yr          4.40% -&gt; 4.225%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">EU Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>UK10yr        4.61% -&gt; 4.53%</li><li>DE10yr        2.73% -&gt; 2.67%</li><li>FR10yr        3.39% -&gt; 3.35%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Japan Bond</a>:</p><ul><li>JP10yr        1.60% -&gt; 1.55%</li></ul><p><a href="https://tradingeconomics.com/">Commodity</a>:</p><ul><li>WTI           65.34 -&gt; 67.25</li><li>Gold          3331 -&gt; 3363</li></ul><h1 id="Trade-Negotiations"><a href="#Trade-Negotiations" class="headerlink" title="Trade Negotiations"></a>Trade Negotiations</h1><p>This week saw a series of trade talks involving the US-EU, US-China, and US-South Korea. From the perspective of avoiding an escalation of the trade war, this was positive news.</p><p>However, the market had already priced in these agreements. Instead, attention shifted to the potential impact of the new tariffs on the global economy, leading to cautious sentiment. This is one of the main reasons European stocks fell instead of rising after the deals were announced.</p><p>As the August 1st deadline approached, President Trump signed a new tariff order on July 31st, further heightening market anxiety and putting downward pressure on US stocks.</p><h1 id="Fed-Reserve-and-Economic-Data"><a href="#Fed-Reserve-and-Economic-Data" class="headerlink" title="Fed Reserve and Economic Data"></a>Fed Reserve and Economic Data</h1><p>On Wednesday, the Fed kept interest rates unchanged (as expected), but the Fed Chair downplayed expectations for a September rate cut during the press conference. This hit the stock market and also put downward pressure on bond prices (pushing yields up).</p><p>However, on Friday, both the Non-Farm Payroll (NFP) and PMI data came in weaker than expected. Meanwile, the NFP of May and June were revised down about 90%, way larger than normal. This led the market to believe the Fed would have to restart rate cuts sooner to counter the risk of an economic recession.</p><p>This reversal in expectations ultimately led to US bond yields falling (prices rising). At the same time, concerns about a recession intensified selling pressure on stocks, causing the US market to pull back significantly from its highs.</p><p>This also impact the Europe stock and bond market. Both European bond yields and stocks trended lower on Friday.</p><h1 id="Japanese-Market"><a href="#Japanese-Market" class="headerlink" title="Japanese Market"></a>Japanese Market</h1><p>On Thursday, the Bank of Japan (BoJ) announced that it would not raise interest rates for now and raised its inflation forecast for this year and next.</p><p>Governor Kazuo Ueda’s comments were also conservative. This pushed Japanese government bond yields slightly lower (prices rose slightly). He also mentioned that the current yen Exchange Rates has not deviated significantly from the Bank of Japan’s expectations and will not have a significant impact on the price outlook. This was interpreted by the market as the BoJ tolerating a weaker yen, which triggered a yen sell-off.</p><p>In theory, no rate hike and a weaker yen are positive for Japanese stocks. However, two stronger factors dominated: profit-taking pressure after last week’s major rally and the drag from falling US stocks. Therefore, Japanese stocks ended the week lower.</p><p><strong><em>NOTE:</em></strong> Due to the time difference, the closing price of the Japanese market on Friday did not fully reflect the negative sentiment from the late-day drop in US stocks caused by weak data. If you look at the performance of Nikkei futures, their decline was comparable to that of US and European markets.</p><h1 id="Crude-Oil"><a href="#Crude-Oil" class="headerlink" title="Crude Oil"></a>Crude Oil</h1><p>Prices rose slightly, driven by two factors:</p><ul><li><p>Demand Side: Progress in trade negotiations reduced uncertainty about demand.</p></li><li><p>Supply Side: News that President Trump would advance sanctions on Russian energy exports created supply-side anxiety.</p></li></ul><h1 id="Gold"><a href="#Gold" class="headerlink" title="Gold"></a>Gold</h1><p>Prices increased slightly, mainly influenced by US Treasury yields. Holding gold does not generate interest, so government bond yields represent the opportunity cost of holding gold. Thus, the decline in US Treasury yields this week lowered the opportunity cost of investing in gold, pushing its price higher.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Robinhood Trading Risk Management Tool</title>
    <link href="/2025/07/30/Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management/"/>
    <url>/2025/07/30/Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="Level-Up-Your-Robinhood-Trading-A-Free-Open-Source-Journal-and-Risk-Manager"><a href="#Level-Up-Your-Robinhood-Trading-A-Free-Open-Source-Journal-and-Risk-Manager" class="headerlink" title="Level Up Your Robinhood Trading: A Free, Open-Source Journal and Risk Manager"></a>Level Up Your Robinhood Trading: A Free, Open-Source Journal and Risk Manager</h2><p>Trading on Robinhood is a double-edged sword. The accessibility is incredible, but for the new age of investors diving into high-risk, high-reward options and volatile stocks, there’s a distinct lack of professional-grade tools to manage that risk. When you’re making complex plays, flying blind is the fastest way to crash.</p><p>That’s why I’m excited to share the <a href="https://github.com/harrisonpan1/Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management.git">Robinhood-Trading-Risk-Management</a>, a free, open-source project built with Python. It can help to keep track of your trading logs and portfolio option greek risk.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Self-developed Project</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Option</tag>
      
      <tag>Risk Management</tag>
      
      <tag>Robinhood</tag>
      
      <tag>Trading</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly Global Market Summary 7/27/2025</title>
    <link href="/2025/07/27/summary250727/"/>
    <url>/2025/07/27/summary250727/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This week’s market logic is quite clear, though the details can get a bit complex. Let’s break it down.</p><h1 id="Japan-Election-Upset-and-the-Bond-Market-Paradox"><a href="#Japan-Election-Upset-and-the-Bond-Market-Paradox" class="headerlink" title="Japan Election Upset and the Bond Market Paradox"></a>Japan Election Upset and the Bond Market Paradox</h1><p>The week’s biggest story started in Japan. Over the weekend, the ruling coalition led by Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba suffered a major defeat in the upper house election, losing its majority. This turns the Ishiba cabinet into a minority government, sparking media speculation that the Prime Minister might resign.</p><p>From a market perspective, this created a complex reaction to Japanese Government Bonds (JGBs):</p><ul><li><strong>Pre-Election Jitters:</strong> Markets had already anticipated an imminent opposition victory. Because the opposition parties generally advocate for expansionary fiscal policy, investors grew concerned about Japan’s deficit and the potential for an over-issuance of government bonds. This led to a sell-off in JGBs starting from early this month.</li><li><strong>Post-Election Reversal:</strong> While the ruling coalition lost, the defeat wasn’t as severe as many had feared. This eased concerns about runaway fiscal spending, which in turn reduced the pressure to sell JGBs.</li><li><strong>Political Risk:</strong> At the same time, the prospect of a minority government and a potential prime minister resignation increased political uncertainty. This boosted safe-haven demand, creating buying pressure for JGBs.</li></ul><p>Based on these factors, one would expect JGB prices to rise. So why did they fall (<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/JP10Y-JP">JP10y 1.532% -&gt; 1.603%</a>)?</p><h1 id="The-Game-Changer-The-US-Japan-Trade-Agreement"><a href="#The-Game-Changer-The-US-Japan-Trade-Agreement" class="headerlink" title="The Game Changer: The US-Japan Trade Agreement"></a>The Game Changer: The US-Japan Trade Agreement</h1><p>The answer lies in the week’s other major news story. On the evening of July 22nd, President Trump announced that the US and Japan had reached a trade agreement. Key terms include a $550 billion investment by Japan in the United States and a reduction of US tariffs on Japanese goods to 15%.</p><p>This news injected a massive dose of optimism into the market:</p><ul><li><strong>Japanese and US Stocks Soared:</strong> Japanese stocks, particularly in the auto sector, surged on the news. This optimism spread to the US, where strong earnings reports (with over 80% of companies beating profit expectations) also helped push the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq to new record highs.</li><li><strong>Safe-Haven Demand Faded:</strong> The positive sentiment caused capital to flow from the safety of bonds into equities. For Japan, the stable trade environment also increased the likelihood that the Bank of Japan could consider restarting interest rate hikes in the future. This created immense downward pressure on Japanese bonds, ultimately overwhelming the upward push from the election results.</li></ul><p>Consequently, JGB yields rose significantly (ie. prices fell).</p><h1 id="US-Treasuries-and-The-Fed"><a href="#US-Treasuries-and-The-Fed" class="headerlink" title="US Treasuries and The Fed"></a>US Treasuries and The Fed</h1><p>On Thursday, President Trump visited the Federal Reserve in Washington, D.C., to review building renovations. He tried to use the $2 billion renovation costs to ramp up political pressure on Chairman Jerome Powell to lower the benchmark interest rate. <a href="https://www.ustreasuryyieldcurve.com/b/gsThlo">This reversed the logic from the previous week, causing the US Treasury yield curve to flatten, as long-term yields fell.</a></p><h1 id="A-Look-at-Europe"><a href="#A-Look-at-Europe" class="headerlink" title="A Look at Europe"></a>A Look at Europe</h1><ul><li><strong>ECB:</strong> The European Central Bank held interest rates steady at 2% on Thursday, pausing its year-long policy easing cycle and adopting a “wait-and-see” approach on future rate cuts. This was in line with expectations and had little market impact.</li><li><strong>Bonds:</strong> Amid the global optimism, German and French bond spreads tightened. In the UK, however, weak retail sales data and the Chancellor’s commitment to fiscal control helped push UK government bonds slightly higher.</li><li><strong>Stocks:</strong> UK stocks rose, driven primarily by corporate earnings. German and French stocks remained largely unchanged as investors await progress on US-EU trade negotiations.</li></ul><h1 id="Dollar-and-Commodities"><a href="#Dollar-and-Commodities" class="headerlink" title="Dollar and Commodities"></a>Dollar and Commodities</h1><ul><li><strong>US Dollar:</strong> Since President Trump’s tariff wars had the effect of strengthening the dollar. A trade agreement, therefore, has the opposite effect. The de-escalation of trade tensions pushed the US dollar lower(<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/%40DX.1?qsearchterm=dollar%20index">-0.79(-0.8%)</a>).</li><li><strong>Gold:</strong> A weaker dollar is typically bullish for gold. However, the dominant force this week was market optimism, which reduces demand for safe-haven assets. As a result, gold finished the week slightly down (<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/XAU%3D?qsearchterm=xau">-$12.61(-0.38%)</a>).</li><li><strong>Oil:</strong> While market optimism provided a tailwind for oil prices, supply-side news created stronger headwinds. Reports indicated that OPEC+ will decide to continue production at its upcoming meeting, the US eased restrictions on Venezuelan oil, and Chinese economic data raised concerns about future energy demand. The downward pressure from supply ultimately won out, and oil prices fell modestly (<a href="https://www.cnbc.com/quotes/%40CL.1?qsearchterm=wti%20crude%20">-0.89(-1.35%)</a>).</li></ul>]]></content>
    
    
    <categories>
      
      <category>Markets</category>
      
    </categories>
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Market Summary</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
